<meetings xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <meeting>
    <Confcode>ED22</Confcode>
    <EventName>Bagel Institute: A Simple Web-Based App for Anxiety-Free Student-Instructor Interaction</EventName>
    <EventSubName></EventSubName>
    <Poster></Poster>
    <EventNumber>CP1</EventNumber>
    <EventDate>Jul 11, 2022</EventDate>
    <EventStartTime>2022-07-11T08:30:00</EventStartTime>
    <EventEndTime>2022-07-11T08:45:00</EventEndTime>
    <EventFilter>ED22|Contributed</EventFilter>
    <EventLocation></EventLocation>
    <EventRoom>404</EventRoom>
    <FloorPlan></FloorPlan>
    <EVENT_FEE></EVENT_FEE>
    <EventKeywords></EventKeywords>
    <EventChairs></EventChairs>
    <EventModerators></EventModerators>
    <EventSpeakers>Christoph Borgers</EventSpeakers>
    <EventSpeakerIDs>716013</EventSpeakerIDs>
    <EventSponsor></EventSponsor>
    <EventHandoutName>Abstract</EventHandoutName>
    <EventHandoutURL>http://meetings.siam.org/sess/dsp_talk.cfm?p=121138</EventHandoutURL>
    <EventDescription>Bagel Institute (https://bagel.institute) is a free web-based app for in-person or online teaching. The app has 
a 2-minute learning curve. There are  two simple functions only, letting students ask
and answer questions  in class without having to reveal
who they are. The app has Latex support. We will report on experiences using  Bagel Institute in several applied mathematics classes, ranging from introductory to graduate level. The main benefit is to give instructors a clearer picture, in real 
time, of 
their students' thinking. This definitely results in slower teaching. Of course we hope
that it also results in more effective and more inclusive 
teaching, but  more data will be needed to support that.
	</EventDescription>
    <EventParent>74686-SESS</EventParent>
    <EventUniqueID>74686-121138</EventUniqueID>
    <STATUS>active</STATUS>
    <AutoRecord>0</AutoRecord>
    <EnabledForIAV>0</EnabledForIAV>
    <MeetingIAVMode xsi:nil="true" />
    <PublishAutoRecordedVideo xsi:nil="true" />
    <Capacity xsi:nil="true" />
    <DirectLinkEnabled>0</DirectLinkEnabled>
    <DirectLinkRecordingEnabled xsi:nil="true" />
    <start>2022-07-11T08:30:00</start>
  </meeting>
  <meeting>
    <Confcode>ED22</Confcode>
    <EventName>Computation and Programming - Why Aren't We Teaching This to Everyone?</EventName>
    <EventSubName></EventSubName>
    <Poster></Poster>
    <EventNumber>CP2</EventNumber>
    <EventDate>Jul 12, 2022</EventDate>
    <EventStartTime>2022-07-12T16:20:00</EventStartTime>
    <EventEndTime>2022-07-12T16:35:00</EventEndTime>
    <EventFilter>ED22|Contributed</EventFilter>
    <EventLocation></EventLocation>
    <EventRoom>406</EventRoom>
    <FloorPlan></FloorPlan>
    <EVENT_FEE></EVENT_FEE>
    <EventKeywords></EventKeywords>
    <EventChairs></EventChairs>
    <EventModerators></EventModerators>
    <EventSpeakers>Harvey Diamond</EventSpeakers>
    <EventSpeakerIDs>806192</EventSpeakerIDs>
    <EventSponsor></EventSponsor>
    <EventHandoutName>Abstract</EventHandoutName>
    <EventHandoutURL>http://meetings.siam.org/sess/dsp_talk.cfm?p=121473</EventHandoutURL>
    <EventDescription>The computational world impacts almost every academic, industrial and business enterprise. It stands on its own as an experimental world of new concepts and fascinating phenomena. It is a world of active learning and investigation. It promotes abstraction in its data structures and operations, while being the most concrete of venues. The numerical, the algebraic, the visual are integrated into one computing system, empowering the user on their own to conceptualize, execute, and display virtually any computation. Modern software, most particularly MATLAB, is easily accessible, includes a general purpose programming language, a stunningly efficient set of data structures and operations based on arrays, and full visualization capability. What could students accomplish with computation as one of the pillars of their academic education, something which can be easily introduced and fully appreciated even in high school. So why aren't we teaching this to everyone?  Having taught a basic course in programming and computation using Matlab for more than ten years, the most compelling way to present this viewpoint, it seems, is through example. These are not specifically motivated by a topic in the standard mathematics curriculum – which speaks to our larger point - but rather by curiosity, or by applying a new programming concept. Having seen the result, one is prompted to go further, to explain it using mathematics, or simply to sit in wonder. 
	</EventDescription>
    <EventParent>74689-SESS</EventParent>
    <EventUniqueID>74689-121473</EventUniqueID>
    <STATUS>active</STATUS>
    <AutoRecord>0</AutoRecord>
    <EnabledForIAV>0</EnabledForIAV>
    <MeetingIAVMode xsi:nil="true" />
    <PublishAutoRecordedVideo xsi:nil="true" />
    <Capacity xsi:nil="true" />
    <DirectLinkEnabled>0</DirectLinkEnabled>
    <DirectLinkRecordingEnabled xsi:nil="true" />
    <start>2022-07-12T16:00:00</start>
  </meeting>
  <meeting>
    <Confcode>ED22</Confcode>
    <EventName>Research on Learning and Teaching University Mathematics: Where We Are and Where We Might Go Next</EventName>
    <EventSubName></EventSubName>
    <Poster></Poster>
    <EventNumber>IP2</EventNumber>
    <EventDate>Jul 11, 2022</EventDate>
    <EventStartTime>2022-07-11T14:00:00</EventStartTime>
    <EventEndTime>2022-07-11T14:45:00</EventEndTime>
    <EventFilter>ED22|Invited Speaker</EventFilter>
    <EventLocation></EventLocation>
    <EventRoom>406</EventRoom>
    <FloorPlan></FloorPlan>
    <EVENT_FEE></EVENT_FEE>
    <EventKeywords></EventKeywords>
    <EventChairs></EventChairs>
    <EventModerators></EventModerators>
    <EventSpeakers>Chris Rasmussen</EventSpeakers>
    <EventSpeakerIDs>783841</EventSpeakerIDs>
    <EventSponsor></EventSponsor>
    <EventHandoutName>Abstract</EventHandoutName>
    <EventHandoutURL>http://meetings.siam.org/sess/dsp_talk.cfm?p=119912</EventHandoutURL>
    <EventDescription>In this talk I begin with a brief overview of what we know about the teaching and learning of calculus in the United States. In particular, I highlight findings from two large US national studies of the precalculus through calculus sequence . Next, I review what we know about the effects and uptake of research-based instructional strategies at the university level. I then reflect on new directions for the broader field of research in university mathematics education. These new directions include expanding the notion of inquiry, research related to departmental and institutional change, and research that centers issues of equity and social justice. 

	
</EventDescription>
    <EventParent>73755-SESS</EventParent>
    <EventUniqueID>73755-119912</EventUniqueID>
    <STATUS>active</STATUS>
    <AutoRecord>0</AutoRecord>
    <EnabledForIAV>0</EnabledForIAV>
    <MeetingIAVMode xsi:nil="true" />
    <PublishAutoRecordedVideo xsi:nil="true" />
    <Capacity xsi:nil="true" />
    <DirectLinkEnabled>0</DirectLinkEnabled>
    <DirectLinkRecordingEnabled xsi:nil="true" />
    <start>2022-07-11T14:00:00</start>
  </meeting>
  <meeting>
    <Confcode>ED22</Confcode>
    <EventName>RTG: Applied Mathematics and Statistics for Data-Driven Discovery</EventName>
    <EventSubName></EventSubName>
    <Poster></Poster>
    <EventNumber>MS2</EventNumber>
    <EventDate>Jul 11, 2022</EventDate>
    <EventStartTime>2022-07-11T08:30:00</EventStartTime>
    <EventEndTime>2022-07-11T10:30:00</EventEndTime>
    <EventFilter>ED22|Minisymposium</EventFilter>
    <EventLocation></EventLocation>
    <EventRoom>403</EventRoom>
    <FloorPlan></FloorPlan>
    <EVENT_FEE></EVENT_FEE>
    <EventKeywords>5100</EventKeywords>
    <EventChairs></EventChairs>
    <EventModerators></EventModerators>
    <EventSpeakers>Laura Miller</EventSpeakers>
    <EventSpeakerIDs>801430</EventSpeakerIDs>
    <EventSponsor></EventSponsor>
    <EventHandoutName>Abstract</EventHandoutName>
    <EventHandoutURL>http://meetings.siam.org/sess/dsp_talk.cfm?p=120910</EventHandoutURL>
    <EventDescription>The Data Driven Discovery RTG at the University of Arizona (UA) is a group of a dozen faculty spanning mathematics, applied &amp; computational math, and statistics, with a comparable number of graduate students and postdocs.  The RTG is dedicated to vertically integrated training in the use of data driven modeling techniques in the mathematical sciences, with applications ranging from medical imaging to fluid dynamics.  In this session, we will report on our experience and many lessons learned starting and running the RTG and the associated Research Experience for Undergraduates program during the COVID-19 pandemic, and our plans for the future.</EventDescription>
    <EventParent>74081-SESS</EventParent>
    <EventUniqueID>74081-120910</EventUniqueID>
    <STATUS>active</STATUS>
    <AutoRecord>0</AutoRecord>
    <EnabledForIAV>0</EnabledForIAV>
    <MeetingIAVMode xsi:nil="true" />
    <PublishAutoRecordedVideo xsi:nil="true" />
    <Capacity xsi:nil="true" />
    <DirectLinkEnabled>0</DirectLinkEnabled>
    <DirectLinkRecordingEnabled xsi:nil="true" />
    <start>2022-07-11T08:30:00</start>
  </meeting>
  <meeting>
    <Confcode>ED22</Confcode>
    <EventName>Mathematical Modeling Education: Developments in Spain</EventName>
    <EventSubName></EventSubName>
    <Poster></Poster>
    <EventNumber>MS4</EventNumber>
    <EventDate>Jul 11, 2022</EventDate>
    <EventStartTime>2022-07-11T08:30:00</EventStartTime>
    <EventEndTime>2022-07-11T10:30:00</EventEndTime>
    <EventFilter>ED22|Minisymposium</EventFilter>
    <EventLocation></EventLocation>
    <EventRoom>401</EventRoom>
    <FloorPlan></FloorPlan>
    <EVENT_FEE></EVENT_FEE>
    <EventKeywords>2800</EventKeywords>
    <EventChairs></EventChairs>
    <EventModerators></EventModerators>
    <EventSpeakers>Irene Ferrando Palomarese</EventSpeakers>
    <EventSpeakerIDs>805593</EventSpeakerIDs>
    <EventSponsor></EventSponsor>
    <EventHandoutName>Abstract</EventHandoutName>
    <EventHandoutURL>http://meetings.siam.org/sess/dsp_talk.cfm?p=120542</EventHandoutURL>
    <EventDescription>Despite the fact that the Spanish educational programmes include modelling as a content to be worked on in Mathematics in secondary education, the reality is that mathematical modelling has not yet effectively entered the classrooms. 
In 2019, after contacting some of the organisers of the IMMC, a group of Spanish mathematicians with different profiles, we started the selection phase of the competition in Spain. The development of the competition has been a challenge that has involved different agents and in which the work of dissemination has been crucial, but also that of teacher training. In order to choose the two teams that will represent Spain in the IMMC, we open the registration phase for teams in November. The organisers of the IMMC-Spain competition set a modelling problem common to all participants. A key aspect of our way of working is the correction; we do not limit ourselves to just qualifying the productions, but we also provide the participants with a qualitative evaluation. This is certainly a motivation for the participants as well as for the teachers. The teams with the best productions are invited to solve the problem in the international phase and the two best productions are selected to participate in the IMMC. 
This presentation will present the details of the selection of teams in Spain and will focus on the difficulties and the impact of modelling in the Spanish education system.
</EventDescription>
    <EventParent>74050-SESS</EventParent>
    <EventUniqueID>74050-120542</EventUniqueID>
    <STATUS>active</STATUS>
    <AutoRecord>0</AutoRecord>
    <EnabledForIAV>0</EnabledForIAV>
    <MeetingIAVMode xsi:nil="true" />
    <PublishAutoRecordedVideo xsi:nil="true" />
    <Capacity xsi:nil="true" />
    <DirectLinkEnabled>0</DirectLinkEnabled>
    <DirectLinkRecordingEnabled xsi:nil="true" />
    <start>2022-07-11T08:30:00</start>
  </meeting>
  <meeting>
    <Confcode>ED22</Confcode>
    <EventName>Mathematical Modeling Education: Developments in Chile</EventName>
    <EventSubName></EventSubName>
    <Poster></Poster>
    <EventNumber>MS4</EventNumber>
    <EventDate>Jul 11, 2022</EventDate>
    <EventStartTime>2022-07-11T08:30:00</EventStartTime>
    <EventEndTime>2022-07-11T10:30:00</EventEndTime>
    <EventFilter>ED22|Minisymposium</EventFilter>
    <EventLocation></EventLocation>
    <EventRoom>401</EventRoom>
    <FloorPlan></FloorPlan>
    <EVENT_FEE></EVENT_FEE>
    <EventKeywords>2800</EventKeywords>
    <EventChairs></EventChairs>
    <EventModerators></EventModerators>
    <EventSpeakers>Flavio Guiñez</EventSpeakers>
    <EventSpeakerIDs>805605</EventSpeakerIDs>
    <EventSponsor></EventSponsor>
    <EventHandoutName>Abstract</EventHandoutName>
    <EventHandoutURL>http://meetings.siam.org/sess/dsp_talk.cfm?p=120567</EventHandoutURL>
    <EventDescription>The mathematics curriculum in Chile has modeling as one of the fundamental skills to be developed by students. Even though for primary and middle school this was introduced almost a decade ago, the evidence we have and our own personal experience suggest that teachers are not being prepared to teach it and that students have little opportunities to work with real-world mathematical modeling problems.

In this talk we will present an overview of different initiatives the Laboratory of Math Education of the Center for Mathematical Modeling (CMM-Edu) of Universidad de Chile has developed to help to improve this situation. The first one is the selection process for the International Mathematical Modeling Challenge (IMMC), which is an annual school-level team-based contest. We will describe what we have learned from running the process, particularly some findings of a study that focuses on the changes on students’ conceptions about the nature of mathematics that could be triggered when working autonomously in modeling problems. 

We will also present other two initiatives that focus on improving teacher preparation to teach modeling: a course of mathematical modeling for a pre-service teacher education program and an online course for in-service teachers which is run nationwide. In both cases we will describe the instructional model, give examples of activities and present some results of the implementation.


</EventDescription>
    <EventParent>74050-SESS</EventParent>
    <EventUniqueID>74050-120567</EventUniqueID>
    <STATUS>active</STATUS>
    <AutoRecord>0</AutoRecord>
    <EnabledForIAV>0</EnabledForIAV>
    <MeetingIAVMode xsi:nil="true" />
    <PublishAutoRecordedVideo xsi:nil="true" />
    <Capacity xsi:nil="true" />
    <DirectLinkEnabled>0</DirectLinkEnabled>
    <DirectLinkRecordingEnabled xsi:nil="true" />
    <start>2022-07-11T08:30:00</start>
  </meeting>
  <meeting>
    <Confcode>ED22</Confcode>
    <EventName>NSF Research Training Groups in the Mathematical Sciences</EventName>
    <EventSubName></EventSubName>
    <Poster></Poster>
    <EventNumber>MS7</EventNumber>
    <EventDate>Jul 11, 2022</EventDate>
    <EventStartTime>2022-07-11T17:30:00</EventStartTime>
    <EventEndTime>2022-07-11T17:55:00</EventEndTime>
    <EventFilter>ED22|Minisymposium</EventFilter>
    <EventLocation></EventLocation>
    <EventRoom>403</EventRoom>
    <FloorPlan></FloorPlan>
    <EVENT_FEE></EVENT_FEE>
    <EventKeywords>5100</EventKeywords>
    <EventChairs></EventChairs>
    <EventModerators></EventModerators>
    <EventSpeakers>Eun Heui Kim</EventSpeakers>
    <EventSpeakerIDs>805838</EventSpeakerIDs>
    <EventSponsor></EventSponsor>
    <EventHandoutName>Abstract</EventHandoutName>
    <EventHandoutURL>http://meetings.siam.org/sess/dsp_talk.cfm?p=121102</EventHandoutURL>
    <EventDescription>This will be a short presentation about the NSF Research Training Groups in the Mathematical Sciences (RTG). We will discuss a brief overview of the RTG program solicitation, followed by a Q&amp;A. 
</EventDescription>
    <EventParent>74082-SESS</EventParent>
    <EventUniqueID>74082-121102</EventUniqueID>
    <STATUS>active</STATUS>
    <AutoRecord>0</AutoRecord>
    <EnabledForIAV>0</EnabledForIAV>
    <MeetingIAVMode xsi:nil="true" />
    <PublishAutoRecordedVideo xsi:nil="true" />
    <Capacity xsi:nil="true" />
    <DirectLinkEnabled>0</DirectLinkEnabled>
    <DirectLinkRecordingEnabled xsi:nil="true" />
    <start>2022-07-11T16:00:00</start>
  </meeting>
  <meeting>
    <Confcode>ED22</Confcode>
    <EventName>Historical Developments of ODE Techniques : The Laplace Transform</EventName>
    <EventSubName></EventSubName>
    <Poster></Poster>
    <EventNumber>MS9</EventNumber>
    <EventDate>Jul 11, 2022</EventDate>
    <EventStartTime>2022-07-11T16:00:00</EventStartTime>
    <EventEndTime>2022-07-11T18:00:00</EventEndTime>
    <EventFilter>ED22|Minisymposium</EventFilter>
    <EventLocation></EventLocation>
    <EventRoom>401</EventRoom>
    <FloorPlan></FloorPlan>
    <EVENT_FEE></EVENT_FEE>
    <EventKeywords>300</EventKeywords>
    <EventChairs></EventChairs>
    <EventModerators></EventModerators>
    <EventSpeakers>Adam Parker</EventSpeakers>
    <EventSpeakerIDs>805785</EventSpeakerIDs>
    <EventSponsor></EventSponsor>
    <EventHandoutName>Abstract</EventHandoutName>
    <EventHandoutURL>http://meetings.siam.org/sess/dsp_talk.cfm?p=121072</EventHandoutURL>
    <EventDescription>The Laplace Transform $\mathcal{L}\{f(s)\} = \int_0^\infty f(t)e^{-st}dt$ had a long and convoluted history before it arrived in the form students see in a standard Ordinary Differential Equation textbook.   Indeed, Deakin in 1981 and 1982 identified over $30$ well-known mathematicians that made important contributions to its development.  While utilizing history and primary sources in teaching mathematics has pedagogical benefits, this  history of the Laplace Transform is much too complicated to be of use in the classroom.  Today, we present a simplified version that traces the history form Euler, to Laplace, and then to Oliver Heaviside and his Operational Calculus.  We will present their contributions along with some historical examples, both of which can be used in an Ordinary Differential Equations course.

</EventDescription>
    <EventParent>74180-SESS</EventParent>
    <EventUniqueID>74180-121072</EventUniqueID>
    <STATUS>active</STATUS>
    <AutoRecord>0</AutoRecord>
    <EnabledForIAV>0</EnabledForIAV>
    <MeetingIAVMode xsi:nil="true" />
    <PublishAutoRecordedVideo xsi:nil="true" />
    <Capacity xsi:nil="true" />
    <DirectLinkEnabled>0</DirectLinkEnabled>
    <DirectLinkRecordingEnabled xsi:nil="true" />
    <start>2022-07-11T16:00:00</start>
  </meeting>
  <meeting>
    <Confcode>ED22</Confcode>
    <EventName>Teaching Discrete Modeling Topics First in Mathematics for the Life Sciences</EventName>
    <EventSubName></EventSubName>
    <Poster></Poster>
    <EventNumber>MS11</EventNumber>
    <EventDate>Jul 12, 2022</EventDate>
    <EventStartTime>2022-07-12T08:30:00</EventStartTime>
    <EventEndTime>2022-07-12T10:30:00</EventEndTime>
    <EventFilter>ED22|Minisymposium</EventFilter>
    <EventLocation></EventLocation>
    <EventRoom>405</EventRoom>
    <FloorPlan></FloorPlan>
    <EVENT_FEE></EVENT_FEE>
    <EventKeywords>2800</EventKeywords>
    <EventChairs></EventChairs>
    <EventModerators></EventModerators>
    <EventSpeakers>Suzanne Lenhart</EventSpeakers>
    <EventSpeakerIDs>4007</EventSpeakerIDs>
    <EventSponsor></EventSponsor>
    <EventHandoutName>Abstract</EventHandoutName>
    <EventHandoutURL>http://meetings.siam.org/sess/dsp_talk.cfm?p=120080</EventHandoutURL>
    <EventDescription>In our Mathematics for the Life Sciences course, we use the 
Rule of Five for different learning styles to meet needs of diverse students: Symbolically, Graphically, Numerically, Verbally, Data-driven.
The concepts and skills in our course help students to appreciate  the components of the modeling process, including assessing hypotheses based on data, formulating a mathematical description of a system based on assumptions, and by analyzing the resulting model. We begin our course with discrete mathematics involving analyzing  data and discrete time modeling, instead of starting with calculus.  We have incorporated MATLAB to introduce basic computer coding and the concepts of algorithms that are applied throughout computational methods in science.  We have also developed an  assessment tool to begin to evaluate  the impact of biological examples on mathematics comprehension in courses for life sciences majors. 

</EventDescription>
    <EventParent>73886-SESS</EventParent>
    <EventUniqueID>73886-120080</EventUniqueID>
    <STATUS>active</STATUS>
    <AutoRecord>0</AutoRecord>
    <EnabledForIAV>0</EnabledForIAV>
    <MeetingIAVMode xsi:nil="true" />
    <PublishAutoRecordedVideo xsi:nil="true" />
    <Capacity xsi:nil="true" />
    <DirectLinkEnabled>0</DirectLinkEnabled>
    <DirectLinkRecordingEnabled xsi:nil="true" />
    <start>2022-07-12T08:30:00</start>
  </meeting>
  <meeting>
    <Confcode>ED22</Confcode>
    <EventName>A Simiode Textbook Example: Hot Potatoes and Parameter Estimation</EventName>
    <EventSubName></EventSubName>
    <Poster></Poster>
    <EventNumber>MS14</EventNumber>
    <EventDate>Jul 12, 2022</EventDate>
    <EventStartTime>2022-07-12T08:30:00</EventStartTime>
    <EventEndTime>2022-07-12T10:30:00</EventEndTime>
    <EventFilter>ED22|Minisymposium</EventFilter>
    <EventLocation></EventLocation>
    <EventRoom>402</EventRoom>
    <FloorPlan></FloorPlan>
    <EVENT_FEE></EVENT_FEE>
    <EventKeywords>2800</EventKeywords>
    <EventChairs></EventChairs>
    <EventModerators></EventModerators>
    <EventSpeakers>Kurt Bryan</EventSpeakers>
    <EventSpeakerIDs>711505</EventSpeakerIDs>
    <EventSponsor></EventSponsor>
    <EventHandoutName>Abstract</EventHandoutName>
    <EventHandoutURL>http://meetings.siam.org/sess/dsp_talk.cfm?p=121310</EventHandoutURL>
    <EventDescription>A modeling-driven approach to motivate the study of ODEs works best when we ``close the loop' in the modeling process, by validating our model against real data. This frequently involves the estimation of unknown parameters in the ODE. We introduce this approach using data concerning the cooling of a hot potato. This data can easily be collected in the classroom and modeled with variations of Newton's Law of Cooling. The important parameters can be estimated using a least-squares approach. We also discuss the Akaike Information Criterion, a means for determining how many and which parameters can reasonably be estimated.</EventDescription>
    <EventParent>74292-SESS</EventParent>
    <EventUniqueID>74292-121310</EventUniqueID>
    <STATUS>active</STATUS>
    <AutoRecord>0</AutoRecord>
    <EnabledForIAV>0</EnabledForIAV>
    <MeetingIAVMode xsi:nil="true" />
    <PublishAutoRecordedVideo xsi:nil="true" />
    <Capacity xsi:nil="true" />
    <DirectLinkEnabled>0</DirectLinkEnabled>
    <DirectLinkRecordingEnabled xsi:nil="true" />
    <start>2022-07-12T08:30:00</start>
  </meeting>
  <meeting>
    <Confcode>ED22</Confcode>
    <EventName>Walking in Brunelleschi’s Footsteps</EventName>
    <EventSubName></EventSubName>
    <Poster></Poster>
    <EventNumber>MS17</EventNumber>
    <EventDate>Jul 12, 2022</EventDate>
    <EventStartTime>2022-07-12T16:00:00</EventStartTime>
    <EventEndTime>2022-07-12T18:00:00</EventEndTime>
    <EventFilter>ED22|Minisymposium</EventFilter>
    <EventLocation></EventLocation>
    <EventRoom>403</EventRoom>
    <FloorPlan></FloorPlan>
    <EVENT_FEE></EVENT_FEE>
    <EventKeywords>2800</EventKeywords>
    <EventChairs></EventChairs>
    <EventModerators></EventModerators>
    <EventSpeakers>Mel Henriksen</EventSpeakers>
    <EventSpeakerIDs>783243</EventSpeakerIDs>
    <EventSponsor></EventSponsor>
    <EventHandoutName>Abstract</EventHandoutName>
    <EventHandoutURL>http://meetings.siam.org/sess/dsp_talk.cfm?p=121007</EventHandoutURL>
    <EventDescription>The dome of the Cathedral of Florence is designed as the upper halves of four intersecting cylinders. It was engineered by Filippo Brunelleschi and completed in 1436. Before modern construction techniques, it was the largest dome in the world and remains the largest brick dome in the world today. 

In this Calculus project, students extend the techniques of calculating volumes of solids of revolution as well as arc length and surface area. They begin by first calculating the volume of a Roman Vault, a structure designed as two intersecting cylinders. Students then calculate the volume of the inner dome of the Cathedral of Florence by developing an appropriate integral and evaluating it. They also calculate the arc length of the cylinder intersections of the cathedral dome.

Once the computations are complete, students present their findings with posters in groups. This project encourages students not only to work collaboratively on an application of what they learned in class, but also to practice their soft skills of communicating their findings in an engaging and visually appealing manner.
</EventDescription>
    <EventParent>74201-SESS</EventParent>
    <EventUniqueID>74201-121007</EventUniqueID>
    <STATUS>active</STATUS>
    <AutoRecord>0</AutoRecord>
    <EnabledForIAV>0</EnabledForIAV>
    <MeetingIAVMode xsi:nil="true" />
    <PublishAutoRecordedVideo xsi:nil="true" />
    <Capacity xsi:nil="true" />
    <DirectLinkEnabled>0</DirectLinkEnabled>
    <DirectLinkRecordingEnabled xsi:nil="true" />
    <start>2022-07-12T16:00:00</start>
  </meeting>
  <meeting>
    <Confcode>ED22</Confcode>
    <EventName>Role of Guided Reflections in Teaching Proofs</EventName>
    <EventSubName></EventSubName>
    <Poster></Poster>
    <EventNumber>MS18</EventNumber>
    <EventDate>Jul 12, 2022</EventDate>
    <EventStartTime>2022-07-12T16:00:00</EventStartTime>
    <EventEndTime>2022-07-12T18:00:00</EventEndTime>
    <EventFilter>ED22|Minisymposium</EventFilter>
    <EventLocation></EventLocation>
    <EventRoom>402</EventRoom>
    <FloorPlan></FloorPlan>
    <EVENT_FEE></EVENT_FEE>
    <EventKeywords>2800</EventKeywords>
    <EventChairs></EventChairs>
    <EventModerators></EventModerators>
    <EventSpeakers>Kathleen Hoffman</EventSpeakers>
    <EventSpeakerIDs>701395</EventSpeakerIDs>
    <EventSponsor></EventSponsor>
    <EventHandoutName>Abstract</EventHandoutName>
    <EventHandoutURL>http://meetings.siam.org/sess/dsp_talk.cfm?p=120096</EventHandoutURL>
    <EventDescription>An interventional course in Introduction to Mathematical Reasoning was developed to mitigate the difficulty of learning to write proofs in a content-based upper level math course. As part of the interventional course, enrolled students were asked to write weekly self-reflections guided by the mechanical, structural, creative, and critical modalities of thinking in proof writing. We categorized  the quality of the students’ responses, and within each category  calculated average course grades in the interventional course, the prerequisite math course, and the advanced core course. Results demonstrated that high quality self-reflection responses were significant predictors of higher average course grades in the interventional course and the advanced course, but not in the prerequisite course. When reflecting on their mastery of the modalities on a rubric-based Likert scale, students’ self-reported scores approached those of an expert grader’s over the duration of the semester. The resulting correlation suggests that repeated exposure to guided-self-reflection may support growth in students’ awareness of their own abilities pertaining to proof writing using the lens of the modalities. Together, these results support the potential power of repeated, modality-based self-reflections as a strategy to improve student outcomes in future advanced math courses.</EventDescription>
    <EventParent>73891-SESS</EventParent>
    <EventUniqueID>73891-120096</EventUniqueID>
    <STATUS>active</STATUS>
    <AutoRecord>0</AutoRecord>
    <EnabledForIAV>0</EnabledForIAV>
    <MeetingIAVMode xsi:nil="true" />
    <PublishAutoRecordedVideo xsi:nil="true" />
    <Capacity xsi:nil="true" />
    <DirectLinkEnabled>0</DirectLinkEnabled>
    <DirectLinkRecordingEnabled xsi:nil="true" />
    <start>2022-07-12T16:00:00</start>
  </meeting>
  <meeting>
    <Confcode>ED22</Confcode>
    <EventName>Industrial &amp; Applied Mathematics and Data Science Education at Metropolitan State University</EventName>
    <EventSubName></EventSubName>
    <Poster></Poster>
    <EventNumber>CP2</EventNumber>
    <EventDate>Jul 12, 2022</EventDate>
    <EventStartTime>2022-07-12T17:00:00</EventStartTime>
    <EventEndTime>2022-07-12T17:15:00</EventEndTime>
    <EventFilter>ED22|Contributed</EventFilter>
    <EventLocation></EventLocation>
    <EventRoom>406</EventRoom>
    <FloorPlan></FloorPlan>
    <EVENT_FEE></EVENT_FEE>
    <EventKeywords></EventKeywords>
    <EventChairs></EventChairs>
    <EventModerators></EventModerators>
    <EventSpeakers>Rikki Wagstrom</EventSpeakers>
    <EventSpeakerIDs>805361</EventSpeakerIDs>
    <EventSponsor></EventSponsor>
    <EventHandoutName>Abstract</EventHandoutName>
    <EventHandoutURL>http://meetings.siam.org/sess/dsp_talk.cfm?p=120000</EventHandoutURL>
    <EventDescription>In response to an alumni survey conducted in 2017, the Mathematics &amp; Statistics Department at Metropolitan State University in Minnesota is transforming its applied mathematics education and offering pre-professional opportunities to support career readiness. The University serves students of diverse backgrounds, with a particular focus on adult learners and communities of color. The initiatives undertaken by the department are designed to support the diverse challenges and interests of these students. Initiatives include the creation of an Industry Advisory Board with representation from a range of Twin Cities-based companies, programmatic additions and changes, course development and redesign, and pre-professional opportunities including job shadowing, mentoring, supervised consulting, and internships. The department recently launched the Industrial &amp; Applied Mathematics BS integrating mathematical, statistical, and computational skills with increased emphasis on modeling, exposure to complex open-ended problems, technical communication skills, and teamwork. Collaboration with the Computer Science and Management Information Systems Departments has resulted in the creation of a Data Science BS with many of the same emphases. This presentation will describe these initiatives.

	</EventDescription>
    <EventParent>74689-SESS</EventParent>
    <EventUniqueID>74689-120000</EventUniqueID>
    <STATUS>active</STATUS>
    <AutoRecord>0</AutoRecord>
    <EnabledForIAV>0</EnabledForIAV>
    <MeetingIAVMode xsi:nil="true" />
    <PublishAutoRecordedVideo xsi:nil="true" />
    <Capacity xsi:nil="true" />
    <DirectLinkEnabled>0</DirectLinkEnabled>
    <DirectLinkRecordingEnabled xsi:nil="true" />
    <start>2022-07-12T16:00:00</start>
  </meeting>
  <meeting>
    <Confcode>ED22</Confcode>
    <EventName>Math &amp; Industry: Running An Industrial Mathematics Research Experience for Undergraduates</EventName>
    <EventSubName></EventSubName>
    <Poster></Poster>
    <EventNumber>MS1</EventNumber>
    <EventDate>Jul 11, 2022</EventDate>
    <EventStartTime>2022-07-11T08:30:00</EventStartTime>
    <EventEndTime>2022-07-11T10:30:00</EventEndTime>
    <EventFilter>ED22|Minisymposium</EventFilter>
    <EventLocation></EventLocation>
    <EventRoom>406</EventRoom>
    <FloorPlan></FloorPlan>
    <EVENT_FEE></EVENT_FEE>
    <EventKeywords>2800</EventKeywords>
    <EventChairs></EventChairs>
    <EventModerators></EventModerators>
    <EventSpeakers>Burt Tilley</EventSpeakers>
    <EventSpeakerIDs>739164</EventSpeakerIDs>
    <EventSponsor></EventSponsor>
    <EventHandoutName>Abstract</EventHandoutName>
    <EventHandoutURL>http://meetings.siam.org/sess/dsp_talk.cfm?p=121100</EventHandoutURL>
    <EventDescription>In the Worcester Polytechnic Institute (WPI) Center for Industrial Mathematics and Statistics (CIMS) Research Experiences for Undergraduates (REU) Program in Industrial Mathematics and Statistics, students work in teams on research problems of industrial and mathematical significance that come directly from industry, and which are of immediate interest to the companies involved in the program.  They work closely with company representatives to define the problem and develop solutions, and they work closely with faculty advisors to maintain a clear focus on the mathematics and statistics at the core of the project.  This nine-week, summer research  provides challenges not faced in standard undergraduate programs and develops skills not always developed in traditional educational programs.  It also provides a glimpse of the many career possibilities that are open to students with a strong mathematical background. This NSF-funded REU Program has been held at WPI during the summers of 1998--2015 and 2018--present.  In this talk, I discuss the structure, planning, and implementation of this summer program, and its broader impacts.
</EventDescription>
    <EventParent>74229-SESS</EventParent>
    <EventUniqueID>74229-121100</EventUniqueID>
    <STATUS>active</STATUS>
    <AutoRecord>0</AutoRecord>
    <EnabledForIAV>0</EnabledForIAV>
    <MeetingIAVMode xsi:nil="true" />
    <PublishAutoRecordedVideo xsi:nil="true" />
    <Capacity xsi:nil="true" />
    <DirectLinkEnabled>0</DirectLinkEnabled>
    <DirectLinkRecordingEnabled xsi:nil="true" />
    <start>2022-07-11T08:30:00</start>
  </meeting>
  <meeting>
    <Confcode>ED22</Confcode>
    <EventName>Logistics of Running a Hybrid Problem-Solving Workshop Involving Graduate Students</EventName>
    <EventSubName></EventSubName>
    <Poster></Poster>
    <EventNumber>MS1</EventNumber>
    <EventDate>Jul 11, 2022</EventDate>
    <EventStartTime>2022-07-11T08:30:00</EventStartTime>
    <EventEndTime>2022-07-11T10:30:00</EventEndTime>
    <EventFilter>ED22|Minisymposium</EventFilter>
    <EventLocation></EventLocation>
    <EventRoom>406</EventRoom>
    <FloorPlan></FloorPlan>
    <EVENT_FEE></EVENT_FEE>
    <EventKeywords>2800</EventKeywords>
    <EventChairs></EventChairs>
    <EventModerators></EventModerators>
    <EventSpeakers>Taras Lakoba</EventSpeakers>
    <EventSpeakerIDs>715127</EventSpeakerIDs>
    <EventSponsor></EventSponsor>
    <EventHandoutName>Abstract</EventHandoutName>
    <EventHandoutURL>http://meetings.siam.org/sess/dsp_talk.cfm?p=121104</EventHandoutURL>
    <EventDescription>Due to the pandemic, the Mathematical Problems in Industry workshop in 2020 and 2021 was hosted online. One advantage of this format was the ability to bring in academic participants from different continents (mostly America and Europe) without incurring significant expenses. It also allowed some participants the flexibility to contribute only part of their time to the workshop, which, for some, was an incentive to participate. The online format also introduced or made more prominent a number of challenges. Following below is a list of some choices that needed to be made to address those challenges.
\begin{itemize}
\item
A platform that would allow the interaction among participants to mimic that in an in-person workshop; MS Teams was chosen for the task.
\item
A schedule that would accommodate participants from time zones differing by as much as 8 hours.
\item
A means of maintaining continuity among groups working in different time zones.
\item
Of paramount importance for both online and in-person workshop is the commitment of industrial participants to guide their academic group. This puts the responsibility on the organizers to convey this importance to the industrial participants. 
\end{itemize}
These issues will be addressed in detail in this talk. 
</EventDescription>
    <EventParent>74229-SESS</EventParent>
    <EventUniqueID>74229-121104</EventUniqueID>
    <STATUS>active</STATUS>
    <AutoRecord>0</AutoRecord>
    <EnabledForIAV>0</EnabledForIAV>
    <MeetingIAVMode xsi:nil="true" />
    <PublishAutoRecordedVideo xsi:nil="true" />
    <Capacity xsi:nil="true" />
    <DirectLinkEnabled>0</DirectLinkEnabled>
    <DirectLinkRecordingEnabled xsi:nil="true" />
    <start>2022-07-11T08:30:00</start>
  </meeting>
  <meeting>
    <Confcode>ED22</Confcode>
    <EventName>Graduate Pre-Service Teacher Preparation for High-Need Schools</EventName>
    <EventSubName></EventSubName>
    <Poster></Poster>
    <EventNumber>MS3</EventNumber>
    <EventDate>Jul 11, 2022</EventDate>
    <EventStartTime>2022-07-11T08:30:00</EventStartTime>
    <EventEndTime>2022-07-11T08:55:00</EventEndTime>
    <EventFilter>ED22|Minisymposium</EventFilter>
    <EventLocation></EventLocation>
    <EventRoom>402</EventRoom>
    <FloorPlan></FloorPlan>
    <EVENT_FEE></EVENT_FEE>
    <EventKeywords>2800</EventKeywords>
    <EventChairs></EventChairs>
    <EventModerators></EventModerators>
    <EventSpeakers>Ben Galluzzo</EventSpeakers>
    <EventSpeakerIDs>784709</EventSpeakerIDs>
    <EventSponsor></EventSponsor>
    <EventHandoutName>Abstract</EventHandoutName>
    <EventHandoutURL>http://meetings.siam.org/sess/dsp_talk.cfm?p=120311</EventHandoutURL>
    <EventDescription>In preparation for their work in high-need schools, the Clarkson University Noyce Program provides scholars with opportunities to learn more about the environments and communities that they will be working in.  As a part of their Masters of Arts in Teaching program, they complete a full-year residency as part of their program and complete an action research project, in addition to other coursework.  The Noyce scholars also reflect on their teaching, focusing on equity and how they respond and relate to their students.  The program provides students opportunities to talk to current teachers in both rural and urban schools to find out what is unique about working in their district in addition to equity-focused activities. In this session, we share about the aspects of the program we find to be successful, and also raise questions and ideas on how to improve the program for future scholars.

</EventDescription>
    <EventParent>73964-SESS</EventParent>
    <EventUniqueID>73964-120311</EventUniqueID>
    <STATUS>active</STATUS>
    <AutoRecord>0</AutoRecord>
    <EnabledForIAV>0</EnabledForIAV>
    <MeetingIAVMode xsi:nil="true" />
    <PublishAutoRecordedVideo xsi:nil="true" />
    <Capacity xsi:nil="true" />
    <DirectLinkEnabled>0</DirectLinkEnabled>
    <DirectLinkRecordingEnabled xsi:nil="true" />
    <start>2022-07-11T08:30:00</start>
  </meeting>
  <meeting>
    <Confcode>ED22</Confcode>
    <EventName>How Statistical Model Development Can Obscure Inequities in Stem Student Outcomes</EventName>
    <EventSubName></EventSubName>
    <Poster></Poster>
    <EventNumber>MS6</EventNumber>
    <EventDate>Jul 11, 2022</EventDate>
    <EventStartTime>2022-07-11T16:30:00</EventStartTime>
    <EventEndTime>2022-07-11T16:55:00</EventEndTime>
    <EventFilter>ED22|Minisymposium</EventFilter>
    <EventLocation></EventLocation>
    <EventRoom>404</EventRoom>
    <FloorPlan></FloorPlan>
    <EVENT_FEE></EVENT_FEE>
    <EventKeywords>2800</EventKeywords>
    <EventChairs></EventChairs>
    <EventModerators></EventModerators>
    <EventSpeakers>Ben Van Dusen</EventSpeakers>
    <EventSpeakerIDs>806414</EventSpeakerIDs>
    <EventSponsor></EventSponsor>
    <EventHandoutName>Abstract</EventHandoutName>
    <EventHandoutURL>http://meetings.siam.org/sess/dsp_talk.cfm?p=121550</EventHandoutURL>
    <EventDescription>Researchers often frame quantitative research as objective, but every step in data collection and analysis can bias findings in often unexamined ways. In this investigation, we examined how the process of selecting variables to include in regression models (model specification) can bias findings about inequities in science and math student outcomes. We identified the four most used methods for model specification in discipline-based education research about equity: a priori, statistical significance, variance explained, and information criterion. Using a quantitative critical perspective that blends statistical theory with critical theory, we reanalyzed the data from a prior publication using each of the four methods and compared the findings from each. We will discuss how these practices can obscure inequities and which methods are best suited for research into issues of equity in the STEM disciplines.
</EventDescription>
    <EventParent>74336-SESS</EventParent>
    <EventUniqueID>74336-121550</EventUniqueID>
    <STATUS>active</STATUS>
    <AutoRecord>0</AutoRecord>
    <EnabledForIAV>0</EnabledForIAV>
    <MeetingIAVMode xsi:nil="true" />
    <PublishAutoRecordedVideo xsi:nil="true" />
    <Capacity xsi:nil="true" />
    <DirectLinkEnabled>0</DirectLinkEnabled>
    <DirectLinkRecordingEnabled xsi:nil="true" />
    <start>2022-07-11T16:00:00</start>
  </meeting>
  <meeting>
    <Confcode>ED22</Confcode>
    <EventName>Research in Mathematical Modeling for Secondary Teacher Education</EventName>
    <EventSubName></EventSubName>
    <Poster></Poster>
    <EventNumber>MS8</EventNumber>
    <EventDate>Jul 11, 2022</EventDate>
    <EventStartTime>2022-07-11T16:00:00</EventStartTime>
    <EventEndTime>2022-07-11T18:00:00</EventEndTime>
    <EventFilter>ED22|Minisymposium</EventFilter>
    <EventLocation></EventLocation>
    <EventRoom>402</EventRoom>
    <FloorPlan></FloorPlan>
    <EVENT_FEE></EVENT_FEE>
    <EventKeywords>3000</EventKeywords>
    <EventChairs></EventChairs>
    <EventModerators></EventModerators>
    <EventSpeakers>Cynthia Anhalt</EventSpeakers>
    <EventSpeakerIDs>773408</EventSpeakerIDs>
    <EventSponsor></EventSponsor>
    <EventHandoutName>Abstract</EventHandoutName>
    <EventHandoutURL>http://meetings.siam.org/sess/dsp_talk.cfm?p=120970</EventHandoutURL>
    <EventDescription>Research in prospective teachers’ development of mathematical modeling knowledge for teaching is gaining momentum.  We found that project-based mathematical modeling experiences provide opportunities for prospective secondary teachers to develop foundational knowledge in modeling and a vision for teaching and learning mathematical modeling.  We designed modeling problems for the MODULE(S2) Project with a variety of social contexts that allow prospective teachers to examine critical social issues to consider in their future teaching. We describe two modeling projects: (1) the use of sandbags as emergency barriers for damage-causing flooding, and (2) the use of historic maps to examine the shrinking land of the Sioux Reservation. The first problem focuses on the arrangement of sandbags as standard protocol by safety guidelines, and the latter explores different methods for finding the area of land in connection to the injustice deeply rooted in the treatment of indigenous people. Both problems call for explicit attention to pedagogical knowledge in structuring discussions around the contextualization of the mathematical results.  Our work informs teacher preparation programs for inclusion of mathematical modeling with authentic social contexts that embrace meaningful curriculum.


</EventDescription>
    <EventParent>74198-SESS</EventParent>
    <EventUniqueID>74198-120970</EventUniqueID>
    <STATUS>active</STATUS>
    <AutoRecord>0</AutoRecord>
    <EnabledForIAV>0</EnabledForIAV>
    <MeetingIAVMode xsi:nil="true" />
    <PublishAutoRecordedVideo xsi:nil="true" />
    <Capacity xsi:nil="true" />
    <DirectLinkEnabled>0</DirectLinkEnabled>
    <DirectLinkRecordingEnabled xsi:nil="true" />
    <start>2022-07-11T16:00:00</start>
  </meeting>
  <meeting>
    <Confcode>ED22</Confcode>
    <EventName>Historical Experiments in a Mathematical Modeling Course</EventName>
    <EventSubName></EventSubName>
    <Poster></Poster>
    <EventNumber>MS9</EventNumber>
    <EventDate>Jul 11, 2022</EventDate>
    <EventStartTime>2022-07-11T16:00:00</EventStartTime>
    <EventEndTime>2022-07-11T18:00:00</EventEndTime>
    <EventFilter>ED22|Minisymposium</EventFilter>
    <EventLocation></EventLocation>
    <EventRoom>401</EventRoom>
    <FloorPlan></FloorPlan>
    <EVENT_FEE></EVENT_FEE>
    <EventKeywords>300</EventKeywords>
    <EventChairs></EventChairs>
    <EventModerators></EventModerators>
    <EventSpeakers>Patrick Shipman</EventSpeakers>
    <EventSpeakerIDs>751042</EventSpeakerIDs>
    <EventSponsor></EventSponsor>
    <EventHandoutName>Abstract</EventHandoutName>
    <EventHandoutURL>http://meetings.siam.org/sess/dsp_talk.cfm?p=120948</EventHandoutURL>
    <EventDescription>Experiments in optics and the understanding of matter have contributed to advances in mathematics. We describe historical experiments that may be replicated in classrooms as part of introductory courses in mathematical modeling.      </EventDescription>
    <EventParent>74180-SESS</EventParent>
    <EventUniqueID>74180-120948</EventUniqueID>
    <STATUS>active</STATUS>
    <AutoRecord>0</AutoRecord>
    <EnabledForIAV>0</EnabledForIAV>
    <MeetingIAVMode xsi:nil="true" />
    <PublishAutoRecordedVideo xsi:nil="true" />
    <Capacity xsi:nil="true" />
    <DirectLinkEnabled>0</DirectLinkEnabled>
    <DirectLinkRecordingEnabled xsi:nil="true" />
    <start>2022-07-11T16:00:00</start>
  </meeting>
  <meeting>
    <Confcode>ED22</Confcode>
    <EventName>Research with First-Year STEM Students</EventName>
    <EventSubName></EventSubName>
    <Poster></Poster>
    <EventNumber>MS16</EventNumber>
    <EventDate>Jul 12, 2022</EventDate>
    <EventStartTime>2022-07-12T16:00:00</EventStartTime>
    <EventEndTime>2022-07-12T16:25:00</EventEndTime>
    <EventFilter>ED22|Minisymposium</EventFilter>
    <EventLocation></EventLocation>
    <EventRoom>404</EventRoom>
    <FloorPlan></FloorPlan>
    <EVENT_FEE></EVENT_FEE>
    <EventKeywords>2800</EventKeywords>
    <EventChairs></EventChairs>
    <EventModerators></EventModerators>
    <EventSpeakers>Axel Brandt</EventSpeakers>
    <EventSpeakerIDs>782398</EventSpeakerIDs>
    <EventSponsor></EventSponsor>
    <EventHandoutName>Abstract</EventHandoutName>
    <EventHandoutURL>http://meetings.siam.org/sess/dsp_talk.cfm?p=120302</EventHandoutURL>
    <EventDescription>Motivated by evidence correlating undergraduate research (UR) with better retention and engagement, Northern Kentucky University facilitates two programs that provide first-year students with UR opportunities in STEM. In this talk, we discuss math-focused UR for students in these programs.

The UR-STEM program provides summer UR opportunities for students early in their college careers. Initiated with NSF funds and now sustained through NKU’s Center for Integrative Natural Science and Mathematics, the paid UR program utilizes an open application and prioritized selection model to include students at-risk of leaving a STEM major. Data from 2017-2021 indicates student participants have been retained at significantly higher levels than non-participants (94\% in STEM major, 98\% at NKU).

Supported by NSF funds, the STEM Ready program seeks to improve mathematics preparation and retention of students interested in STEM. During the two-week summer bridge program, STEM Ready participants complete three guided UR projects: one in biology, chemistry, and data science. Preliminary data suggest participants benefit from the program. The cumulative GPA and grades in participants’ first math course for the summer 2020 cohort (N=22; 50\% PEERs, first-generation, and low-income; ACT mean 22.2, median 23) were equivalent to other first-year STEM majors (ACT mean 24.6, median 25) and their retention at NKU into spring semester was slightly higher (91\% vs 77\%).





</EventDescription>
    <EventParent>73861-SESS</EventParent>
    <EventUniqueID>73861-120302</EventUniqueID>
    <STATUS>active</STATUS>
    <AutoRecord>0</AutoRecord>
    <EnabledForIAV>0</EnabledForIAV>
    <MeetingIAVMode xsi:nil="true" />
    <PublishAutoRecordedVideo xsi:nil="true" />
    <Capacity xsi:nil="true" />
    <DirectLinkEnabled>0</DirectLinkEnabled>
    <DirectLinkRecordingEnabled xsi:nil="true" />
    <start>2022-07-12T16:00:00</start>
  </meeting>
  <meeting>
    <Confcode>ED22</Confcode>
    <EventName>Bridging the Gap Between High School and Undergraduate Mathematics by Exploring Problems in Ecological Modeling: Training Tomorrow’s Leaders in Stem Mentorship</EventName>
    <EventSubName></EventSubName>
    <Poster></Poster>
    <EventNumber>MS16</EventNumber>
    <EventDate>Jul 12, 2022</EventDate>
    <EventStartTime>2022-07-12T16:30:00</EventStartTime>
    <EventEndTime>2022-07-12T16:55:00</EventEndTime>
    <EventFilter>ED22|Minisymposium</EventFilter>
    <EventLocation></EventLocation>
    <EventRoom>404</EventRoom>
    <FloorPlan></FloorPlan>
    <EVENT_FEE></EVENT_FEE>
    <EventKeywords>2800</EventKeywords>
    <EventChairs></EventChairs>
    <EventModerators></EventModerators>
    <EventSpeakers>Diana White</EventSpeakers>
    <EventSpeakerIDs>783807</EventSpeakerIDs>
    <EventSponsor></EventSponsor>
    <EventHandoutName>Abstract</EventHandoutName>
    <EventHandoutURL>http://meetings.siam.org/sess/dsp_talk.cfm?p=120303</EventHandoutURL>
    <EventDescription>Training and appreciation of quantitative sciences in both high school and undergraduate biology and ecology is lacking, but this type of training is crucial to collecting and using data to fully understand how such systems behave. I will discuss a project for which I have incorporated predictive modeling into high school summer curriculum on watershed management/environmental science, where undergraduates outside mathematics (from fields such as biology, environmental science, psychology, and data science) were recruited as program mentors - the idea being to develop a trained workforce through a feedback mechanism where trainees become trainers. The program, Project WHIRL (Protectors of the Watershed in the Indian River Lakes), originally run as a volunteer program established in 2019 by the Indian River Lakes Conservancy (Upstate NY). In the pilot 2021 program, high school students collected field data from local lakes and input these into a predictive model that tested weevils' efficacy (a biocontrol) at reducing a local invasive aquatic, Eurasian Watermilfoil. Students learned how to collect field data, clean and analyze data in excel, the basics of supervised machine learning (how the model was developed by my team), and how to use predictive modeling to make predictions of biocontrol success. I will discuss the overall theme of the project, its results, and its success in initiating training of a skilled workforce in both quantitative fields and watershed management.</EventDescription>
    <EventParent>73861-SESS</EventParent>
    <EventUniqueID>73861-120303</EventUniqueID>
    <STATUS>active</STATUS>
    <AutoRecord>0</AutoRecord>
    <EnabledForIAV>0</EnabledForIAV>
    <MeetingIAVMode xsi:nil="true" />
    <PublishAutoRecordedVideo xsi:nil="true" />
    <Capacity xsi:nil="true" />
    <DirectLinkEnabled>0</DirectLinkEnabled>
    <DirectLinkRecordingEnabled xsi:nil="true" />
    <start>2022-07-12T16:00:00</start>
  </meeting>
  <meeting>
    <Confcode>ED22</Confcode>
    <EventName>Opening Remarks and Presentation: Preparing and Supporting Teachers to Include Mathematical Modeling in Their Curriculum </EventName>
    <EventSubName></EventSubName>
    <Poster></Poster>
    <EventNumber>IP1</EventNumber>
    <EventDate>Jul 11, 2022</EventDate>
    <EventStartTime>2022-07-11T10:45:00</EventStartTime>
    <EventEndTime>2022-07-11T11:45:00</EventEndTime>
    <EventFilter>ED22|Invited Speaker</EventFilter>
    <EventLocation></EventLocation>
    <EventRoom>406</EventRoom>
    <FloorPlan></FloorPlan>
    <EVENT_FEE></EVENT_FEE>
    <EventKeywords></EventKeywords>
    <EventChairs></EventChairs>
    <EventModerators></EventModerators>
    <EventSpeakers>Brynja Kohler</EventSpeakers>
    <EventSpeakerIDs>729229</EventSpeakerIDs>
    <EventSponsor></EventSponsor>
    <EventHandoutName>Abstract</EventHandoutName>
    <EventHandoutURL>http://meetings.siam.org/sess/dsp_talk.cfm?p=119911</EventHandoutURL>
    <EventDescription>Students clearly deserve stimulating problem-solving opportunities in which they create and explore mathematical models to address situations relevant and meaningful to them. Yet despite calls to incorporate more modeling activities in our classes, teachers at all levels struggle to put recommendations into action.  Since undergraduate mathematics serves as a confluence in the teacher preparation stream, it must include ‘model’ mathematical modeling pedagogy. In this talk, I will share insights my collaborators and I have gained from designing and implementing data driven mathematical modeling activities in undergraduate courses. I will further detail various strategies for engaging undergraduate mathematics faculty as well as prospective and professional secondary teachers in mathematical modeling focused professional development.

	
</EventDescription>
    <EventParent>73754-SESS</EventParent>
    <EventUniqueID>73754-119911</EventUniqueID>
    <STATUS>active</STATUS>
    <AutoRecord>0</AutoRecord>
    <EnabledForIAV>0</EnabledForIAV>
    <MeetingIAVMode xsi:nil="true" />
    <PublishAutoRecordedVideo xsi:nil="true" />
    <Capacity xsi:nil="true" />
    <DirectLinkEnabled>0</DirectLinkEnabled>
    <DirectLinkRecordingEnabled xsi:nil="true" />
    <start>2022-07-11T10:45:00</start>
  </meeting>
  <meeting>
    <Confcode>ED22</Confcode>
    <EventName>RTG: Mathematics of Information and Data with Applications to Science</EventName>
    <EventSubName></EventSubName>
    <Poster></Poster>
    <EventNumber>MS2</EventNumber>
    <EventDate>Jul 11, 2022</EventDate>
    <EventStartTime>2022-07-11T08:30:00</EventStartTime>
    <EventEndTime>2022-07-11T10:30:00</EventEndTime>
    <EventFilter>ED22|Minisymposium</EventFilter>
    <EventLocation></EventLocation>
    <EventRoom>403</EventRoom>
    <FloorPlan></FloorPlan>
    <EVENT_FEE></EVENT_FEE>
    <EventKeywords>5100</EventKeywords>
    <EventChairs></EventChairs>
    <EventModerators></EventModerators>
    <EventSpeakers>Bjorn Sandstede</EventSpeakers>
    <EventSpeakerIDs>72042</EventSpeakerIDs>
    <EventSponsor></EventSponsor>
    <EventHandoutName>Abstract</EventHandoutName>
    <EventHandoutURL>http://meetings.siam.org/sess/dsp_talk.cfm?p=120908</EventHandoutURL>
    <EventDescription>I will provide an overview of the educational activities of the research training group "Mathematics of Information and Data with Applications to Science" at Brown University. The central theme of this RTG is the mathematical foundations of data science and their applications, and we approach this topic with a strong interdisciplinary flavor. The educational activities focus on vertically integrated training of undergraduate students, graduate students, and postdoctoral fellows. Concrete training activities include first-year seminars (e.g. on data science and social justice), enhanced undergraduate and graduate curricula, summer research experiences for undergraduates, graduate students, and postdoctoral fellows, and semester working groups for advanced graduate students and postdoctoral fellows. Our goals for workforce development center around the recruitment, retention, and training of a diverse cohort of applied mathematicians trained in data science.
</EventDescription>
    <EventParent>74081-SESS</EventParent>
    <EventUniqueID>74081-120908</EventUniqueID>
    <STATUS>active</STATUS>
    <AutoRecord>0</AutoRecord>
    <EnabledForIAV>0</EnabledForIAV>
    <MeetingIAVMode xsi:nil="true" />
    <PublishAutoRecordedVideo xsi:nil="true" />
    <Capacity xsi:nil="true" />
    <DirectLinkEnabled>0</DirectLinkEnabled>
    <DirectLinkRecordingEnabled xsi:nil="true" />
    <start>2022-07-11T08:30:00</start>
  </meeting>
  <meeting>
    <Confcode>ED22</Confcode>
    <EventName>Tapia Camps for K12 Students at Rice University</EventName>
    <EventSubName></EventSubName>
    <Poster></Poster>
    <EventNumber>MS5</EventNumber>
    <EventDate>Jul 11, 2022</EventDate>
    <EventStartTime>2022-07-11T16:00:00</EventStartTime>
    <EventEndTime>2022-07-11T18:00:00</EventEndTime>
    <EventFilter>ED22|Minisymposium</EventFilter>
    <EventLocation></EventLocation>
    <EventRoom>405</EventRoom>
    <FloorPlan></FloorPlan>
    <EVENT_FEE></EVENT_FEE>
    <EventKeywords>2800</EventKeywords>
    <EventChairs></EventChairs>
    <EventModerators></EventModerators>
    <EventSpeakers>Paul Hand</EventSpeakers>
    <EventSpeakerIDs>769784</EventSpeakerIDs>
    <EventSponsor></EventSponsor>
    <EventHandoutName>Abstract</EventHandoutName>
    <EventHandoutURL>http://meetings.siam.org/sess/dsp_talk.cfm?p=122100</EventHandoutURL>
    <EventDescription>The Tapia Center for Excellence and Equity at Rice University has been delivering STEM summer camps to middle and high school students.  Since 2017, over a thousand students have participated, of which 47% were women and 70% were from underrepresented racial groups in STEM.  The programs focus on STEM, communication, and equity, and they build a community of young scientists from all over Texas, the country, and the world.  The students interact with university students and faculty, including Dr. Richard Tapia, winner of the National Medal of Science.  In this presentation, the camp director Dr. Paul Hand will share stories from the programs.
</EventDescription>
    <EventParent>74435-SESS</EventParent>
    <EventUniqueID>74435-122100</EventUniqueID>
    <STATUS>active</STATUS>
    <AutoRecord>0</AutoRecord>
    <EnabledForIAV>0</EnabledForIAV>
    <MeetingIAVMode xsi:nil="true" />
    <PublishAutoRecordedVideo xsi:nil="true" />
    <Capacity xsi:nil="true" />
    <DirectLinkEnabled>0</DirectLinkEnabled>
    <DirectLinkRecordingEnabled xsi:nil="true" />
    <start>2022-07-11T16:00:00</start>
  </meeting>
  <meeting>
    <Confcode>ED22</Confcode>
    <EventName>Building Resilient Math Communities in the Classroom and Research Lab</EventName>
    <EventSubName></EventSubName>
    <Poster></Poster>
    <EventNumber>MS5</EventNumber>
    <EventDate>Jul 11, 2022</EventDate>
    <EventStartTime>2022-07-11T16:00:00</EventStartTime>
    <EventEndTime>2022-07-11T18:00:00</EventEndTime>
    <EventFilter>ED22|Minisymposium</EventFilter>
    <EventLocation></EventLocation>
    <EventRoom>405</EventRoom>
    <FloorPlan></FloorPlan>
    <EVENT_FEE></EVENT_FEE>
    <EventKeywords>2800</EventKeywords>
    <EventChairs></EventChairs>
    <EventModerators></EventModerators>
    <EventSpeakers>Josef Sifuentes</EventSpeakers>
    <EventSpeakerIDs>744264</EventSpeakerIDs>
    <EventSponsor></EventSponsor>
    <EventHandoutName>Abstract</EventHandoutName>
    <EventHandoutURL>http://meetings.siam.org/sess/dsp_talk.cfm?p=122667</EventHandoutURL>
    <EventDescription>
At the University of Texas Rio Grande Valley (UTRGV), we have worked to build communities of faculty and students both in the classroom and the research lab. These communities have created a critical mass of support for students on the path to graduate school. A component of these efforts is flipping upper-level courses so that lecture is structured around group work and communication. This helps to build a more resilient community of undergraduate students. Through an NSF and Sloan Foundation grant, some of the courses have been co-taught by faculty from UTRGV and UT Dallas, who have then collaborated on summer programs for undergraduate students intended to create a pathway to graduate programs. In this way, faculty with a shared commitment to widening this path toward research also form a collaborative community. Additionally, through summer research opportunities for undergraduates, we extend the concept of a community of students to the research lab. By creating a pathway for talented students from the Texas-Mexico border to research participation, we can contribute to the diversity of tomorrows set of leaders and mathematicians. During this talk I will share the lessons I have learned from being a part and helping to build these diverse research communities. 

</EventDescription>
    <EventParent>74435-SESS</EventParent>
    <EventUniqueID>74435-122667</EventUniqueID>
    <STATUS>active</STATUS>
    <AutoRecord>0</AutoRecord>
    <EnabledForIAV>0</EnabledForIAV>
    <MeetingIAVMode xsi:nil="true" />
    <PublishAutoRecordedVideo xsi:nil="true" />
    <Capacity xsi:nil="true" />
    <DirectLinkEnabled>0</DirectLinkEnabled>
    <DirectLinkRecordingEnabled xsi:nil="true" />
    <start>2022-07-11T16:00:00</start>
  </meeting>
  <meeting>
    <Confcode>ED22</Confcode>
    <EventName>Promoting Effective Practices in JEDI for Applied Mathematics Education</EventName>
    <EventSubName></EventSubName>
    <Poster></Poster>
    <EventNumber>MS10</EventNumber>
    <EventDate>Jul 12, 2022</EventDate>
    <EventStartTime>2022-07-12T08:30:00</EventStartTime>
    <EventEndTime>2022-07-12T10:30:00</EventEndTime>
    <EventFilter>ED22|Minisymposium</EventFilter>
    <EventLocation></EventLocation>
    <EventRoom>406</EventRoom>
    <FloorPlan></FloorPlan>
    <EVENT_FEE></EVENT_FEE>
    <EventKeywords>2800</EventKeywords>
    <EventChairs></EventChairs>
    <EventModerators></EventModerators>
    <EventSpeakers>Gerardo Hernandez-Duenas</EventSpeakers>
    <EventSpeakerIDs>764425</EventSpeakerIDs>
    <EventSponsor></EventSponsor>
    <EventHandoutName>Abstract</EventHandoutName>
    <EventHandoutURL>http://meetings.siam.org/sess/dsp_talk.cfm?p=120884</EventHandoutURL>
    <EventDescription>In this talk, we will share some experiences and lessons learnt from sharing best practices in JEDI for Applied Mathematics. The ideas helped identifying persistent racial injustices and inequalities in the community that have led to renewed concern and interest in addressing the need to promote JEDI in teaching, learning and research in Applied Mathematics. Thoughts and ideas evolved from collaborations with the SIAM Diversity Advisory Committee that helped to develop authentic partnership with members in the United States who were also concerned about the most impacted by the inequities caused by systemic racism.  We hope to share some of the lessons learnt around systemic barriers to opportunities and benefits for students and faculty, and how these barriers impact access to, retention in, and success in Applied Mathematics Education, research, and workforce development both in Mexico and the United States.
</EventDescription>
    <EventParent>74170-SESS</EventParent>
    <EventUniqueID>74170-120884</EventUniqueID>
    <STATUS>active</STATUS>
    <AutoRecord>0</AutoRecord>
    <EnabledForIAV>0</EnabledForIAV>
    <MeetingIAVMode xsi:nil="true" />
    <PublishAutoRecordedVideo xsi:nil="true" />
    <Capacity xsi:nil="true" />
    <DirectLinkEnabled>0</DirectLinkEnabled>
    <DirectLinkRecordingEnabled xsi:nil="true" />
    <start>2022-07-12T08:30:00</start>
  </meeting>
  <meeting>
    <Confcode>ED22</Confcode>
    <EventName>Math-Bio Undergraduate Research in Ecology</EventName>
    <EventSubName></EventSubName>
    <Poster></Poster>
    <EventNumber>MS12</EventNumber>
    <EventDate>Jul 12, 2022</EventDate>
    <EventStartTime>2022-07-12T08:30:00</EventStartTime>
    <EventEndTime>2022-07-12T10:30:00</EventEndTime>
    <EventFilter>ED22|Minisymposium</EventFilter>
    <EventLocation></EventLocation>
    <EventRoom>404</EventRoom>
    <FloorPlan></FloorPlan>
    <EVENT_FEE></EVENT_FEE>
    <EventKeywords>2800</EventKeywords>
    <EventChairs></EventChairs>
    <EventModerators></EventModerators>
    <EventSpeakers>Kwadwo Antwi-Fordjour</EventSpeakers>
    <EventSpeakerIDs>805515</EventSpeakerIDs>
    <EventSponsor></EventSponsor>
    <EventHandoutName>Abstract</EventHandoutName>
    <EventHandoutURL>http://meetings.siam.org/sess/dsp_talk.cfm?p=120298</EventHandoutURL>
    <EventDescription>Interdisciplinary research provides solutions to problems in multiple disciplines and can sometimes be challenging. In this talk, we will discuss two recent math-bio projects undertaken with Samford undergraduate students. The mathematics and biology students involved in these projects were able to apply the theories they learned in their classes. Also, the students developed multifaceted competency in collaborative science.</EventDescription>
    <EventParent>73860-SESS</EventParent>
    <EventUniqueID>73860-120298</EventUniqueID>
    <STATUS>active</STATUS>
    <AutoRecord>0</AutoRecord>
    <EnabledForIAV>0</EnabledForIAV>
    <MeetingIAVMode xsi:nil="true" />
    <PublishAutoRecordedVideo xsi:nil="true" />
    <Capacity xsi:nil="true" />
    <DirectLinkEnabled>0</DirectLinkEnabled>
    <DirectLinkRecordingEnabled xsi:nil="true" />
    <start>2022-07-12T08:30:00</start>
  </meeting>
  <meeting>
    <Confcode>ED22</Confcode>
    <EventName>(Mis)Adventures in Experiential Learning: 10+ Years of Hands-On Learning in College Algebra</EventName>
    <EventSubName></EventSubName>
    <Poster></Poster>
    <EventNumber>MS13</EventNumber>
    <EventDate>Jul 12, 2022</EventDate>
    <EventStartTime>2022-07-12T08:30:00</EventStartTime>
    <EventEndTime>2022-07-12T10:30:00</EventEndTime>
    <EventFilter>ED22|Minisymposium</EventFilter>
    <EventLocation></EventLocation>
    <EventRoom>403</EventRoom>
    <FloorPlan></FloorPlan>
    <EVENT_FEE></EVENT_FEE>
    <EventKeywords>3000</EventKeywords>
    <EventChairs></EventChairs>
    <EventModerators></EventModerators>
    <EventSpeakers>Matthew Lewis</EventSpeakers>
    <EventSpeakerIDs>792019</EventSpeakerIDs>
    <EventSponsor></EventSponsor>
    <EventHandoutName>Abstract</EventHandoutName>
    <EventHandoutURL>http://meetings.siam.org/sess/dsp_talk.cfm?p=120984</EventHandoutURL>
    <EventDescription>10+ years ago, college algebra classes at BYU-I were transformed from a traditional, lecture-based course to an experiential learning approach that relies heavily on basic mathematical modeling of real-world phenomena. I share the original vision of the course, recent changes, student reactions and our vision for the future of the class.</EventDescription>
    <EventParent>74199-SESS</EventParent>
    <EventUniqueID>74199-120984</EventUniqueID>
    <STATUS>active</STATUS>
    <AutoRecord>0</AutoRecord>
    <EnabledForIAV>0</EnabledForIAV>
    <MeetingIAVMode xsi:nil="true" />
    <PublishAutoRecordedVideo xsi:nil="true" />
    <Capacity xsi:nil="true" />
    <DirectLinkEnabled>0</DirectLinkEnabled>
    <DirectLinkRecordingEnabled xsi:nil="true" />
    <start>2022-07-12T08:30:00</start>
  </meeting>
  <meeting>
    <Confcode>ED22</Confcode>
    <EventName>Modeling with Data: the Good, the Sparse and the Imperfect</EventName>
    <EventSubName></EventSubName>
    <Poster></Poster>
    <EventNumber>MS13</EventNumber>
    <EventDate>Jul 12, 2022</EventDate>
    <EventStartTime>2022-07-12T08:30:00</EventStartTime>
    <EventEndTime>2022-07-12T10:30:00</EventEndTime>
    <EventFilter>ED22|Minisymposium</EventFilter>
    <EventLocation></EventLocation>
    <EventRoom>403</EventRoom>
    <FloorPlan></FloorPlan>
    <EVENT_FEE></EVENT_FEE>
    <EventKeywords>3000</EventKeywords>
    <EventChairs></EventChairs>
    <EventModerators></EventModerators>
    <EventSpeakers>Emek Kose</EventSpeakers>
    <EventSpeakerIDs>805922</EventSpeakerIDs>
    <EventSponsor></EventSponsor>
    <EventHandoutName>Abstract</EventHandoutName>
    <EventHandoutURL>http://meetings.siam.org/sess/dsp_talk.cfm?p=121169</EventHandoutURL>
    <EventDescription>
Biological data is tremendously valuable, often difficult to obtain, sparsely sampled and imperfect. In this talk we will examine the great opportunities and challenges of working with real data in mathematical modeling. 


</EventDescription>
    <EventParent>74199-SESS</EventParent>
    <EventUniqueID>74199-121169</EventUniqueID>
    <STATUS>active</STATUS>
    <AutoRecord>0</AutoRecord>
    <EnabledForIAV>0</EnabledForIAV>
    <MeetingIAVMode xsi:nil="true" />
    <PublishAutoRecordedVideo xsi:nil="true" />
    <Capacity xsi:nil="true" />
    <DirectLinkEnabled>0</DirectLinkEnabled>
    <DirectLinkRecordingEnabled xsi:nil="true" />
    <start>2022-07-12T08:30:00</start>
  </meeting>
  <meeting>
    <Confcode>ED22</Confcode>
    <EventName>A Modern Undergraduate Experience in Modeling Differential Equations: SCUDEM</EventName>
    <EventSubName></EventSubName>
    <Poster></Poster>
    <EventNumber>MS14</EventNumber>
    <EventDate>Jul 12, 2022</EventDate>
    <EventStartTime>2022-07-12T08:30:00</EventStartTime>
    <EventEndTime>2022-07-12T10:30:00</EventEndTime>
    <EventFilter>ED22|Minisymposium</EventFilter>
    <EventLocation></EventLocation>
    <EventRoom>402</EventRoom>
    <FloorPlan></FloorPlan>
    <EVENT_FEE></EVENT_FEE>
    <EventKeywords>2800</EventKeywords>
    <EventChairs></EventChairs>
    <EventModerators></EventModerators>
    <EventSpeakers>Anthony Stefan</EventSpeakers>
    <EventSpeakerIDs>806085</EventSpeakerIDs>
    <EventSponsor></EventSponsor>
    <EventHandoutName>Abstract</EventHandoutName>
    <EventHandoutURL>http://meetings.siam.org/sess/dsp_talk.cfm?p=121312</EventHandoutURL>
    <EventDescription>SCUDEM (SIMIODE Challenge Using Differential Equations Modeling)  offers coaches, students, and judges a modern approach to teaching, learning, and mentoring, respectively, modeling differential equations. I have experienced each of these perspectives and wish to share my SCUDEM journey with you. We find that the SCUDEM challenge is both a rich undergraduate mathematical challenge outside the classroom for all students and potentially replicates how researching applied mathematics with colleagues and advisors is in graduate school as an undergraduate level experience. This presentation will introduce the SCUDEM challenge, describe a coach's experience and resources, show examples of a few student responses, and discuss the benefits of engaging in SCUDEM.
</EventDescription>
    <EventParent>74292-SESS</EventParent>
    <EventUniqueID>74292-121312</EventUniqueID>
    <STATUS>active</STATUS>
    <AutoRecord>0</AutoRecord>
    <EnabledForIAV>0</EnabledForIAV>
    <MeetingIAVMode xsi:nil="true" />
    <PublishAutoRecordedVideo xsi:nil="true" />
    <Capacity xsi:nil="true" />
    <DirectLinkEnabled>0</DirectLinkEnabled>
    <DirectLinkRecordingEnabled xsi:nil="true" />
    <start>2022-07-12T08:30:00</start>
  </meeting>
  <meeting>
    <Confcode>ED22</Confcode>
    <EventName>Advancing Racial Equity Through Inclusion</EventName>
    <EventSubName></EventSubName>
    <Poster></Poster>
    <EventNumber>MS15</EventNumber>
    <EventDate>Jul 12, 2022</EventDate>
    <EventStartTime>2022-07-12T16:00:00</EventStartTime>
    <EventEndTime>2022-07-12T18:00:00</EventEndTime>
    <EventFilter>ED22|Minisymposium</EventFilter>
    <EventLocation></EventLocation>
    <EventRoom>405</EventRoom>
    <FloorPlan></FloorPlan>
    <EVENT_FEE></EVENT_FEE>
    <EventKeywords>2800</EventKeywords>
    <EventChairs></EventChairs>
    <EventModerators></EventModerators>
    <EventSpeakers>Matthew Hawks</EventSpeakers>
    <EventSpeakerIDs>805711</EventSpeakerIDs>
    <EventSponsor></EventSponsor>
    <EventHandoutName>Abstract</EventHandoutName>
    <EventHandoutURL>http://meetings.siam.org/sess/dsp_talk.cfm?p=120887</EventHandoutURL>
    <EventDescription>How can instructors encourage underrepresented students to pursue further studies in statistics? Three major pioneers in our field promoted eugenics! Even generations later, the statistics discipline can appear hostile to those who are not white and male. This talk provides three tangible ways for instructors to overcome this apparent barrier. First, formulate a course policy that - up front - explicitly recognizes past exclusions. Such a statement addresses concerns that a student may not ``belong" in the field. Second, institute a practice that nurtures respect for every individual. Asking a daily question allows students to open up to their peers and provides opportunities for student validation. Third, incorporate a biographical assignment that exposes students to contributions from underrepresented individuals. Such an assignment helps students to recognize that inherent, immutable characteristics are not predictors of a successful future in statistics. Attendees will receive daily, tangible methods to enfold inclusion into their classroom and foster an environment that explicitly encourages underrepresented students. The session seeks to empower instructors - to assist them in their vital mission to ensure underrepresented students do not self-exclude from a future in the field of statistics.</EventDescription>
    <EventParent>74171-SESS</EventParent>
    <EventUniqueID>74171-120887</EventUniqueID>
    <STATUS>active</STATUS>
    <AutoRecord>0</AutoRecord>
    <EnabledForIAV>0</EnabledForIAV>
    <MeetingIAVMode xsi:nil="true" />
    <PublishAutoRecordedVideo xsi:nil="true" />
    <Capacity xsi:nil="true" />
    <DirectLinkEnabled>0</DirectLinkEnabled>
    <DirectLinkRecordingEnabled xsi:nil="true" />
    <start>2022-07-12T16:00:00</start>
  </meeting>
  <meeting>
    <Confcode>ED22</Confcode>
    <EventName>Panel: How Can We Advance Racial Equity in the Applied Mathematics Commuinity?</EventName>
    <EventSubName></EventSubName>
    <Poster></Poster>
    <EventNumber>MS15</EventNumber>
    <EventDate>Jul 12, 2022</EventDate>
    <EventStartTime>2022-07-12T16:00:00</EventStartTime>
    <EventEndTime>2022-07-12T18:00:00</EventEndTime>
    <EventFilter>ED22|Minisymposium</EventFilter>
    <EventLocation></EventLocation>
    <EventRoom>405</EventRoom>
    <FloorPlan></FloorPlan>
    <EVENT_FEE></EVENT_FEE>
    <EventKeywords>2800</EventKeywords>
    <EventChairs></EventChairs>
    <EventModerators></EventModerators>
    <EventSpeakers>TBA TBA</EventSpeakers>
    <EventSpeakerIDs>727601</EventSpeakerIDs>
    <EventSponsor></EventSponsor>
    <EventHandoutName>Abstract</EventHandoutName>
    <EventHandoutURL>http://meetings.siam.org/sess/dsp_talk.cfm?p=120891</EventHandoutURL>
    <EventDescription>The final event in the minisymposium on advancing racial equity in the applied mathematics community will be an opportunity for the organizers and speakers in the two sessions to dialogue with each other and the broader community about concrete steps that can be taken to advance racial equity in the mathematical sciences. This panel will be online and accessible to all registered attendees of AN22 and ED22.</EventDescription>
    <EventParent>74171-SESS</EventParent>
    <EventUniqueID>74171-120891</EventUniqueID>
    <STATUS>active</STATUS>
    <AutoRecord>0</AutoRecord>
    <EnabledForIAV>0</EnabledForIAV>
    <MeetingIAVMode xsi:nil="true" />
    <PublishAutoRecordedVideo xsi:nil="true" />
    <Capacity xsi:nil="true" />
    <DirectLinkEnabled>0</DirectLinkEnabled>
    <DirectLinkRecordingEnabled xsi:nil="true" />
    <start>2022-07-12T16:00:00</start>
  </meeting>
  <meeting>
    <Confcode>ED22</Confcode>
    <EventName>Building Mathematical and Scientific Communication Skills in Statistics Using Projects</EventName>
    <EventSubName></EventSubName>
    <Poster></Poster>
    <EventNumber>MS17</EventNumber>
    <EventDate>Jul 12, 2022</EventDate>
    <EventStartTime>2022-07-12T16:00:00</EventStartTime>
    <EventEndTime>2022-07-12T18:00:00</EventEndTime>
    <EventFilter>ED22|Minisymposium</EventFilter>
    <EventLocation></EventLocation>
    <EventRoom>403</EventRoom>
    <FloorPlan></FloorPlan>
    <EVENT_FEE></EVENT_FEE>
    <EventKeywords>2800</EventKeywords>
    <EventChairs></EventChairs>
    <EventModerators></EventModerators>
    <EventSpeakers>Jacob Price</EventSpeakers>
    <EventSpeakerIDs>779205</EventSpeakerIDs>
    <EventSponsor></EventSponsor>
    <EventHandoutName>Abstract</EventHandoutName>
    <EventHandoutURL>http://meetings.siam.org/sess/dsp_talk.cfm?p=121000</EventHandoutURL>
    <EventDescription>Careful written and verbal communication is of critical importance in the field of statistics. Unlike mathematical proof-writing, the audience for writing about statistics may frequently have little experience with the formal mathematics underlying the results. Thus, being able to carefully and accurately explain statistical conclusions to a non-expert audience is a necessary skill for students to develop. This is not a skill that they are frequently asked to practice. Long-term projects give students a chance to dedicate time to this valuable skill. In this talk, I present several projects that aim to develop these skills at the introductory, intermediate, and advanced levels. At the introductory level, long-term projects give students time to write extensively about mathematics, which might be a new experience for them. At the intermediate level, students practice writing and presenting in the forms expected for scientific communication. At the advanced level, students continue to refine their scientific writing and presenting, but also are pushed to practice explaining statistical ideas to other audiences, for example with ``popular science' articles. I will share resources and rubrics related to these projects, as well as my reflections on them.</EventDescription>
    <EventParent>74201-SESS</EventParent>
    <EventUniqueID>74201-121000</EventUniqueID>
    <STATUS>active</STATUS>
    <AutoRecord>0</AutoRecord>
    <EnabledForIAV>0</EnabledForIAV>
    <MeetingIAVMode xsi:nil="true" />
    <PublishAutoRecordedVideo xsi:nil="true" />
    <Capacity xsi:nil="true" />
    <DirectLinkEnabled>0</DirectLinkEnabled>
    <DirectLinkRecordingEnabled xsi:nil="true" />
    <start>2022-07-12T16:00:00</start>
  </meeting>
  <meeting>
    <Confcode>ED22</Confcode>
    <EventName>Investigating Explanation in Proof-Based Mathematics</EventName>
    <EventSubName></EventSubName>
    <Poster></Poster>
    <EventNumber>MS18</EventNumber>
    <EventDate>Jul 12, 2022</EventDate>
    <EventStartTime>2022-07-12T16:00:00</EventStartTime>
    <EventEndTime>2022-07-12T18:00:00</EventEndTime>
    <EventFilter>ED22|Minisymposium</EventFilter>
    <EventLocation></EventLocation>
    <EventRoom>402</EventRoom>
    <FloorPlan></FloorPlan>
    <EVENT_FEE></EVENT_FEE>
    <EventKeywords>2800</EventKeywords>
    <EventChairs></EventChairs>
    <EventModerators></EventModerators>
    <EventSpeakers>Juan Pablo Mejia Ramos</EventSpeakers>
    <EventSpeakerIDs>805431</EventSpeakerIDs>
    <EventSponsor></EventSponsor>
    <EventHandoutName>Abstract</EventHandoutName>
    <EventHandoutURL>http://meetings.siam.org/sess/dsp_talk.cfm?p=120097</EventHandoutURL>
    <EventDescription>Proof has several roles in mathematical practice and in the mathematics classroom. One of those roles is to explain why a given proposition holds (as opposed to, for example, demonstrating that it does). Indeed, explanation is a particularly important role of proof in the mathematics classroom, but not one that it always fulfills. Philosophers of mathematics and mathematics educators have struggled for decades to identify what makes a proof explanatory, or what makes a proof of a given proposition more explanatory than another one. While there have been promising, recent developments in this area, explicit criteria for what makes a proof (more or less) explanatory are still being debated. In this presentation, I illustrate a novel empirical approach to investigating the notion of explanation in proof-based mathematics. In particular, I report on a couple of studies aimed at investigating the extent to which mathematicians and undergraduate students share a notion of explanatoriness in proof-based mathematics (both among and between themselves). Results from these studies suggest this is a fruitful approach for studying what makes a proof (more or less) explanatory in mathematics.
</EventDescription>
    <EventParent>73891-SESS</EventParent>
    <EventUniqueID>73891-120097</EventUniqueID>
    <STATUS>active</STATUS>
    <AutoRecord>0</AutoRecord>
    <EnabledForIAV>0</EnabledForIAV>
    <MeetingIAVMode xsi:nil="true" />
    <PublishAutoRecordedVideo xsi:nil="true" />
    <Capacity xsi:nil="true" />
    <DirectLinkEnabled>0</DirectLinkEnabled>
    <DirectLinkRecordingEnabled xsi:nil="true" />
    <start>2022-07-12T16:00:00</start>
  </meeting>
  <meeting>
    <Confcode>ED22</Confcode>
    <EventName>Introduction to Comap’s Certificate in Modeling (CiM) Program for Educators – Part I of II</EventName>
    <EventSubName></EventSubName>
    <Poster></Poster>
    <EventNumber>MT1</EventNumber>
    <EventDate>Jul 11, 2022</EventDate>
    <EventStartTime>2022-07-11T08:30:00</EventStartTime>
    <EventEndTime>2022-07-11T10:30:00</EventEndTime>
    <EventFilter>ED22|Minitutorial</EventFilter>
    <EventLocation></EventLocation>
    <EventRoom>405</EventRoom>
    <FloorPlan></FloorPlan>
    <EVENT_FEE></EVENT_FEE>
    <EventKeywords></EventKeywords>
    <EventChairs></EventChairs>
    <EventModerators></EventModerators>
    <EventSpeakers>Michelle Isenhour</EventSpeakers>
    <EventSpeakerIDs>807334</EventSpeakerIDs>
    <EventSponsor></EventSponsor>
    <EventHandoutName>Abstract</EventHandoutName>
    <EventHandoutURL>http://meetings.siam.org/sess/dsp_talk.cfm?p=122691</EventHandoutURL>
    <EventDescription>During this workshop, we will introduce participants to the CiM program as well as the opportunity to obtain the Modeling Educator Certificate (MEC). Workshop participants will participate in two hour-long sessions where COMAP will expose participants to the material contained within the first two modules of the Modeling for Education course. During module 1, participants will trace a bit of history of educational practices from traditional/computational (#1-15 odd), to “word” problems, to applied problem solving, to “modeling problem.” After completing module 1, every participant will have a better understanding of the philosophy of teaching/learning and framework for applied problem solving and modeling. During module 2, participants will explore a Showcase of (Modeling) Examples to learn how to expose students to various fields, levels of solutions, and types of mathematics involved. In addition to being exposed to the course in-class activities, workshop participants will also experience some of the pre- and post-class activities planned as part of the program. Following the completion of module 2, the workshop will conclude with a discussion about the workshop experience and opportunity to obtain the modeling certificate.

	</EventDescription>
    <EventParent>74631-SESS</EventParent>
    <EventUniqueID>74631-122691</EventUniqueID>
    <STATUS>active</STATUS>
    <AutoRecord>0</AutoRecord>
    <EnabledForIAV>0</EnabledForIAV>
    <MeetingIAVMode xsi:nil="true" />
    <PublishAutoRecordedVideo xsi:nil="true" />
    <Capacity xsi:nil="true" />
    <DirectLinkEnabled>0</DirectLinkEnabled>
    <DirectLinkRecordingEnabled xsi:nil="true" />
    <start>2022-07-11T08:30:00</start>
  </meeting>
  <meeting>
    <Confcode>ED22</Confcode>
    <EventName>Confidence-Based Marking (CBM) in Online Mathematics Instruction: How to Involve Students in Assessment-for-Learning?</EventName>
    <EventSubName></EventSubName>
    <Poster></Poster>
    <EventNumber>CP1</EventNumber>
    <EventDate>Jul 11, 2022</EventDate>
    <EventStartTime>2022-07-11T08:50:00</EventStartTime>
    <EventEndTime>2022-07-11T09:05:00</EventEndTime>
    <EventFilter>ED22|Contributed</EventFilter>
    <EventLocation></EventLocation>
    <EventRoom>404</EventRoom>
    <FloorPlan></FloorPlan>
    <EVENT_FEE></EVENT_FEE>
    <EventKeywords></EventKeywords>
    <EventChairs></EventChairs>
    <EventModerators></EventModerators>
    <EventSpeakers>Sima Caspari-Sadeghi</EventSpeakers>
    <EventSpeakerIDs>805296</EventSpeakerIDs>
    <EventSponsor></EventSponsor>
    <EventHandoutName>Abstract</EventHandoutName>
    <EventHandoutURL>http://meetings.siam.org/sess/dsp_talk.cfm?p=119909</EventHandoutURL>
    <EventDescription>This paper addresses the need for developing Self-regulated Learning (SRL) as the ‘holy grail’ in online instruction. A collaborative action research, aiming at embedding self-and-peer assessment into mathematics learning, was carried out over 14-weeks in a master program in mathematics and computer sciences at university of Passau, Germany. Students were engaged in Student-generated Questions (SGQ) and Confidence-based Marking (CBM): they were asked to conduct inquiry-based learning, develop relevant questions, ask their peers to answer the questions and rate their confidence in their answers throughout the online course. Data were triangulated from three sources: (a) assessment artifacts, i.e. SGQ and CBM, as evidence of learning,and (b) students’ attitude captured through ‘Task Perception Questionnaire’. Assessment data were analysed by three experts based on their judgement of ‘quality’. Kappa measure was used to assess consistency among raters. Quantitative analysis of questionnaire data indicated positive attitudes towards CBM (engaging, fair, easy, or useful) among students. Analysis of field-notes and observation made by instructors provided complementary evidence about real-time reactions and experiences (confusion, frustration, bewilderment) of students as they were performing CBM tasks. We examine the limitations as well as implications of this project and conclude with a discussion of future action plans to improve such classroom research.   
</EventDescription>
    <EventParent>74686-SESS</EventParent>
    <EventUniqueID>74686-119909</EventUniqueID>
    <STATUS>active</STATUS>
    <AutoRecord>0</AutoRecord>
    <EnabledForIAV>0</EnabledForIAV>
    <MeetingIAVMode xsi:nil="true" />
    <PublishAutoRecordedVideo xsi:nil="true" />
    <Capacity xsi:nil="true" />
    <DirectLinkEnabled>0</DirectLinkEnabled>
    <DirectLinkRecordingEnabled xsi:nil="true" />
    <start>2022-07-11T08:30:00</start>
  </meeting>
  <meeting>
    <Confcode>ED22</Confcode>
    <EventName>The Mathematical Problems in Industry Workshop: Past, Present, and Future</EventName>
    <EventSubName></EventSubName>
    <Poster></Poster>
    <EventNumber>MS1</EventNumber>
    <EventDate>Jul 11, 2022</EventDate>
    <EventStartTime>2022-07-11T08:30:00</EventStartTime>
    <EventEndTime>2022-07-11T10:30:00</EventEndTime>
    <EventFilter>ED22|Minisymposium</EventFilter>
    <EventLocation></EventLocation>
    <EventRoom>406</EventRoom>
    <FloorPlan></FloorPlan>
    <EVENT_FEE></EVENT_FEE>
    <EventKeywords>2800</EventKeywords>
    <EventChairs></EventChairs>
    <EventModerators></EventModerators>
    <EventSpeakers>Richard Moore</EventSpeakers>
    <EventSpeakerIDs>716671</EventSpeakerIDs>
    <EventSponsor></EventSponsor>
    <EventHandoutName>Abstract</EventHandoutName>
    <EventHandoutURL>http://meetings.siam.org/sess/dsp_talk.cfm?p=121105</EventHandoutURL>
    <EventDescription xsi:nil="true" />
    <EventParent>74229-SESS</EventParent>
    <EventUniqueID>74229-121105</EventUniqueID>
    <STATUS>active</STATUS>
    <AutoRecord>0</AutoRecord>
    <EnabledForIAV>0</EnabledForIAV>
    <MeetingIAVMode xsi:nil="true" />
    <PublishAutoRecordedVideo xsi:nil="true" />
    <Capacity xsi:nil="true" />
    <DirectLinkEnabled>0</DirectLinkEnabled>
    <DirectLinkRecordingEnabled xsi:nil="true" />
    <start>2022-07-11T08:30:00</start>
  </meeting>
  <meeting>
    <Confcode>ED22</Confcode>
    <EventName>Addressing the Need for Stem Teachers in Rural and Urban High-Need Schools</EventName>
    <EventSubName></EventSubName>
    <Poster></Poster>
    <EventNumber>MS3</EventNumber>
    <EventDate>Jul 11, 2022</EventDate>
    <EventStartTime>2022-07-11T09:00:00</EventStartTime>
    <EventEndTime>2022-07-11T09:25:00</EventEndTime>
    <EventFilter>ED22|Minisymposium</EventFilter>
    <EventLocation></EventLocation>
    <EventRoom>402</EventRoom>
    <FloorPlan></FloorPlan>
    <EVENT_FEE></EVENT_FEE>
    <EventKeywords>2800</EventKeywords>
    <EventChairs></EventChairs>
    <EventModerators></EventModerators>
    <EventSpeakers>Jan DeWaters</EventSpeakers>
    <EventSpeakerIDs>805517</EventSpeakerIDs>
    <EventSponsor></EventSponsor>
    <EventHandoutName>Abstract</EventHandoutName>
    <EventHandoutURL>http://meetings.siam.org/sess/dsp_talk.cfm?p=120310</EventHandoutURL>
    <EventDescription>Economically disadvantaged communities face unique challenges to engage and retain talented K-12 teachers, especially those with aptitude in STEM. STEM teacher shortages that exist in K-12 schools across the country are even more prevalent in high-need school districts. A range of factors contribute to the barriers that limit the applicant pool: lower teaching salaries, fewer resources, lack of access to materials and programming, and – often – the need to teach multiple subjects because there are fewer faculty. Early field experiences that engage undergraduate STEM students in mentoring and teaching K-12 students, through educational outreach programs, competitions and design challenges, after-school tutoring, and peer mentoring programs, provide enhanced K-12 STEM learning opportunities in high-needs school districts while simultaneously planting seeds for undergraduate students to consider careers in STEM education. Among our MAT applicants we have observed a high preponderance of students who participated in some type of early field experience, and students whose experiences were in high-needs schools are particularly drawn to working in similar situations. A combination of early field experiences in high-needs schools, together with additional coursework that helps develop cultural competence and equity literacy, helps to ensure a successful transition as our students move into their early careers.</EventDescription>
    <EventParent>73964-SESS</EventParent>
    <EventUniqueID>73964-120310</EventUniqueID>
    <STATUS>active</STATUS>
    <AutoRecord>0</AutoRecord>
    <EnabledForIAV>0</EnabledForIAV>
    <MeetingIAVMode xsi:nil="true" />
    <PublishAutoRecordedVideo xsi:nil="true" />
    <Capacity xsi:nil="true" />
    <DirectLinkEnabled>0</DirectLinkEnabled>
    <DirectLinkRecordingEnabled xsi:nil="true" />
    <start>2022-07-11T08:30:00</start>
  </meeting>
  <meeting>
    <Confcode>ED22</Confcode>
    <EventName>Mathematical Modeling Education: Developments in the Netherlands</EventName>
    <EventSubName></EventSubName>
    <Poster></Poster>
    <EventNumber>MS4</EventNumber>
    <EventDate>Jul 11, 2022</EventDate>
    <EventStartTime>2022-07-11T08:30:00</EventStartTime>
    <EventEndTime>2022-07-11T10:30:00</EventEndTime>
    <EventFilter>ED22|Minisymposium</EventFilter>
    <EventLocation></EventLocation>
    <EventRoom>401</EventRoom>
    <FloorPlan></FloorPlan>
    <EVENT_FEE></EVENT_FEE>
    <EventKeywords>2800</EventKeywords>
    <EventChairs></EventChairs>
    <EventModerators></EventModerators>
    <EventSpeakers>Henk van der Kooij</EventSpeakers>
    <EventSpeakerIDs>805592</EventSpeakerIDs>
    <EventSponsor></EventSponsor>
    <EventHandoutName>Abstract</EventHandoutName>
    <EventHandoutURL>http://meetings.siam.org/sess/dsp_talk.cfm?p=120540</EventHandoutURL>
    <EventDescription>In 1985, two new programs were introduced in Senior High School, replacing the existing mathematics program: Mathematics A, preparing for social sciences and Mathematics B for natural sciences. New in both programs was explicit attention for applications and aspects of modeling. Because modeling is hard to assess in time-limited national exams, the Freudenthal Institute developed the Mathematics A-lympiad and Mathematics B-day, a one-day modeling experience for teams of four students. About one-third of all schools use these tasks every year for all students in grade 11, as mandatory part of their school exam. All teacher-training institutes prepare students for these aspects of their future job. All commercial textbooks have to pay attention to applications and modeling, because the national curriculum prescribes so.
Seen from this perspective, there is no need for institutional change in the Netherlands, although sometimes back-to-basics movements try to influence policymakers.
IMMC is promoted in the Netherlands, because we believe that students and teachers deserve the possibility of working on a realistic problem to experience how mathematics can be used to attack and solve real life problems. We promote IMMC by doing workshops at teacher conferences, publish articles in the national mathematics teachers journal and through personal networks.

</EventDescription>
    <EventParent>74050-SESS</EventParent>
    <EventUniqueID>74050-120540</EventUniqueID>
    <STATUS>active</STATUS>
    <AutoRecord>0</AutoRecord>
    <EnabledForIAV>0</EnabledForIAV>
    <MeetingIAVMode xsi:nil="true" />
    <PublishAutoRecordedVideo xsi:nil="true" />
    <Capacity xsi:nil="true" />
    <DirectLinkEnabled>0</DirectLinkEnabled>
    <DirectLinkRecordingEnabled xsi:nil="true" />
    <start>2022-07-11T08:30:00</start>
  </meeting>
  <meeting>
    <Confcode>ED22</Confcode>
    <EventName>Undergraduate Engagement in Some Biological Control Problems</EventName>
    <EventSubName></EventSubName>
    <Poster></Poster>
    <EventNumber>MS12</EventNumber>
    <EventDate>Jul 12, 2022</EventDate>
    <EventStartTime>2022-07-12T08:30:00</EventStartTime>
    <EventEndTime>2022-07-12T10:30:00</EventEndTime>
    <EventFilter>ED22|Minisymposium</EventFilter>
    <EventLocation></EventLocation>
    <EventRoom>404</EventRoom>
    <FloorPlan></FloorPlan>
    <EVENT_FEE></EVENT_FEE>
    <EventKeywords>2800</EventKeywords>
    <EventChairs></EventChairs>
    <EventModerators></EventModerators>
    <EventSpeakers>Rana Parshad</EventSpeakers>
    <EventSpeakerIDs>793432</EventSpeakerIDs>
    <EventSponsor></EventSponsor>
    <EventHandoutName>Abstract</EventHandoutName>
    <EventHandoutURL>http://meetings.siam.org/sess/dsp_talk.cfm?p=120301</EventHandoutURL>
    <EventDescription xsi:nil="true" />
    <EventParent>73860-SESS</EventParent>
    <EventUniqueID>73860-120301</EventUniqueID>
    <STATUS>active</STATUS>
    <AutoRecord>0</AutoRecord>
    <EnabledForIAV>0</EnabledForIAV>
    <MeetingIAVMode xsi:nil="true" />
    <PublishAutoRecordedVideo xsi:nil="true" />
    <Capacity xsi:nil="true" />
    <DirectLinkEnabled>0</DirectLinkEnabled>
    <DirectLinkRecordingEnabled xsi:nil="true" />
    <start>2022-07-12T08:30:00</start>
  </meeting>
  <meeting>
    <Confcode>ED22</Confcode>
    <EventName>Introduction to Comap’s Certificate in Modeling (CiM) Program for Educators – Part I of II </EventName>
    <EventSubName></EventSubName>
    <Poster></Poster>
    <EventNumber>MT1</EventNumber>
    <EventDate>Jul 11, 2022</EventDate>
    <EventStartTime>2022-07-11T08:30:00</EventStartTime>
    <EventEndTime>2022-07-11T10:30:00</EventEndTime>
    <EventFilter>ED22|Minitutorial</EventFilter>
    <EventLocation></EventLocation>
    <EventRoom>405</EventRoom>
    <FloorPlan></FloorPlan>
    <EVENT_FEE></EVENT_FEE>
    <EventKeywords></EventKeywords>
    <EventChairs></EventChairs>
    <EventModerators></EventModerators>
    <EventSpeakers>Karl Schmitt</EventSpeakers>
    <EventSpeakerIDs>732230</EventSpeakerIDs>
    <EventSponsor></EventSponsor>
    <EventHandoutName>Abstract</EventHandoutName>
    <EventHandoutURL>http://meetings.siam.org/sess/dsp_talk.cfm?p=123503</EventHandoutURL>
    <EventDescription xsi:nil="true" />
    <EventParent>74631-SESS</EventParent>
    <EventUniqueID>74631-123503</EventUniqueID>
    <STATUS>active</STATUS>
    <AutoRecord>0</AutoRecord>
    <EnabledForIAV>0</EnabledForIAV>
    <MeetingIAVMode xsi:nil="true" />
    <PublishAutoRecordedVideo xsi:nil="true" />
    <Capacity xsi:nil="true" />
    <DirectLinkEnabled>0</DirectLinkEnabled>
    <DirectLinkRecordingEnabled xsi:nil="true" />
    <start>2022-07-11T08:30:00</start>
  </meeting>
  <meeting>
    <Confcode>ED22</Confcode>
    <EventName>Education, Data, and Social Justice</EventName>
    <EventSubName></EventSubName>
    <Poster></Poster>
    <EventNumber>IP3</EventNumber>
    <EventDate>Jul 12, 2022</EventDate>
    <EventStartTime>2022-07-12T11:00:00</EventStartTime>
    <EventEndTime>2022-07-12T11:45:00</EventEndTime>
    <EventFilter>ED22|Invited Speaker</EventFilter>
    <EventLocation></EventLocation>
    <EventRoom>406</EventRoom>
    <FloorPlan></FloorPlan>
    <EVENT_FEE></EVENT_FEE>
    <EventKeywords></EventKeywords>
    <EventChairs></EventChairs>
    <EventModerators></EventModerators>
    <EventSpeakers>Chad Topaz</EventSpeakers>
    <EventSpeakerIDs>87940</EventSpeakerIDs>
    <EventSponsor></EventSponsor>
    <EventHandoutName>Abstract</EventHandoutName>
    <EventHandoutURL>http://meetings.siam.org/sess/dsp_talk.cfm?p=119913</EventHandoutURL>
    <EventDescription>While the importance of data science training has been highlighted by stakeholders across the mathematical sciences, the fusion of data skills with core parts of the curriculum has yet to be fully realized. In parallel to this challenge, the mathematical sciences are struggling with issues of equity, diversity, and inclusion. This talk presents pathways for incorporating data skills into undergraduate mathematics education in ways that support social justice. One pathway is through the classroom. I will present selected examples of course activities such as creation of computational art designed to celebrate artists from marginalized identity groups. A second pathway is through undergraduate research. I will showcase data-intensive student projects, including work on incarceration policy on Rikers Island. Finally, I will highlight resources for instructors who themselves want to grow their data skills and/or their understanding of social justice.

	
</EventDescription>
    <EventParent>73756-SESS</EventParent>
    <EventUniqueID>73756-119913</EventUniqueID>
    <STATUS>active</STATUS>
    <AutoRecord>0</AutoRecord>
    <EnabledForIAV>0</EnabledForIAV>
    <MeetingIAVMode xsi:nil="true" />
    <PublishAutoRecordedVideo xsi:nil="true" />
    <Capacity xsi:nil="true" />
    <DirectLinkEnabled>0</DirectLinkEnabled>
    <DirectLinkRecordingEnabled xsi:nil="true" />
    <start>2022-07-12T11:00:00</start>
  </meeting>
  <meeting>
    <Confcode>ED22</Confcode>
    <EventName>Mathematical Modeling Education: Developments in the Russian Federation</EventName>
    <EventSubName></EventSubName>
    <Poster></Poster>
    <EventNumber>MS4</EventNumber>
    <EventDate>Jul 11, 2022</EventDate>
    <EventStartTime>2022-07-11T08:30:00</EventStartTime>
    <EventEndTime>2022-07-11T10:30:00</EventEndTime>
    <EventFilter>ED22|Minisymposium</EventFilter>
    <EventLocation></EventLocation>
    <EventRoom>401</EventRoom>
    <FloorPlan></FloorPlan>
    <EVENT_FEE></EVENT_FEE>
    <EventKeywords>2800</EventKeywords>
    <EventChairs></EventChairs>
    <EventModerators></EventModerators>
    <EventSpeakers>Vladimir Dubrovsky</EventSpeakers>
    <EventSpeakerIDs>805590</EventSpeakerIDs>
    <EventSponsor></EventSponsor>
    <EventHandoutName>Abstract</EventHandoutName>
    <EventHandoutURL>http://meetings.siam.org/sess/dsp_talk.cfm?p=120537</EventHandoutURL>
    <EventDescription>
Two teams from Russia have been participating in IMMC every year since its first edition. Initially, only two schools were involved in the selection, but step by step, the number of schools and teams increased, and lately we have about 30 teams from the places scattered all over the country, from Siberia through Urals to Caucasus and to Moscow, competing for a pass to the international round. To popularize IMMC and related activities, we use various events for high school students and teachers, most notably, the international Mathematical Modeling Tournament (MMT) conducted annually by the Kolmogorov School of MSU. MMT comprises four contests, one of which is similar to IMMC and the other three are closer to traditional olympiads in terms of their format and to applied mathematics in terms of content, which makes them easier accessible for unprepared students. Sample problems from MMT will be presented. 
More generally, we will discuss the reasons why Russian teams are not as successful at IMMC as could be expected judging by their results at IMO and other traditional olympiads.

</EventDescription>
    <EventParent>74050-SESS</EventParent>
    <EventUniqueID>74050-120537</EventUniqueID>
    <STATUS>active</STATUS>
    <AutoRecord>0</AutoRecord>
    <EnabledForIAV>0</EnabledForIAV>
    <MeetingIAVMode xsi:nil="true" />
    <PublishAutoRecordedVideo xsi:nil="true" />
    <Capacity xsi:nil="true" />
    <DirectLinkEnabled>0</DirectLinkEnabled>
    <DirectLinkRecordingEnabled xsi:nil="true" />
    <start>2022-07-11T08:30:00</start>
  </meeting>
  <meeting>
    <Confcode>ED22</Confcode>
    <EventName>The History and Future of Lathisms: Latinxs and Hispanics in the Mathematical Sciences</EventName>
    <EventSubName></EventSubName>
    <Poster></Poster>
    <EventNumber>MS5</EventNumber>
    <EventDate>Jul 11, 2022</EventDate>
    <EventStartTime>2022-07-11T16:00:00</EventStartTime>
    <EventEndTime>2022-07-11T18:00:00</EventEndTime>
    <EventFilter>ED22|Minisymposium</EventFilter>
    <EventLocation></EventLocation>
    <EventRoom>405</EventRoom>
    <FloorPlan></FloorPlan>
    <EVENT_FEE></EVENT_FEE>
    <EventKeywords>2800</EventKeywords>
    <EventChairs></EventChairs>
    <EventModerators></EventModerators>
    <EventSpeakers>Pamela Harris</EventSpeakers>
    <EventSpeakerIDs>779079</EventSpeakerIDs>
    <EventSponsor></EventSponsor>
    <EventHandoutName>Abstract</EventHandoutName>
    <EventHandoutURL>http://meetings.siam.org/sess/dsp_talk.cfm?p=122102</EventHandoutURL>
    <EventDescription>In this talk I will discuss the history of Lathisms, from its creation to our hopes for the future. I will also share some of the current challenges and opportunities we face when building inclusive communities that uplift those who are most marginalized in the mathematical sciences. Lastly, I will give a variety of ways in which those who are interested can get involved with Lathisms. Its goals and programming aim to be community driven, and it needs the support of our community members to grow and thrive. 
</EventDescription>
    <EventParent>74435-SESS</EventParent>
    <EventUniqueID>74435-122102</EventUniqueID>
    <STATUS>active</STATUS>
    <AutoRecord>0</AutoRecord>
    <EnabledForIAV>0</EnabledForIAV>
    <MeetingIAVMode xsi:nil="true" />
    <PublishAutoRecordedVideo xsi:nil="true" />
    <Capacity xsi:nil="true" />
    <DirectLinkEnabled>0</DirectLinkEnabled>
    <DirectLinkRecordingEnabled xsi:nil="true" />
    <start>2022-07-11T16:00:00</start>
  </meeting>
  <meeting>
    <Confcode>ED22</Confcode>
    <EventName>Sharing Resources and Facilitating Community Conversations About QuantCrit</EventName>
    <EventSubName></EventSubName>
    <Poster></Poster>
    <EventNumber>MS6</EventNumber>
    <EventDate>Jul 11, 2022</EventDate>
    <EventStartTime>2022-07-11T17:30:00</EventStartTime>
    <EventEndTime>2022-07-11T17:55:00</EventEndTime>
    <EventFilter>ED22|Minisymposium</EventFilter>
    <EventLocation></EventLocation>
    <EventRoom>404</EventRoom>
    <FloorPlan></FloorPlan>
    <EVENT_FEE></EVENT_FEE>
    <EventKeywords>2800</EventKeywords>
    <EventChairs></EventChairs>
    <EventModerators></EventModerators>
    <EventSpeakers>Carrie Diaz Eaton</EventSpeakers>
    <EventSpeakerIDs>805726</EventSpeakerIDs>
    <EventSponsor></EventSponsor>
    <EventHandoutName>Abstract</EventHandoutName>
    <EventHandoutURL>http://meetings.siam.org/sess/dsp_talk.cfm?p=121552</EventHandoutURL>
    <EventDescription>As new fields, like mathematics for social justice and QuantCrit, are explored and defined, it is important to identify where current work is happening. We do this in order to be more efficient (stop reinventing the wheel) and to build quickly on the work already done. In this active, participant-driven session, we will work on compiling resources and sharing experiences from our session speakers and participants.
</EventDescription>
    <EventParent>74336-SESS</EventParent>
    <EventUniqueID>74336-121552</EventUniqueID>
    <STATUS>active</STATUS>
    <AutoRecord>0</AutoRecord>
    <EnabledForIAV>0</EnabledForIAV>
    <MeetingIAVMode xsi:nil="true" />
    <PublishAutoRecordedVideo xsi:nil="true" />
    <Capacity xsi:nil="true" />
    <DirectLinkEnabled>0</DirectLinkEnabled>
    <DirectLinkRecordingEnabled xsi:nil="true" />
    <start>2022-07-11T16:00:00</start>
  </meeting>
  <meeting>
    <Confcode>ED22</Confcode>
    <EventName>RTG: Data-Intensive Research and Computing at the University of California, Merced</EventName>
    <EventSubName></EventSubName>
    <Poster></Poster>
    <EventNumber>MS7</EventNumber>
    <EventDate>Jul 11, 2022</EventDate>
    <EventStartTime>2022-07-11T17:00:00</EventStartTime>
    <EventEndTime>2022-07-11T17:25:00</EventEndTime>
    <EventFilter>ED22|Minisymposium</EventFilter>
    <EventLocation></EventLocation>
    <EventRoom>403</EventRoom>
    <FloorPlan></FloorPlan>
    <EVENT_FEE></EVENT_FEE>
    <EventKeywords>5100</EventKeywords>
    <EventChairs></EventChairs>
    <EventModerators></EventModerators>
    <EventSpeakers>Francois Blanchette</EventSpeakers>
    <EventSpeakerIDs>750466</EventSpeakerIDs>
    <EventSponsor></EventSponsor>
    <EventHandoutName>Abstract</EventHandoutName>
    <EventHandoutURL>http://meetings.siam.org/sess/dsp_talk.cfm?p=120909</EventHandoutURL>
    <EventDescription>Since summer 2019, the University of California Merced campus has been running the Data-Intensive Research And Computing (DIRAC) RTG. In this presentation, we will describe the research foci of our program and present the structure we put in place to enhance and support mentoring at all levels. In particular, we formed small Mentoring and Research Training (SMaRT) teams that are vertically integrated, combining faculty, postdocs, graduate students, and undergraduate researchers to establish a community of researchers that can serve to support each other at various points of their careers. We will discuss successes and challenges encountered over the last three years of this project.</EventDescription>
    <EventParent>74082-SESS</EventParent>
    <EventUniqueID>74082-120909</EventUniqueID>
    <STATUS>active</STATUS>
    <AutoRecord>0</AutoRecord>
    <EnabledForIAV>0</EnabledForIAV>
    <MeetingIAVMode xsi:nil="true" />
    <PublishAutoRecordedVideo xsi:nil="true" />
    <Capacity xsi:nil="true" />
    <DirectLinkEnabled>0</DirectLinkEnabled>
    <DirectLinkRecordingEnabled xsi:nil="true" />
    <start>2022-07-11T16:00:00</start>
  </meeting>
  <meeting>
    <Confcode>ED22</Confcode>
    <EventName>Through the Looking Glass: Self-Reflections on Effective Dei Work from a Year-Plus of Trying</EventName>
    <EventSubName></EventSubName>
    <Poster></Poster>
    <EventNumber>MS10</EventNumber>
    <EventDate>Jul 12, 2022</EventDate>
    <EventStartTime>2022-07-12T08:30:00</EventStartTime>
    <EventEndTime>2022-07-12T10:30:00</EventEndTime>
    <EventFilter>ED22|Minisymposium</EventFilter>
    <EventLocation></EventLocation>
    <EventRoom>406</EventRoom>
    <FloorPlan></FloorPlan>
    <EVENT_FEE></EVENT_FEE>
    <EventKeywords>2800</EventKeywords>
    <EventChairs></EventChairs>
    <EventModerators></EventModerators>
    <EventSpeakers>Suzanne Sindi</EventSpeakers>
    <EventSpeakerIDs>756849</EventSpeakerIDs>
    <EventSponsor></EventSponsor>
    <EventHandoutName>Abstract</EventHandoutName>
    <EventHandoutURL>http://meetings.siam.org/sess/dsp_talk.cfm?p=120885</EventHandoutURL>
    <EventDescription xsi:nil="true" />
    <EventParent>74170-SESS</EventParent>
    <EventUniqueID>74170-120885</EventUniqueID>
    <STATUS>active</STATUS>
    <AutoRecord>0</AutoRecord>
    <EnabledForIAV>0</EnabledForIAV>
    <MeetingIAVMode xsi:nil="true" />
    <PublishAutoRecordedVideo xsi:nil="true" />
    <Capacity xsi:nil="true" />
    <DirectLinkEnabled>0</DirectLinkEnabled>
    <DirectLinkRecordingEnabled xsi:nil="true" />
    <start>2022-07-12T08:30:00</start>
  </meeting>
  <meeting>
    <Confcode>ED22</Confcode>
    <EventName>Quantitative Education for Life Science Undergraduates: Lessons from 40 Years of Efforts</EventName>
    <EventSubName></EventSubName>
    <Poster></Poster>
    <EventNumber>MS11</EventNumber>
    <EventDate>Jul 12, 2022</EventDate>
    <EventStartTime>2022-07-12T08:30:00</EventStartTime>
    <EventEndTime>2022-07-12T10:30:00</EventEndTime>
    <EventFilter>ED22|Minisymposium</EventFilter>
    <EventLocation></EventLocation>
    <EventRoom>405</EventRoom>
    <FloorPlan></FloorPlan>
    <EVENT_FEE></EVENT_FEE>
    <EventKeywords>2800</EventKeywords>
    <EventChairs></EventChairs>
    <EventModerators></EventModerators>
    <EventSpeakers>Louis Gross</EventSpeakers>
    <EventSpeakerIDs>720567</EventSpeakerIDs>
    <EventSponsor></EventSponsor>
    <EventHandoutName>Abstract</EventHandoutName>
    <EventHandoutURL>http://meetings.siam.org/sess/dsp_talk.cfm?p=120082</EventHandoutURL>
    <EventDescription>I will summarize briefly a range of activities over the past several decades to enhance the quantitative conceptual and skill development of undergraduate life science students. These have included formal quantitative courses with emphasis on biological examples, as well as approaches that incorporate quantitative concepts within life science courses. Discussion will include a few case studies to illustrate how biological examples might enhance insight about several different areas of mathematics. I will point out the limited evidence regarding the effectiveness of examples in learning mathematical concepts, discuss progress on a BioCalculus Concept Inventory to assess student's mathematics abilities as affected by the use of real-world examples from the life sciences, and present a novel approach to the problem of prioritization of quantitative topics taking account of local faculty expectations.</EventDescription>
    <EventParent>73886-SESS</EventParent>
    <EventUniqueID>73886-120082</EventUniqueID>
    <STATUS>active</STATUS>
    <AutoRecord>0</AutoRecord>
    <EnabledForIAV>0</EnabledForIAV>
    <MeetingIAVMode xsi:nil="true" />
    <PublishAutoRecordedVideo xsi:nil="true" />
    <Capacity xsi:nil="true" />
    <DirectLinkEnabled>0</DirectLinkEnabled>
    <DirectLinkRecordingEnabled xsi:nil="true" />
    <start>2022-07-12T08:30:00</start>
  </meeting>
  <meeting>
    <Confcode>ED22</Confcode>
    <EventName>Interdisciplinary Mentoring: Mentoring Undergraduate in Biology and Mathematics on Modeling Plant-Virus-Vector Interactions</EventName>
    <EventSubName></EventSubName>
    <Poster></Poster>
    <EventNumber>MS12</EventNumber>
    <EventDate>Jul 12, 2022</EventDate>
    <EventStartTime>2022-07-12T08:30:00</EventStartTime>
    <EventEndTime>2022-07-12T10:30:00</EventEndTime>
    <EventFilter>ED22|Minisymposium</EventFilter>
    <EventLocation></EventLocation>
    <EventRoom>404</EventRoom>
    <FloorPlan></FloorPlan>
    <EVENT_FEE></EVENT_FEE>
    <EventKeywords>2800</EventKeywords>
    <EventChairs></EventChairs>
    <EventModerators></EventModerators>
    <EventSpeakers>Folashade Agusto</EventSpeakers>
    <EventSpeakerIDs>805602</EventSpeakerIDs>
    <EventSponsor></EventSponsor>
    <EventHandoutName>Abstract</EventHandoutName>
    <EventHandoutURL>http://meetings.siam.org/sess/dsp_talk.cfm?p=120557</EventHandoutURL>
    <EventDescription>In this seminar, I will describe our two institutional mentoring approach of biology and mathematics undergraduate students. Our team consist of two groups of undergraduate students, each group had two mathematics students and one biology student with three faculty mentors from two institutions within 45 mins drive of each other. The groups were set up this way to provide the undergraduate students a first-hand overview of interdisciplinary research experience on modeling plant-virus-vector interactions.  I will report how the group concept is used to support undergraduate research in mathematical biology and the mentoring challenges we experienced. 




</EventDescription>
    <EventParent>73860-SESS</EventParent>
    <EventUniqueID>73860-120557</EventUniqueID>
    <STATUS>active</STATUS>
    <AutoRecord>0</AutoRecord>
    <EnabledForIAV>0</EnabledForIAV>
    <MeetingIAVMode xsi:nil="true" />
    <PublishAutoRecordedVideo xsi:nil="true" />
    <Capacity xsi:nil="true" />
    <DirectLinkEnabled>0</DirectLinkEnabled>
    <DirectLinkRecordingEnabled xsi:nil="true" />
    <start>2022-07-12T08:30:00</start>
  </meeting>
  <meeting>
    <Confcode>ED22</Confcode>
    <EventName>Laboratory Modules for Numerical Methods</EventName>
    <EventSubName></EventSubName>
    <Poster></Poster>
    <EventNumber>MS17</EventNumber>
    <EventDate>Jul 12, 2022</EventDate>
    <EventStartTime>2022-07-12T16:00:00</EventStartTime>
    <EventEndTime>2022-07-12T18:00:00</EventEndTime>
    <EventFilter>ED22|Minisymposium</EventFilter>
    <EventLocation></EventLocation>
    <EventRoom>403</EventRoom>
    <FloorPlan></FloorPlan>
    <EVENT_FEE></EVENT_FEE>
    <EventKeywords>2800</EventKeywords>
    <EventChairs></EventChairs>
    <EventModerators></EventModerators>
    <EventSpeakers>Jakob Kotas</EventSpeakers>
    <EventSpeakerIDs>805751</EventSpeakerIDs>
    <EventSponsor></EventSponsor>
    <EventHandoutName>Abstract</EventHandoutName>
    <EventHandoutURL>http://meetings.siam.org/sess/dsp_talk.cfm?p=120997</EventHandoutURL>
    <EventDescription>Education research has suggested that students who receive a wider variety of sensory inputs during the learning process will be able to make more connections and more deeply understand course content. To this end, three laboratory learning modules were designed for a numerical methods course to help students develop intuition for physical systems, to allow for a comparison of real data against numerical solutions of physics equations, and to increase student engagement. These modules were designed to reinforce specific topics covered in the numerical methods curriculum, including numerical differentiation and numerical solution of ordinary differential equations (ODEs) and partial differential equations (PDEs). In this talk I will discuss our development and implementation of these modules.</EventDescription>
    <EventParent>74201-SESS</EventParent>
    <EventUniqueID>74201-120997</EventUniqueID>
    <STATUS>active</STATUS>
    <AutoRecord>0</AutoRecord>
    <EnabledForIAV>0</EnabledForIAV>
    <MeetingIAVMode xsi:nil="true" />
    <PublishAutoRecordedVideo xsi:nil="true" />
    <Capacity xsi:nil="true" />
    <DirectLinkEnabled>0</DirectLinkEnabled>
    <DirectLinkRecordingEnabled xsi:nil="true" />
    <start>2022-07-12T16:00:00</start>
  </meeting>
  <meeting>
    <Confcode>ED22</Confcode>
    <EventName>The Effect of Repetition Learning in Data Analysis Projects</EventName>
    <EventSubName></EventSubName>
    <Poster></Poster>
    <EventNumber>CP2</EventNumber>
    <EventDate>Jul 12, 2022</EventDate>
    <EventStartTime>2022-07-12T17:20:00</EventStartTime>
    <EventEndTime>2022-07-12T17:35:00</EventEndTime>
    <EventFilter>ED22|Contributed</EventFilter>
    <EventLocation></EventLocation>
    <EventRoom>406</EventRoom>
    <FloorPlan></FloorPlan>
    <EVENT_FEE></EVENT_FEE>
    <EventKeywords></EventKeywords>
    <EventChairs></EventChairs>
    <EventModerators></EventModerators>
    <EventSpeakers>Xiaoyi Yang</EventSpeakers>
    <EventSpeakerIDs>805839</EventSpeakerIDs>
    <EventSponsor></EventSponsor>
    <EventHandoutName>Abstract</EventHandoutName>
    <EventHandoutURL>http://meetings.siam.org/sess/dsp_talk.cfm?p=121106</EventHandoutURL>
    <EventDescription>Repetition learning has been considered as an efficient tool to help students to master the knowledge, but it is seldom applied in subjective assignments, like a data analysis project. In practice, we believe that project assignments are less likely to be reviewed after grading, thus it is hard to know whether students have learned from their mistakes. Moreover, because of the flexibility of topic/methodology choices, there may exist more than one correct answer/approach, thus students are always encouraged to view the questions from different perspectives even with the same data. In this work, we want to know what if a student gets a second chance to do the exact same project assignment, can they self-improved the work quality? Between the two submissions, we add a group reflection activity that students will be asked to read the peers’ work, to reflect on what their peers have done great, but they need to improve. This is slightly different from the normal peer review which we focus more on giving suggestions to the peers. Group reflection requires students to think more about how to improve their own work, thus may also be able to improve their self-learning ability. We’d like to quantitatively measure how the repetition project and group reflection may affect students’ learning outcomes in different project settings through both their project scores and word choices in the final analysis report. 
	</EventDescription>
    <EventParent>74689-SESS</EventParent>
    <EventUniqueID>74689-121106</EventUniqueID>
    <STATUS>active</STATUS>
    <AutoRecord>0</AutoRecord>
    <EnabledForIAV>0</EnabledForIAV>
    <MeetingIAVMode xsi:nil="true" />
    <PublishAutoRecordedVideo xsi:nil="true" />
    <Capacity xsi:nil="true" />
    <DirectLinkEnabled>0</DirectLinkEnabled>
    <DirectLinkRecordingEnabled xsi:nil="true" />
    <start>2022-07-12T16:00:00</start>
  </meeting>
  <meeting>
    <Confcode>ED22</Confcode>
    <EventName>Research Projects in Data-Enabled Industrial Mathematics: from a Course to NSF REU Site</EventName>
    <EventSubName></EventSubName>
    <Poster></Poster>
    <EventNumber>CP2</EventNumber>
    <EventDate>Jul 12, 2022</EventDate>
    <EventStartTime>2022-07-12T16:00:00</EventStartTime>
    <EventEndTime>2022-07-12T16:15:00</EventEndTime>
    <EventFilter>ED22|Contributed</EventFilter>
    <EventLocation></EventLocation>
    <EventRoom>406</EventRoom>
    <FloorPlan></FloorPlan>
    <EVENT_FEE></EVENT_FEE>
    <EventKeywords></EventKeywords>
    <EventChairs></EventChairs>
    <EventModerators></EventModerators>
    <EventSpeakers>Mihhail Berezovski</EventSpeakers>
    <EventSpeakerIDs>783188</EventSpeakerIDs>
    <EventSponsor></EventSponsor>
    <EventHandoutName>Abstract</EventHandoutName>
    <EventHandoutURL>http://meetings.siam.org/sess/dsp_talk.cfm?p=121493</EventHandoutURL>
    <EventDescription>Undergraduate research projects with industrial partners combine the essence of academic research and hand-on practice in the real world by building a bridge between them. The real-world problems have an educational impact that cannot be replicated in the traditional mathematics classroom setting. 

In this talk, we will discuss the challenges of bringing collaboration with real business, industry, or government (BIG) into the undergraduate research.  We highlight differences and challenges compare to traditional undergraduate research. We will share our experience from a course to nationwide NSF REU site at Embry-Riddle Aeronautical University. 
</EventDescription>
    <EventParent>74689-SESS</EventParent>
    <EventUniqueID>74689-121493</EventUniqueID>
    <STATUS>active</STATUS>
    <AutoRecord>0</AutoRecord>
    <EnabledForIAV>0</EnabledForIAV>
    <MeetingIAVMode xsi:nil="true" />
    <PublishAutoRecordedVideo xsi:nil="true" />
    <Capacity xsi:nil="true" />
    <DirectLinkEnabled>0</DirectLinkEnabled>
    <DirectLinkRecordingEnabled xsi:nil="true" />
    <start>2022-07-12T16:00:00</start>
  </meeting>
  <meeting>
    <Confcode>ED22</Confcode>
    <EventName>Experiences in Offering a New Undergraduate Course in Mathematical Foundations of Data Science</EventName>
    <EventSubName></EventSubName>
    <Poster></Poster>
    <EventNumber>CP2</EventNumber>
    <EventDate>Jul 12, 2022</EventDate>
    <EventStartTime>2022-07-12T16:40:00</EventStartTime>
    <EventEndTime>2022-07-12T16:55:00</EventEndTime>
    <EventFilter>ED22|Contributed</EventFilter>
    <EventLocation></EventLocation>
    <EventRoom>406</EventRoom>
    <FloorPlan></FloorPlan>
    <EVENT_FEE></EVENT_FEE>
    <EventKeywords></EventKeywords>
    <EventChairs></EventChairs>
    <EventModerators></EventModerators>
    <EventSpeakers>Mansoor Haider</EventSpeakers>
    <EventSpeakerIDs>703625</EventSpeakerIDs>
    <EventSponsor></EventSponsor>
    <EventHandoutName>Abstract</EventHandoutName>
    <EventHandoutURL>http://meetings.siam.org/sess/dsp_talk.cfm?p=121659</EventHandoutURL>
    <EventDescription>This presentation will summarize experiences developing and delivering a new undergraduate course covering foundational topics in data science and data-driven mathematical modeling. The target audience for this course is junior and senior undergraduates pursuing majors or minors in mathematics or applied mathematics at a large STEM-focused public university. Course prerequisites included vector calculus, a first course in linear algebra and some familiarity with Matlab. Strategies and reflections will be shared regarding selection of course topics and source materials, modes for delivery of course content, design of homework sets and group projects, and integration of data into the curriculum. Student feedback as well as experiences with integrating this course into existing degree paths and data science initiatives will also be discussed. </EventDescription>
    <EventParent>74689-SESS</EventParent>
    <EventUniqueID>74689-121659</EventUniqueID>
    <STATUS>active</STATUS>
    <AutoRecord>0</AutoRecord>
    <EnabledForIAV>0</EnabledForIAV>
    <MeetingIAVMode xsi:nil="true" />
    <PublishAutoRecordedVideo xsi:nil="true" />
    <Capacity xsi:nil="true" />
    <DirectLinkEnabled>0</DirectLinkEnabled>
    <DirectLinkRecordingEnabled xsi:nil="true" />
    <start>2022-07-12T16:00:00</start>
  </meeting>
  <meeting>
    <Confcode>ED22</Confcode>
    <EventName>RTG: Randomized Numerical Analysis</EventName>
    <EventSubName></EventSubName>
    <Poster></Poster>
    <EventNumber>MS2</EventNumber>
    <EventDate>Jul 11, 2022</EventDate>
    <EventStartTime>2022-07-11T08:30:00</EventStartTime>
    <EventEndTime>2022-07-11T10:30:00</EventEndTime>
    <EventFilter>ED22|Minisymposium</EventFilter>
    <EventLocation></EventLocation>
    <EventRoom>403</EventRoom>
    <FloorPlan></FloorPlan>
    <EVENT_FEE></EVENT_FEE>
    <EventKeywords>5100</EventKeywords>
    <EventChairs></EventChairs>
    <EventModerators></EventModerators>
    <EventSpeakers>Alen Alexanderian</EventSpeakers>
    <EventSpeakerIDs>795734</EventSpeakerIDs>
    <EventSponsor></EventSponsor>
    <EventHandoutName>Abstract</EventHandoutName>
    <EventHandoutURL>http://meetings.siam.org/sess/dsp_talk.cfm?p=120907</EventHandoutURL>
    <EventDescription>We report on the research, educational, and outreach activities of the NC State RTG award on Randomized Numerical Analysis.  Our research activities are organized across the three interconnected themes of sensitivity analysis, randomized numerical linear algebra, and nonlinear equations.  Our graduate fellows are expected to complete an internship during their studies. These internships typically take place at national labs and have resulted in career opportunities, research collaborations, and new partnerships.  

The program has generated an extensive amount of new research and results; it has provided an enriching environment for our students, postdocs, and faculty participants.



</EventDescription>
    <EventParent>74081-SESS</EventParent>
    <EventUniqueID>74081-120907</EventUniqueID>
    <STATUS>active</STATUS>
    <AutoRecord>0</AutoRecord>
    <EnabledForIAV>0</EnabledForIAV>
    <MeetingIAVMode xsi:nil="true" />
    <PublishAutoRecordedVideo xsi:nil="true" />
    <Capacity xsi:nil="true" />
    <DirectLinkEnabled>0</DirectLinkEnabled>
    <DirectLinkRecordingEnabled xsi:nil="true" />
    <start>2022-07-11T08:30:00</start>
  </meeting>
  <meeting>
    <Confcode>ED22</Confcode>
    <EventName>Questioning Dogma - How P-Values Can Hide Inequities</EventName>
    <EventSubName></EventSubName>
    <Poster></Poster>
    <EventNumber>MS6</EventNumber>
    <EventDate>Jul 11, 2022</EventDate>
    <EventStartTime>2022-07-11T16:00:00</EventStartTime>
    <EventEndTime>2022-07-11T16:25:00</EventEndTime>
    <EventFilter>ED22|Minisymposium</EventFilter>
    <EventLocation></EventLocation>
    <EventRoom>404</EventRoom>
    <FloorPlan></FloorPlan>
    <EVENT_FEE></EVENT_FEE>
    <EventKeywords>2800</EventKeywords>
    <EventChairs></EventChairs>
    <EventModerators></EventModerators>
    <EventSpeakers>Jayson Nissen</EventSpeakers>
    <EventSpeakerIDs>806412</EventSpeakerIDs>
    <EventSponsor></EventSponsor>
    <EventHandoutName>Abstract</EventHandoutName>
    <EventHandoutURL>http://meetings.siam.org/sess/dsp_talk.cfm?p=121549</EventHandoutURL>
    <EventDescription>Scholars, largely women of color, have used qualitative methods to show the inequities that Black women and other women of color face during their STEM education. Quantitative discipline-based education research (DBER), however, largely fails to engage in similar intersectional work to complement this qualitative research. ``Mindless statistics" (Gigerenzer, 2004) stand in the way intersectional quantitative research through a dogmatic dedication to $p &lt; 0.05$. Dogmatic, because the American Statistical Association calls for ``Moving to a world beyond `$p &lt; 0.05$'" (Wasserstein, Schirm, and Lazar, 2019). This dedication to statistical significance pushes researchers to aggregate data across demographic groups. We argue researchers should instead focus on disentangling and informing the intersecting power structures of racism, sexism, and classism. We will discuss common statistical practices in DBER, how these practices obscure inequities, and solutions to these issues.

</EventDescription>
    <EventParent>74336-SESS</EventParent>
    <EventUniqueID>74336-121549</EventUniqueID>
    <STATUS>active</STATUS>
    <AutoRecord>0</AutoRecord>
    <EnabledForIAV>0</EnabledForIAV>
    <MeetingIAVMode xsi:nil="true" />
    <PublishAutoRecordedVideo xsi:nil="true" />
    <Capacity xsi:nil="true" />
    <DirectLinkEnabled>0</DirectLinkEnabled>
    <DirectLinkRecordingEnabled xsi:nil="true" />
    <start>2022-07-11T16:00:00</start>
  </meeting>
  <meeting>
    <Confcode>ED22</Confcode>
    <EventName>RTG: Computational Mathematics for Data Science</EventName>
    <EventSubName></EventSubName>
    <Poster></Poster>
    <EventNumber>MS7</EventNumber>
    <EventDate>Jul 11, 2022</EventDate>
    <EventStartTime>2022-07-11T16:00:00</EventStartTime>
    <EventEndTime>2022-07-11T16:35:00</EventEndTime>
    <EventFilter>ED22|Minisymposium</EventFilter>
    <EventLocation></EventLocation>
    <EventRoom>403</EventRoom>
    <FloorPlan></FloorPlan>
    <EVENT_FEE></EVENT_FEE>
    <EventKeywords>5100</EventKeywords>
    <EventChairs></EventChairs>
    <EventModerators></EventModerators>
    <EventSpeakers>James Nagy</EventSpeakers>
    <EventSpeakerIDs>35611</EventSpeakerIDs>
    <EventSponsor></EventSponsor>
    <EventHandoutName>Abstract</EventHandoutName>
    <EventHandoutURL>http://meetings.siam.org/sess/dsp_talk.cfm?p=120906</EventHandoutURL>
    <EventDescription>The Emory RTG is designed unify and further develop the mathematical theory and computational tools used in applications ranging from data assimilation to machine learning. This comprehensive approach will be based on knowledge from, and make novel contributions to mathematics, computational science, and data science. Particular focus will be on the mathematics of deep learning and data assimilation and their application in impactful areas of medicine (cardiac modeling, medical imaging), the weather and environment (hurricane storm surge modeling), and disease outbreak modeling. Common threads in these areas are their mathematical foundations, most importantly differential equations, optimization, linear algebra and advanced techniques from computational science, such as parallel and distributed computing. This RTG program is anchored around year-long research themes that include one or more of the above mentioned core research themes. Training will by multi-faceted, to include education, potential career skills and experiences, soft skills, scientific integrity, and promoting an appreciation for diversity.</EventDescription>
    <EventParent>74082-SESS</EventParent>
    <EventUniqueID>74082-120906</EventUniqueID>
    <STATUS>active</STATUS>
    <AutoRecord>0</AutoRecord>
    <EnabledForIAV>0</EnabledForIAV>
    <MeetingIAVMode xsi:nil="true" />
    <PublishAutoRecordedVideo xsi:nil="true" />
    <Capacity xsi:nil="true" />
    <DirectLinkEnabled>0</DirectLinkEnabled>
    <DirectLinkRecordingEnabled xsi:nil="true" />
    <start>2022-07-11T16:00:00</start>
  </meeting>
  <meeting>
    <Confcode>ED22</Confcode>
    <EventName>Implementing Mathematical Modeling with Prospective Elementary Teachers</EventName>
    <EventSubName></EventSubName>
    <Poster></Poster>
    <EventNumber>MS8</EventNumber>
    <EventDate>Jul 11, 2022</EventDate>
    <EventStartTime>2022-07-11T16:00:00</EventStartTime>
    <EventEndTime>2022-07-11T18:00:00</EventEndTime>
    <EventFilter>ED22|Minisymposium</EventFilter>
    <EventLocation></EventLocation>
    <EventRoom>402</EventRoom>
    <FloorPlan></FloorPlan>
    <EVENT_FEE></EVENT_FEE>
    <EventKeywords>3000</EventKeywords>
    <EventChairs></EventChairs>
    <EventModerators></EventModerators>
    <EventSpeakers>Will Tidwell</EventSpeakers>
    <EventSpeakerIDs>805742</EventSpeakerIDs>
    <EventSponsor></EventSponsor>
    <EventHandoutName>Abstract</EventHandoutName>
    <EventHandoutURL>http://meetings.siam.org/sess/dsp_talk.cfm?p=120974</EventHandoutURL>
    <EventDescription>Over the last two decades, the mathematics education community increased research on and attention to the education of prospective teachers in mathematical modeling. Much research is devoted to better preparing future and current middle and high school teachers in teaching modeling within teacher education. Yet, standards across the United States include mathematical modeling in elementary grades. The Guidelines for Assessment and Instruction in Mathematical Modeling Education (GAIMME) report (2016) emphasizes modeling in elementary grades to help students develop skills in modeling for later grades. To better understand elementary teachers’ conceptions of mathematical modeling, research was conducted using mathematical modeling curricular units that were implemented in mathematics content courses for prospective elementary teachers. The curricular units emphasized the mathematical modeling process focusing on the various elements of and approaches to modeling rather than solely on the final models. In addition to student-created models and reports, questionnaires assessing conceptions and reflections on the modeling process were collected during two modeling units across the course of a semester. In this colloquium, we discuss the findings from implementing these mathematical modeling curricular units and their impact on prospective elementary teachers’ conceptions of mathematical modeling.
</EventDescription>
    <EventParent>74198-SESS</EventParent>
    <EventUniqueID>74198-120974</EventUniqueID>
    <STATUS>active</STATUS>
    <AutoRecord>0</AutoRecord>
    <EnabledForIAV>0</EnabledForIAV>
    <MeetingIAVMode xsi:nil="true" />
    <PublishAutoRecordedVideo xsi:nil="true" />
    <Capacity xsi:nil="true" />
    <DirectLinkEnabled>0</DirectLinkEnabled>
    <DirectLinkRecordingEnabled xsi:nil="true" />
    <start>2022-07-11T16:00:00</start>
  </meeting>
  <meeting>
    <Confcode>ED22</Confcode>
    <EventName>Math Modeling and Social Justice</EventName>
    <EventSubName></EventSubName>
    <Poster></Poster>
    <EventNumber>MS13</EventNumber>
    <EventDate>Jul 12, 2022</EventDate>
    <EventStartTime>2022-07-12T08:30:00</EventStartTime>
    <EventEndTime>2022-07-12T10:30:00</EventEndTime>
    <EventFilter>ED22|Minisymposium</EventFilter>
    <EventLocation></EventLocation>
    <EventRoom>403</EventRoom>
    <FloorPlan></FloorPlan>
    <EVENT_FEE></EVENT_FEE>
    <EventKeywords>3000</EventKeywords>
    <EventChairs></EventChairs>
    <EventModerators></EventModerators>
    <EventSpeakers>Wesley Hamilton</EventSpeakers>
    <EventSpeakerIDs>805748</EventSpeakerIDs>
    <EventSponsor></EventSponsor>
    <EventHandoutName>Abstract</EventHandoutName>
    <EventHandoutURL>http://meetings.siam.org/sess/dsp_talk.cfm?p=120994</EventHandoutURL>
    <EventDescription>In the Spring 2022 semester, the University of Utah hosted a "datathon4justice" modeled after a datathon organized by QSIDE in Fall 2021. This event gathered undergraduates interested in ways that computational methods can address social justice questions, and for many was the first time they realized such connections could be used in fruitful ways. I'll talk about the route we followed to put on this event, from QSIDE's (excellent) 2021 datathon4justice through getting support from the university through some specifics about the organization process.</EventDescription>
    <EventParent>74199-SESS</EventParent>
    <EventUniqueID>74199-120994</EventUniqueID>
    <STATUS>active</STATUS>
    <AutoRecord>0</AutoRecord>
    <EnabledForIAV>0</EnabledForIAV>
    <MeetingIAVMode xsi:nil="true" />
    <PublishAutoRecordedVideo xsi:nil="true" />
    <Capacity xsi:nil="true" />
    <DirectLinkEnabled>0</DirectLinkEnabled>
    <DirectLinkRecordingEnabled xsi:nil="true" />
    <start>2022-07-12T08:30:00</start>
  </meeting>
  <meeting>
    <Confcode>ED22</Confcode>
    <EventName>Leveraging Agile Project Methodology in Undergraduate Research Mentorship and Delivery</EventName>
    <EventSubName></EventSubName>
    <Poster></Poster>
    <EventNumber>MS16</EventNumber>
    <EventDate>Jul 12, 2022</EventDate>
    <EventStartTime>2022-07-12T17:00:00</EventStartTime>
    <EventEndTime>2022-07-12T17:25:00</EventEndTime>
    <EventFilter>ED22|Minisymposium</EventFilter>
    <EventLocation></EventLocation>
    <EventRoom>404</EventRoom>
    <FloorPlan></FloorPlan>
    <EVENT_FEE></EVENT_FEE>
    <EventKeywords>2800</EventKeywords>
    <EventChairs></EventChairs>
    <EventModerators></EventModerators>
    <EventSpeakers>Matthew Beauregard</EventSpeakers>
    <EventSpeakerIDs>793428</EventSpeakerIDs>
    <EventSponsor></EventSponsor>
    <EventHandoutName>Abstract</EventHandoutName>
    <EventHandoutURL>http://meetings.siam.org/sess/dsp_talk.cfm?p=120304</EventHandoutURL>
    <EventDescription>It is understood that early exposure to research and subsequent curriculum incorporation for undergraduates can lead to increased retention and a strengthening of the underlying community of majors within the STEM disciplines.  In this talk, an overview of a multi-year, successful mentored undergraduate research program is discussed.  The research experience utilized an agile project methodology and incorporated concerted discussions of self-efficacy and personal STEM identity. This research is supported by the National Science Foundation grant DMS-1715044.
</EventDescription>
    <EventParent>73861-SESS</EventParent>
    <EventUniqueID>73861-120304</EventUniqueID>
    <STATUS>inactive</STATUS>
    <AutoRecord>0</AutoRecord>
    <EnabledForIAV>0</EnabledForIAV>
    <MeetingIAVMode xsi:nil="true" />
    <PublishAutoRecordedVideo xsi:nil="true" />
    <Capacity xsi:nil="true" />
    <DirectLinkEnabled>0</DirectLinkEnabled>
    <DirectLinkRecordingEnabled xsi:nil="true" />
    <start>2022-07-12T16:00:00</start>
  </meeting>
  <meeting>
    <Confcode>ED22</Confcode>
    <EventName>Research from the Sidelines with Sports Analytics</EventName>
    <EventSubName></EventSubName>
    <Poster></Poster>
    <EventNumber>MS16</EventNumber>
    <EventDate>Jul 12, 2022</EventDate>
    <EventStartTime>2022-07-12T17:00:00</EventStartTime>
    <EventEndTime>2022-07-12T17:25:00</EventEndTime>
    <EventFilter>ED22|Minisymposium</EventFilter>
    <EventLocation></EventLocation>
    <EventRoom>404</EventRoom>
    <FloorPlan></FloorPlan>
    <EVENT_FEE></EVENT_FEE>
    <EventKeywords>2800</EventKeywords>
    <EventChairs></EventChairs>
    <EventModerators></EventModerators>
    <EventSpeakers>Timothy Chartier</EventSpeakers>
    <EventSpeakerIDs>89782</EventSpeakerIDs>
    <EventSponsor></EventSponsor>
    <EventHandoutName>Abstract</EventHandoutName>
    <EventHandoutURL>http://meetings.siam.org/sess/dsp_talk.cfm?p=120305</EventHandoutURL>
    <EventDescription>Sports analytics has gathered tremendous momentum as one of the most dynamic fields. Diving deep into the numbers of sports can be game changing or a framework for data analytics research. What questions can be explored? What actionable insights can be gleaned for teams? From March Madness to national media broadcasts, analytics are becoming increasingly indispensable. Dr. Tim Chartier will discuss outlooks that help with successful analytics, and the variety of questions that can be tackled. He will also share how he leads students to dig into sports using math and computer science, and their success across the NBA, NFL, NASCAR, ESPN and his own college teams.
</EventDescription>
    <EventParent>73861-SESS</EventParent>
    <EventUniqueID>73861-120305</EventUniqueID>
    <STATUS>active</STATUS>
    <AutoRecord>0</AutoRecord>
    <EnabledForIAV>0</EnabledForIAV>
    <MeetingIAVMode xsi:nil="true" />
    <PublishAutoRecordedVideo xsi:nil="true" />
    <Capacity xsi:nil="true" />
    <DirectLinkEnabled>0</DirectLinkEnabled>
    <DirectLinkRecordingEnabled xsi:nil="true" />
    <start>2022-07-12T16:00:00</start>
  </meeting>
  <meeting>
    <Confcode>ED22</Confcode>
    <EventName>Enhancing Student Learning Through Projects and Presentations in a Mathematical Modeling Class</EventName>
    <EventSubName></EventSubName>
    <Poster></Poster>
    <EventNumber>MS17</EventNumber>
    <EventDate>Jul 12, 2022</EventDate>
    <EventStartTime>2022-07-12T16:00:00</EventStartTime>
    <EventEndTime>2022-07-12T18:00:00</EventEndTime>
    <EventFilter>ED22|Minisymposium</EventFilter>
    <EventLocation></EventLocation>
    <EventRoom>403</EventRoom>
    <FloorPlan></FloorPlan>
    <EVENT_FEE></EVENT_FEE>
    <EventKeywords>2800</EventKeywords>
    <EventChairs></EventChairs>
    <EventModerators></EventModerators>
    <EventSpeakers>Eli Goldwyn</EventSpeakers>
    <EventSpeakerIDs>805752</EventSpeakerIDs>
    <EventSponsor></EventSponsor>
    <EventHandoutName>Abstract</EventHandoutName>
    <EventHandoutURL>http://meetings.siam.org/sess/dsp_talk.cfm?p=120998</EventHandoutURL>
    <EventDescription>Classes such as \emph{Mathematical Modeling} and \emph{Nonlinear Dynamics} offer unique opportunities to enhance student learning through group or individual projects. When I first included student projects in these classes I was anxious about whether students learning and interest in the material would decline. I was also concerned with student motivation and work quality without the more regular and standardized homework and exams. On the contrary, I have found students worked much harder and seemed to master the material involved in their project at a deeper level than they did with homework or exam questions. Additionally, both in conversation with me and in their course evaluations, a large majority of students commented on how much they enjoyed and learned from their projects. Several of these students mentioned that they wish they had more time for their projects. In this talk, I discuss the guidance I give and the structure I provide students for their project. I also focus on what I have learned and changed over the last few years of assigning student projects.


</EventDescription>
    <EventParent>74201-SESS</EventParent>
    <EventUniqueID>74201-120998</EventUniqueID>
    <STATUS>active</STATUS>
    <AutoRecord>0</AutoRecord>
    <EnabledForIAV>0</EnabledForIAV>
    <MeetingIAVMode xsi:nil="true" />
    <PublishAutoRecordedVideo xsi:nil="true" />
    <Capacity xsi:nil="true" />
    <DirectLinkEnabled>0</DirectLinkEnabled>
    <DirectLinkRecordingEnabled xsi:nil="true" />
    <start>2022-07-12T16:00:00</start>
  </meeting>
  <meeting>
    <Confcode>ED22</Confcode>
    <EventName>Closing Remarks and Presentation: Toward a Culturally Relevant and Historically Responsive Data Science</EventName>
    <EventSubName></EventSubName>
    <Poster></Poster>
    <EventNumber>IP4</EventNumber>
    <EventDate>Jul 12, 2022</EventDate>
    <EventStartTime>2022-07-12T11:45:00</EventStartTime>
    <EventEndTime>2022-07-12T12:35:00</EventEndTime>
    <EventFilter>ED22|Invited Speaker</EventFilter>
    <EventLocation></EventLocation>
    <EventRoom>406</EventRoom>
    <FloorPlan></FloorPlan>
    <EVENT_FEE></EVENT_FEE>
    <EventKeywords></EventKeywords>
    <EventChairs></EventChairs>
    <EventModerators></EventModerators>
    <EventSpeakers>Nathan Alexander</EventSpeakers>
    <EventSpeakerIDs>805303</EventSpeakerIDs>
    <EventSponsor></EventSponsor>
    <EventHandoutName>Abstract</EventHandoutName>
    <EventHandoutURL>http://meetings.siam.org/sess/dsp_talk.cfm?p=119910</EventHandoutURL>
    <EventDescription>In the expanding discourses around data science and statistical data analysis, less work has been done
to make culturally- and historically- centered pedagogies a central area of investigation. To this end,
this invited talk will examine seminal theories in education focused on the role of culture and history in
teaching and student learning. Within the development of inquiry-based classrooms, these frameworks
support our collective knowledge around the role of culture and history in relation to applied
mathematics, statistics, and data science education in k-12, postsecondary, and community settings.
Moreover, these frameworks can be used to support the ongoing development of data science programs
and research-practice partnerships that advance actionable and critical data science practices.

	
</EventDescription>
    <EventParent>73753-SESS</EventParent>
    <EventUniqueID>73753-119910</EventUniqueID>
    <STATUS>active</STATUS>
    <AutoRecord>0</AutoRecord>
    <EnabledForIAV>0</EnabledForIAV>
    <MeetingIAVMode xsi:nil="true" />
    <PublishAutoRecordedVideo xsi:nil="true" />
    <Capacity xsi:nil="true" />
    <DirectLinkEnabled>0</DirectLinkEnabled>
    <DirectLinkRecordingEnabled xsi:nil="true" />
    <start>2022-07-12T11:45:00</start>
  </meeting>
  <meeting>
    <Confcode>ED22</Confcode>
    <EventName>RTG: Modeling and Computations for Complex Systems at Southern Methodist University</EventName>
    <EventSubName></EventSubName>
    <Poster></Poster>
    <EventNumber>MS2</EventNumber>
    <EventDate>Jul 11, 2022</EventDate>
    <EventStartTime>2022-07-11T08:30:00</EventStartTime>
    <EventEndTime>2022-07-11T10:30:00</EventEndTime>
    <EventFilter>ED22|Minisymposium</EventFilter>
    <EventLocation></EventLocation>
    <EventRoom>403</EventRoom>
    <FloorPlan></FloorPlan>
    <EVENT_FEE></EVENT_FEE>
    <EventKeywords>5100</EventKeywords>
    <EventChairs></EventChairs>
    <EventModerators></EventModerators>
    <EventSpeakers>Andrea Barreiro</EventSpeakers>
    <EventSpeakerIDs>729272</EventSpeakerIDs>
    <EventSponsor></EventSponsor>
    <EventHandoutName>Abstract</EventHandoutName>
    <EventHandoutURL>http://meetings.siam.org/sess/dsp_talk.cfm?p=123418</EventHandoutURL>
    <EventDescription>As this RTG starts its fourth year, I will provide a list of activities, accomplishments and challenges we have faced during the first three years. With 3 core topics running in parallel:  Computation-enabled investigations into circuits and cognition, Nonlinear dynamics and the modeling of large systems and
Modeling complex transport processes in nanoscale manufacturing, specific educational activities focused on vertically integrated training of undergraduate students, graduate students, and postdoctoral fellows have worked well.  A bigger challenge has been developing cross-fertilization. For this we have found that the postdocs have played a critical role in facilitating this.  With this in mind, the presentation will highlight successes and upcoming plans, with a summary of the overall impact the RTG  has had in our general PhD program.</EventDescription>
    <EventParent>74081-SESS</EventParent>
    <EventUniqueID>74081-123418</EventUniqueID>
    <STATUS>active</STATUS>
    <AutoRecord>0</AutoRecord>
    <EnabledForIAV>0</EnabledForIAV>
    <MeetingIAVMode xsi:nil="true" />
    <PublishAutoRecordedVideo xsi:nil="true" />
    <Capacity xsi:nil="true" />
    <DirectLinkEnabled>0</DirectLinkEnabled>
    <DirectLinkRecordingEnabled xsi:nil="true" />
    <start>2022-07-11T08:30:00</start>
  </meeting>
  <meeting>
    <Confcode>ED22</Confcode>
    <EventName>A QuantCrit Investigation of Society’s Educational Debts in Stem</EventName>
    <EventSubName></EventSubName>
    <Poster></Poster>
    <EventNumber>MS6</EventNumber>
    <EventDate>Jul 11, 2022</EventDate>
    <EventStartTime>2022-07-11T17:00:00</EventStartTime>
    <EventEndTime>2022-07-11T17:25:00</EventEndTime>
    <EventFilter>ED22|Minisymposium</EventFilter>
    <EventLocation></EventLocation>
    <EventRoom>404</EventRoom>
    <FloorPlan></FloorPlan>
    <EVENT_FEE></EVENT_FEE>
    <EventKeywords>2800</EventKeywords>
    <EventChairs></EventChairs>
    <EventModerators></EventModerators>
    <EventSpeakers>Mollee Schulz</EventSpeakers>
    <EventSpeakerIDs>806415</EventSpeakerIDs>
    <EventSponsor></EventSponsor>
    <EventHandoutName>Abstract</EventHandoutName>
    <EventHandoutURL>http://meetings.siam.org/sess/dsp_talk.cfm?p=121551</EventHandoutURL>
    <EventDescription>This talk offers an example research project that is grounded in QuantCrit and followed the methods proposed in the prior two talks. The American Chemical Society holds supporting diverse student populations engaging in chemistry as a core value. We analyzed chemical concept inventory scores from 4,612 students across 12 institutions to determine what inequities in content knowledge existed before and after introductory college chemistry courses. We interpreted our findings from a Quantitative Critical (QuantCrit) perspective that framed inequities as educational debts that society owed students due to racism, sexism, or both. Results showed that society owed women and Black men large educational debts before and after instruction. Society’s educational debts before instruction were large enough that women and Black men’s average scores were lower than White men’s average pretest scores even after instruction. Society would have to provide opportunities equivalent to taking the course up to two and a half times to repay the largest educational debts. These findings show the scale of the inequities in the science education systems and highlight the need for reallocating resources and opportunities throughout the K-16 education system to mitigate, prevent, and repay society’s educational debts from sexism and racism.</EventDescription>
    <EventParent>74336-SESS</EventParent>
    <EventUniqueID>74336-121551</EventUniqueID>
    <STATUS>active</STATUS>
    <AutoRecord>0</AutoRecord>
    <EnabledForIAV>0</EnabledForIAV>
    <MeetingIAVMode xsi:nil="true" />
    <PublishAutoRecordedVideo xsi:nil="true" />
    <Capacity xsi:nil="true" />
    <DirectLinkEnabled>0</DirectLinkEnabled>
    <DirectLinkRecordingEnabled xsi:nil="true" />
    <start>2022-07-11T16:00:00</start>
  </meeting>
  <meeting>
    <Confcode>ED22</Confcode>
    <EventName>Historical Reflections on Teaching The Fundamental Theorems of Vector Calculus</EventName>
    <EventSubName></EventSubName>
    <Poster></Poster>
    <EventNumber>MS9</EventNumber>
    <EventDate>Jul 11, 2022</EventDate>
    <EventStartTime>2022-07-11T16:00:00</EventStartTime>
    <EventEndTime>2022-07-11T18:00:00</EventEndTime>
    <EventFilter>ED22|Minisymposium</EventFilter>
    <EventLocation></EventLocation>
    <EventRoom>401</EventRoom>
    <FloorPlan></FloorPlan>
    <EVENT_FEE></EVENT_FEE>
    <EventKeywords>300</EventKeywords>
    <EventChairs></EventChairs>
    <EventModerators></EventModerators>
    <EventSpeakers>Alan von Herrmann</EventSpeakers>
    <EventSpeakerIDs>805736</EventSpeakerIDs>
    <EventSponsor></EventSponsor>
    <EventHandoutName>Abstract</EventHandoutName>
    <EventHandoutURL>http://meetings.siam.org/sess/dsp_talk.cfm?p=120945</EventHandoutURL>
    <EventDescription>This talk explores some history of the fundamental theorems of vector calculus, namely, Green's Theorem, Stokes' Theorem, and the divergence theorem. The historical development informs the teaching of these theorems and establishing connections to applications. 

</EventDescription>
    <EventParent>74180-SESS</EventParent>
    <EventUniqueID>74180-120945</EventUniqueID>
    <STATUS>active</STATUS>
    <AutoRecord>0</AutoRecord>
    <EnabledForIAV>0</EnabledForIAV>
    <MeetingIAVMode xsi:nil="true" />
    <PublishAutoRecordedVideo xsi:nil="true" />
    <Capacity xsi:nil="true" />
    <DirectLinkEnabled>0</DirectLinkEnabled>
    <DirectLinkRecordingEnabled xsi:nil="true" />
    <start>2022-07-11T16:00:00</start>
  </meeting>
  <meeting>
    <Confcode>ED22</Confcode>
    <EventName>A Retrospective Look at MSRI’s 2021 Math and Racial Justice Workshop</EventName>
    <EventSubName></EventSubName>
    <Poster></Poster>
    <EventNumber>MS10</EventNumber>
    <EventDate>Jul 12, 2022</EventDate>
    <EventStartTime>2022-07-12T08:30:00</EventStartTime>
    <EventEndTime>2022-07-12T10:30:00</EventEndTime>
    <EventFilter>ED22|Minisymposium</EventFilter>
    <EventLocation></EventLocation>
    <EventRoom>406</EventRoom>
    <FloorPlan></FloorPlan>
    <EVENT_FEE></EVENT_FEE>
    <EventKeywords>2800</EventKeywords>
    <EventChairs></EventChairs>
    <EventModerators></EventModerators>
    <EventSpeakers>Ron Buckmire</EventSpeakers>
    <EventSpeakerIDs>48079</EventSpeakerIDs>
    <EventSponsor></EventSponsor>
    <EventHandoutName>Abstract</EventHandoutName>
    <EventHandoutURL>http://meetings.siam.org/sess/dsp_talk.cfm?p=120883</EventHandoutURL>
    <EventDescription>The Mathematical Sciences Research Institute (MSRI) hosted the inaugural [Online] Workshop on Mathematics and Racial Justice (\url{https://www.msri.org/workshops/1012}) over six days in June 2021. The workshop included sessions on Bias in Algorithms and Technology; Fair Division, Allocation, and Representation; Public Health Disparities; and Racial Inequities in Mathematics Education. In this talk we will present a retrospective look back at the 2021 workshop in order to share lessons learned, to highlight and amplify its successes and to look forward to future activities that build upon this event to advance racial equity in the mathematical sciences community.</EventDescription>
    <EventParent>74170-SESS</EventParent>
    <EventUniqueID>74170-120883</EventUniqueID>
    <STATUS>active</STATUS>
    <AutoRecord>0</AutoRecord>
    <EnabledForIAV>0</EnabledForIAV>
    <MeetingIAVMode xsi:nil="true" />
    <PublishAutoRecordedVideo xsi:nil="true" />
    <Capacity xsi:nil="true" />
    <DirectLinkEnabled>0</DirectLinkEnabled>
    <DirectLinkRecordingEnabled xsi:nil="true" />
    <start>2022-07-12T08:30:00</start>
  </meeting>
  <meeting>
    <Confcode>ED22</Confcode>
    <EventName>Deconstructing Whiteness and Bias in Applied Mathematics Classrooms</EventName>
    <EventSubName></EventSubName>
    <Poster></Poster>
    <EventNumber>MS10</EventNumber>
    <EventDate>Jul 12, 2022</EventDate>
    <EventStartTime>2022-07-12T08:30:00</EventStartTime>
    <EventEndTime>2022-07-12T10:30:00</EventEndTime>
    <EventFilter>ED22|Minisymposium</EventFilter>
    <EventLocation></EventLocation>
    <EventRoom>406</EventRoom>
    <FloorPlan></FloorPlan>
    <EVENT_FEE></EVENT_FEE>
    <EventKeywords>2800</EventKeywords>
    <EventChairs></EventChairs>
    <EventModerators></EventModerators>
    <EventSpeakers>Mario Banuelos</EventSpeakers>
    <EventSpeakerIDs>788318</EventSpeakerIDs>
    <EventSponsor></EventSponsor>
    <EventHandoutName>Abstract</EventHandoutName>
    <EventHandoutURL>http://meetings.siam.org/sess/dsp_talk.cfm?p=120886</EventHandoutURL>
    <EventDescription>The majority of applied mathematics and applied mathematics education involves some use of data. However, required courses in statistics or applied mathematics rarely focus on the ethical repercussions of using that data in a meaningful way. Inside the classroom, there is a growing need to discuss and address issues of how whiteness has influenced the development of mathematical education, models, and algorithms. By having students share their own experiences, connect the material on a personal level, and discussing the ethical considerations of presented content, we can begin to deconstruct whiteness and address bias in the mathematical content we teach as well as the data we use. This talk will primarily focus framing whiteness in applied mathematics classrooms and on practical approaches to incorporate examples, discussions, and assignments on addressing bias in data and creating a community in applied mathematics classrooms.</EventDescription>
    <EventParent>74170-SESS</EventParent>
    <EventUniqueID>74170-120886</EventUniqueID>
    <STATUS>active</STATUS>
    <AutoRecord>0</AutoRecord>
    <EnabledForIAV>0</EnabledForIAV>
    <MeetingIAVMode xsi:nil="true" />
    <PublishAutoRecordedVideo xsi:nil="true" />
    <Capacity xsi:nil="true" />
    <DirectLinkEnabled>0</DirectLinkEnabled>
    <DirectLinkRecordingEnabled xsi:nil="true" />
    <start>2022-07-12T08:30:00</start>
  </meeting>
  <meeting>
    <Confcode>ED22</Confcode>
    <EventName>The IUSE Project: Implementing Quantitative Biology Modules Across Institutions</EventName>
    <EventSubName></EventSubName>
    <Poster></Poster>
    <EventNumber>MS11</EventNumber>
    <EventDate>Jul 12, 2022</EventDate>
    <EventStartTime>2022-07-12T08:30:00</EventStartTime>
    <EventEndTime>2022-07-12T10:30:00</EventEndTime>
    <EventFilter>ED22|Minisymposium</EventFilter>
    <EventLocation></EventLocation>
    <EventRoom>405</EventRoom>
    <FloorPlan></FloorPlan>
    <EVENT_FEE></EVENT_FEE>
    <EventKeywords>2800</EventKeywords>
    <EventChairs></EventChairs>
    <EventModerators></EventModerators>
    <EventSpeakers>Sarah Leupen</EventSpeakers>
    <EventSpeakerIDs>805420</EventSpeakerIDs>
    <EventSponsor></EventSponsor>
    <EventHandoutName>Abstract</EventHandoutName>
    <EventHandoutURL>http://meetings.siam.org/sess/dsp_talk.cfm?p=120083</EventHandoutURL>
    <EventDescription>Calls for transforming biological curricula have spurred a flurry of activity in interdisciplinary STEM education, particularly quantitative biology. A previous HHMI-funded UMBC project developed competency-based modules to facilitate quantitative reasoning in biology courses. Increases in quantitative competencies resulted, but a discrepancy in achievement gains between direct entry and transfer students. To address this, UMBC joined with four community college partners to develop a consortium to facilitate quantitative module development in core biology courses and to facilitate large-scale implementation. Funded by an NSF IUSE grant, the consortium tracks student achievement with the intention of both mitigating the achievement gap between direct entry and transfer students, as well as understanding the effect of increased exposure to quantitative modules. Three years into the project, modules have been created, implemented and assessed across all five institutions and all four courses of the Biology core, creating a rich data set. Pre-post tests from multiple modules show significant gains in student understanding at the end of the module. We will also present data from student surveys about the modules and from a global assessment test given to students in their first course of the Biology core (at all institutions) and again to graduating seniors at UMBC. Finally, we will discuss lessons learned in this challenging, pandemic-straddling, multi-institutional project. 

</EventDescription>
    <EventParent>73886-SESS</EventParent>
    <EventUniqueID>73886-120083</EventUniqueID>
    <STATUS>active</STATUS>
    <AutoRecord>0</AutoRecord>
    <EnabledForIAV>0</EnabledForIAV>
    <MeetingIAVMode xsi:nil="true" />
    <PublishAutoRecordedVideo xsi:nil="true" />
    <Capacity xsi:nil="true" />
    <DirectLinkEnabled>0</DirectLinkEnabled>
    <DirectLinkRecordingEnabled xsi:nil="true" />
    <start>2022-07-12T08:30:00</start>
  </meeting>
  <meeting>
    <Confcode>ED22</Confcode>
    <EventName>What Does the Simiode Community of Practice Offer?</EventName>
    <EventSubName></EventSubName>
    <Poster></Poster>
    <EventNumber>MS14</EventNumber>
    <EventDate>Jul 12, 2022</EventDate>
    <EventStartTime>2022-07-12T08:30:00</EventStartTime>
    <EventEndTime>2022-07-12T10:30:00</EventEndTime>
    <EventFilter>ED22|Minisymposium</EventFilter>
    <EventLocation></EventLocation>
    <EventRoom>402</EventRoom>
    <FloorPlan></FloorPlan>
    <EVENT_FEE></EVENT_FEE>
    <EventKeywords>2800</EventKeywords>
    <EventChairs></EventChairs>
    <EventModerators></EventModerators>
    <EventSpeakers>Brian Winkel</EventSpeakers>
    <EventSpeakerIDs>773369</EventSpeakerIDs>
    <EventSponsor></EventSponsor>
    <EventHandoutName>Abstract</EventHandoutName>
    <EventHandoutURL>http://meetings.siam.org/sess/dsp_talk.cfm?p=121309</EventHandoutURL>
    <EventDescription>We introduce the SIMIODE (Systemic Initiative for Modeling Investigations and Opportunities with Differential Equations) community and its many features and offerings, first among them are Modeling Scenarios, teaching materials to permit faculty to support classroom endeavours in applying modeling to motivate teaching differential equations. We illustrate the offerings of SIMIODE and demonstrate the principles in several Modeling Scenarios.
</EventDescription>
    <EventParent>74292-SESS</EventParent>
    <EventUniqueID>74292-121309</EventUniqueID>
    <STATUS>active</STATUS>
    <AutoRecord>0</AutoRecord>
    <EnabledForIAV>0</EnabledForIAV>
    <MeetingIAVMode xsi:nil="true" />
    <PublishAutoRecordedVideo xsi:nil="true" />
    <Capacity xsi:nil="true" />
    <DirectLinkEnabled>0</DirectLinkEnabled>
    <DirectLinkRecordingEnabled xsi:nil="true" />
    <start>2022-07-12T08:30:00</start>
  </meeting>
  <meeting>
    <Confcode>ED22</Confcode>
    <EventName>Implementing SIMIODE Activities in Teaching Differential Equations</EventName>
    <EventSubName></EventSubName>
    <Poster></Poster>
    <EventNumber>MS14</EventNumber>
    <EventDate>Jul 12, 2022</EventDate>
    <EventStartTime>2022-07-12T08:30:00</EventStartTime>
    <EventEndTime>2022-07-12T10:30:00</EventEndTime>
    <EventFilter>ED22|Minisymposium</EventFilter>
    <EventLocation></EventLocation>
    <EventRoom>402</EventRoom>
    <FloorPlan></FloorPlan>
    <EVENT_FEE></EVENT_FEE>
    <EventKeywords>2800</EventKeywords>
    <EventChairs></EventChairs>
    <EventModerators></EventModerators>
    <EventSpeakers>Corban Harwood</EventSpeakers>
    <EventSpeakerIDs>783282</EventSpeakerIDs>
    <EventSponsor></EventSponsor>
    <EventHandoutName>Abstract</EventHandoutName>
    <EventHandoutURL>http://meetings.siam.org/sess/dsp_talk.cfm?p=121311</EventHandoutURL>
    <EventDescription>SIMIODE Modeling Scenarios and Technique Narratives, articles providing project activities and teaching guides, provide tangible connections to course content and can motivate students to learn at a deeper level. This talk focuses on the efficient implementation of two projects in a Differential Equations course from SIMIODE publications which develop and analyze mathematical models of a problem based upon known data and real-life situations. Logistical pitfalls and insights are highlighted as well as several key implementation resources. Student feedback demonstrates a positive correlation between the use of projects and an enhanced understanding of the course topics when logistical issues are reduced. Best practices learned over the years will be shared along with example student work on the projects.

</EventDescription>
    <EventParent>74292-SESS</EventParent>
    <EventUniqueID>74292-121311</EventUniqueID>
    <STATUS>active</STATUS>
    <AutoRecord>0</AutoRecord>
    <EnabledForIAV>0</EnabledForIAV>
    <MeetingIAVMode xsi:nil="true" />
    <PublishAutoRecordedVideo xsi:nil="true" />
    <Capacity xsi:nil="true" />
    <DirectLinkEnabled>0</DirectLinkEnabled>
    <DirectLinkRecordingEnabled xsi:nil="true" />
    <start>2022-07-12T08:30:00</start>
  </meeting>
  <meeting>
    <Confcode>ED22</Confcode>
    <EventName>Cultivating Inclusion Through Broader Engagement at SIAM Conferences (be@siam)</EventName>
    <EventSubName></EventSubName>
    <Poster></Poster>
    <EventNumber>MS15</EventNumber>
    <EventDate>Jul 12, 2022</EventDate>
    <EventStartTime>2022-07-12T16:00:00</EventStartTime>
    <EventEndTime>2022-07-12T18:00:00</EventEndTime>
    <EventFilter>ED22|Minisymposium</EventFilter>
    <EventLocation></EventLocation>
    <EventRoom>405</EventRoom>
    <FloorPlan></FloorPlan>
    <EVENT_FEE></EVENT_FEE>
    <EventKeywords>2800</EventKeywords>
    <EventChairs></EventChairs>
    <EventModerators></EventModerators>
    <EventSpeakers>Mary Ann Leung</EventSpeakers>
    <EventSpeakerIDs>721529</EventSpeakerIDs>
    <EventSponsor></EventSponsor>
    <EventHandoutName>Abstract</EventHandoutName>
    <EventHandoutURL>http://meetings.siam.org/sess/dsp_talk.cfm?p=120890</EventHandoutURL>
    <EventDescription>Racial equity in applied mathematics requires an understanding of the forces which have resulted in inequity as well as techniques to transform curriculum, policies, practices, and the community.  Inclusion is an essential ingredient in advancing racial equity in applied mathematics.  The Broader Engagement program at the SIAM Computational Science and Engineering conferences has been an effort to increase the participation of students and professionals from underrepresented groups in the society as well as catalyze the normalization of inclusion by engaging, educating, and including the broader community.  In this session, we will review the approach, components, and reflections from BE@CSE programs beginning in 2015.
</EventDescription>
    <EventParent>74171-SESS</EventParent>
    <EventUniqueID>74171-120890</EventUniqueID>
    <STATUS>active</STATUS>
    <AutoRecord>0</AutoRecord>
    <EnabledForIAV>0</EnabledForIAV>
    <MeetingIAVMode xsi:nil="true" />
    <PublishAutoRecordedVideo xsi:nil="true" />
    <Capacity xsi:nil="true" />
    <DirectLinkEnabled>0</DirectLinkEnabled>
    <DirectLinkRecordingEnabled xsi:nil="true" />
    <start>2022-07-12T16:00:00</start>
  </meeting>
  <meeting>
    <Confcode>ED22</Confcode>
    <EventName>Proof Comprehension: What Does It Mean to Understand a Proof and How Can This Understanding Be Measured?</EventName>
    <EventSubName></EventSubName>
    <Poster></Poster>
    <EventNumber>MS18</EventNumber>
    <EventDate>Jul 12, 2022</EventDate>
    <EventStartTime>2022-07-12T16:00:00</EventStartTime>
    <EventEndTime>2022-07-12T18:00:00</EventEndTime>
    <EventFilter>ED22|Minisymposium</EventFilter>
    <EventLocation></EventLocation>
    <EventRoom>402</EventRoom>
    <FloorPlan></FloorPlan>
    <EVENT_FEE></EVENT_FEE>
    <EventKeywords>2800</EventKeywords>
    <EventChairs></EventChairs>
    <EventModerators></EventModerators>
    <EventSpeakers>Keith Weber</EventSpeakers>
    <EventSpeakerIDs>805430</EventSpeakerIDs>
    <EventSponsor></EventSponsor>
    <EventHandoutName>Abstract</EventHandoutName>
    <EventHandoutURL>http://meetings.siam.org/sess/dsp_talk.cfm?p=120095</EventHandoutURL>
    <EventDescription>We first describe the development of a model of proof comprehension through interviews with mathematicians. We use this to highlight different ways in which a proof can be understood. We then describe the development and validation of proof comprehension tests. We argue that we have 12 item multiple choice proof comprehension tests that can validly and reliably measure students' ability to understand proofs. Finally, we use these instruments to show proof comprehension is predictive of students' academic performance in proof-oriented mathematics courses, even when factors such as math SATs and grades in prior mathematics courses are accounted for.
</EventDescription>
    <EventParent>73891-SESS</EventParent>
    <EventUniqueID>73891-120095</EventUniqueID>
    <STATUS>active</STATUS>
    <AutoRecord>0</AutoRecord>
    <EnabledForIAV>0</EnabledForIAV>
    <MeetingIAVMode xsi:nil="true" />
    <PublishAutoRecordedVideo xsi:nil="true" />
    <Capacity xsi:nil="true" />
    <DirectLinkEnabled>0</DirectLinkEnabled>
    <DirectLinkRecordingEnabled xsi:nil="true" />
    <start>2022-07-12T16:00:00</start>
  </meeting>
  <meeting>
    <Confcode>ED22</Confcode>
    <EventName>Teaching and Operationalizing Authentic Proof-Based Activity in the University Classroom</EventName>
    <EventSubName></EventSubName>
    <Poster></Poster>
    <EventNumber>MS18</EventNumber>
    <EventDate>Jul 12, 2022</EventDate>
    <EventStartTime>2022-07-12T16:00:00</EventStartTime>
    <EventEndTime>2022-07-12T18:00:00</EventEndTime>
    <EventFilter>ED22|Minisymposium</EventFilter>
    <EventLocation></EventLocation>
    <EventRoom>402</EventRoom>
    <FloorPlan></FloorPlan>
    <EVENT_FEE></EVENT_FEE>
    <EventKeywords>2800</EventKeywords>
    <EventChairs></EventChairs>
    <EventModerators></EventModerators>
    <EventSpeakers>Kathleen Melhuish</EventSpeakers>
    <EventSpeakerIDs>805432</EventSpeakerIDs>
    <EventSponsor></EventSponsor>
    <EventHandoutName>Abstract</EventHandoutName>
    <EventHandoutURL>http://meetings.siam.org/sess/dsp_talk.cfm?p=120098</EventHandoutURL>
    <EventDescription>Educators often advocate for students to engage in authentic mathematical activity. However, we have found that such activity has not yet been operationalized to allow for meaningful analysis of student activity in proof-based courses. As part of a larger research project, we developed the Authentic Mathematical Proof Activity (AMPA) framework to both operationalize the nature of this activity and to address the ways in which student activity may be more or less authentic. Leveraging the extant literature on how research mathematicians go about their work, we identify a set of tools and motives that characterize the reported proof-related activities. Further, we document classroom activity from an authentic-to-the-disciplinary perspective (accounting for the variety, complexity, and accuracy of tool use) and an authentic-to-the-student perspective (accounting for who has agency in generating tools, authority to evaluate contributions, and whose contributions are taken up). Using data from a design-based research project focused on undergraduate abstract algebra, we illustrate the utility of the AMPA framework. In particular, we share evidence of ways that students engage in authentic mathematical proof activity, as well as the ways that tensions between disciplinary and student authenticity shape activity.
</EventDescription>
    <EventParent>73891-SESS</EventParent>
    <EventUniqueID>73891-120098</EventUniqueID>
    <STATUS>active</STATUS>
    <AutoRecord>0</AutoRecord>
    <EnabledForIAV>0</EnabledForIAV>
    <MeetingIAVMode xsi:nil="true" />
    <PublishAutoRecordedVideo xsi:nil="true" />
    <Capacity xsi:nil="true" />
    <DirectLinkEnabled>0</DirectLinkEnabled>
    <DirectLinkRecordingEnabled xsi:nil="true" />
    <start>2022-07-12T16:00:00</start>
  </meeting>
  <meeting>
    <Confcode>ED22</Confcode>
    <EventName>Introduction to Comap’s Certificate in Modeling (CiM) Program for Educators – Part II of II</EventName>
    <EventSubName></EventSubName>
    <Poster></Poster>
    <EventNumber>MT2</EventNumber>
    <EventDate>Jul 11, 2022</EventDate>
    <EventStartTime>2022-07-11T16:00:00</EventStartTime>
    <EventEndTime>2022-07-11T18:00:00</EventEndTime>
    <EventFilter>ED22|Minitutorial</EventFilter>
    <EventLocation></EventLocation>
    <EventRoom>406</EventRoom>
    <FloorPlan></FloorPlan>
    <EVENT_FEE></EVENT_FEE>
    <EventKeywords></EventKeywords>
    <EventChairs></EventChairs>
    <EventModerators></EventModerators>
    <EventSpeakers>Michelle Isenhour</EventSpeakers>
    <EventSpeakerIDs>807334</EventSpeakerIDs>
    <EventSponsor></EventSponsor>
    <EventHandoutName>Abstract</EventHandoutName>
    <EventHandoutURL>http://meetings.siam.org/sess/dsp_talk.cfm?p=122693</EventHandoutURL>
    <EventDescription>During this workshop, we will introduce participants to the CiM program as well as the opportunity to obtain the Modeling Educator Certificate (MEC). Workshop participants will participate in two hour-long sessions where COMAP will expose participants to the material contained within the first two modules of the Modeling for Education course. During module 1, participants will trace a bit of history of educational practices from traditional/computational (#1-15 odd), to “word” problems, to applied problem solving, to “modeling problem.” After completing module 1, every participant will have a better understanding of the philosophy of teaching/learning and framework for applied problem solving and modeling. During module 2, participants will explore a Showcase of (Modeling) Examples to learn how to expose students to various fields, levels of solutions, and types of mathematics involved. In addition to being exposed to the course in-class activities, workshop participants will also experience some of the pre- and post-class activities planned as part of the program. Following the completion of module 2, the workshop will conclude with a discussion about the workshop experience and opportunity to obtain the modeling certificate.

	</EventDescription>
    <EventParent>74632-SESS</EventParent>
    <EventUniqueID>74632-122693</EventUniqueID>
    <STATUS>active</STATUS>
    <AutoRecord>0</AutoRecord>
    <EnabledForIAV>0</EnabledForIAV>
    <MeetingIAVMode xsi:nil="true" />
    <PublishAutoRecordedVideo xsi:nil="true" />
    <Capacity xsi:nil="true" />
    <DirectLinkEnabled>0</DirectLinkEnabled>
    <DirectLinkRecordingEnabled xsi:nil="true" />
    <start>2022-07-11T16:00:00</start>
  </meeting>
  <meeting>
    <Confcode>ED22</Confcode>
    <EventName>Introduction to Comap’s Certificate in Modeling (CiM) Program for Educators – Part II of II </EventName>
    <EventSubName></EventSubName>
    <Poster></Poster>
    <EventNumber>MT2</EventNumber>
    <EventDate>Jul 11, 2022</EventDate>
    <EventStartTime>2022-07-11T16:00:00</EventStartTime>
    <EventEndTime>2022-07-11T18:00:00</EventEndTime>
    <EventFilter>ED22|Minitutorial</EventFilter>
    <EventLocation></EventLocation>
    <EventRoom>406</EventRoom>
    <FloorPlan></FloorPlan>
    <EVENT_FEE></EVENT_FEE>
    <EventKeywords></EventKeywords>
    <EventChairs></EventChairs>
    <EventModerators></EventModerators>
    <EventSpeakers>Karl Schmitt</EventSpeakers>
    <EventSpeakerIDs>732230</EventSpeakerIDs>
    <EventSponsor></EventSponsor>
    <EventHandoutName>Abstract</EventHandoutName>
    <EventHandoutURL>http://meetings.siam.org/sess/dsp_talk.cfm?p=123504</EventHandoutURL>
    <EventDescription xsi:nil="true" />
    <EventParent>74632-SESS</EventParent>
    <EventUniqueID>74632-123504</EventUniqueID>
    <STATUS>active</STATUS>
    <AutoRecord>0</AutoRecord>
    <EnabledForIAV>0</EnabledForIAV>
    <MeetingIAVMode xsi:nil="true" />
    <PublishAutoRecordedVideo xsi:nil="true" />
    <Capacity xsi:nil="true" />
    <DirectLinkEnabled>0</DirectLinkEnabled>
    <DirectLinkRecordingEnabled xsi:nil="true" />
    <start>2022-07-11T16:00:00</start>
  </meeting>
  <meeting>
    <Confcode>ED22</Confcode>
    <EventName>Functional and Fourier Analysis Learning Trajectories for Engineering Mathematics Education</EventName>
    <EventSubName></EventSubName>
    <Poster></Poster>
    <EventNumber>CP1</EventNumber>
    <EventDate>Jul 11, 2022</EventDate>
    <EventStartTime>2022-07-11T09:10:00</EventStartTime>
    <EventEndTime>2022-07-11T09:25:00</EventEndTime>
    <EventFilter>ED22|Contributed</EventFilter>
    <EventLocation></EventLocation>
    <EventRoom>404</EventRoom>
    <FloorPlan></FloorPlan>
    <EVENT_FEE></EVENT_FEE>
    <EventKeywords></EventKeywords>
    <EventChairs></EventChairs>
    <EventModerators></EventModerators>
    <EventSpeakers>Celil Ekici</EventSpeakers>
    <EventSpeakerIDs>806682</EventSpeakerIDs>
    <EventSponsor></EventSponsor>
    <EventHandoutName>Abstract</EventHandoutName>
    <EventHandoutURL>http://meetings.siam.org/sess/dsp_talk.cfm?p=121783</EventHandoutURL>
    <EventDescription>Fourier and functional analysis are critical for engineering mathematics education with its diverse applications in control theory, signal analysis, electromagnetics, vibration, and acoustic. Learning trajectories are used here as a pedagogical tool to build bridges between mathematics and engineering courses. Towards building a scholarship of teaching and learning of applied mathematics for engineers for applied mathematics and engineering students, interdisciplinary faculty from applied Mathematics and Engineering collaboratively worked on development of Fourier and Functional Analysis ideas across mathematics and engineering courses. The design research, as described in Prediger, Gravemeijer, Confrey, (2015) and Streefland (1994) is conducted to explicate learning trajectories for Fourier and Functional Analysis to support local instructional practices. Using concept maps, the Fourier and Functional analysis learning trajectories are depicted as spanning across the following courses: Trigonometry, Calculus III, Complex Analysis, Ordinary Differential Equations, Linear Algebra, Control Theory, Signal Processing, Electromagnetics. Engineering and applied mathematics instructors reflected and articulated these pathways  from their disciplinary perspectives, highlighting the critical transitions such as the transition from subspace to inner product spaces in Linear Algebra, and Fourier transform with Maxwell’s equations in Electromagnetism in the frequency domain.  </EventDescription>
    <EventParent>74686-SESS</EventParent>
    <EventUniqueID>74686-121783</EventUniqueID>
    <STATUS>active</STATUS>
    <AutoRecord>0</AutoRecord>
    <EnabledForIAV>0</EnabledForIAV>
    <MeetingIAVMode xsi:nil="true" />
    <PublishAutoRecordedVideo xsi:nil="true" />
    <Capacity xsi:nil="true" />
    <DirectLinkEnabled>0</DirectLinkEnabled>
    <DirectLinkRecordingEnabled xsi:nil="true" />
    <start>2022-07-11T08:30:00</start>
  </meeting>
  <meeting>
    <Confcode>ED22</Confcode>
    <EventName>Applied Honors Calculus at Michigan</EventName>
    <EventSubName></EventSubName>
    <Poster></Poster>
    <EventNumber>CP2</EventNumber>
    <EventDate>Jul 12, 2022</EventDate>
    <EventStartTime>2022-07-12T17:40:00</EventStartTime>
    <EventEndTime>2022-07-12T17:55:00</EventEndTime>
    <EventFilter>ED22|Contributed</EventFilter>
    <EventLocation></EventLocation>
    <EventRoom>406</EventRoom>
    <FloorPlan></FloorPlan>
    <EVENT_FEE></EVENT_FEE>
    <EventKeywords></EventKeywords>
    <EventChairs></EventChairs>
    <EventModerators></EventModerators>
    <EventSpeakers>Robert Krasny</EventSpeakers>
    <EventSpeakerIDs>10328</EventSpeakerIDs>
    <EventSponsor></EventSponsor>
    <EventHandoutName>Abstract</EventHandoutName>
    <EventHandoutURL>http://meetings.siam.org/sess/dsp_talk.cfm?p=121501</EventHandoutURL>
    <EventDescription>Applied Honors Calculus (Math 156) at Michigan is a 2nd semester calculus course for STEM majors who took AP calculus in high school. The course started in 1994 in response to a request from the College of Engineering, and it emphasizes the science applications of calculus and math topics relevant to the students' subsequent STEM classes. This talk will describe the course and the teaching strategies that have been found to work well.

	</EventDescription>
    <EventParent>74689-SESS</EventParent>
    <EventUniqueID>74689-121501</EventUniqueID>
    <STATUS>active</STATUS>
    <AutoRecord>0</AutoRecord>
    <EnabledForIAV>0</EnabledForIAV>
    <MeetingIAVMode xsi:nil="true" />
    <PublishAutoRecordedVideo xsi:nil="true" />
    <Capacity xsi:nil="true" />
    <DirectLinkEnabled>0</DirectLinkEnabled>
    <DirectLinkRecordingEnabled xsi:nil="true" />
    <start>2022-07-12T16:00:00</start>
  </meeting>
  <meeting>
    <Confcode>ED22</Confcode>
    <EventName>Joint Plenary with the SIAM Annual Meeting AN22: Building Mathematical Communities of Students, Faculty, and the Public to Create Pathways from K-12 to Graduate Programs</EventName>
    <EventSubName></EventSubName>
    <Poster></Poster>
    <EventNumber>JP1</EventNumber>
    <EventDate>Jul 11, 2022</EventDate>
    <EventStartTime>2022-07-11T11:45:00</EventStartTime>
    <EventEndTime>2022-07-11T12:30:00</EventEndTime>
    <EventFilter>ED22|Invited Speaker</EventFilter>
    <EventLocation></EventLocation>
    <EventRoom>Spirit of Pittsburgh A - 3rd Floor</EventRoom>
    <FloorPlan></FloorPlan>
    <EVENT_FEE></EVENT_FEE>
    <EventKeywords></EventKeywords>
    <EventChairs></EventChairs>
    <EventModerators></EventModerators>
    <EventSpeakers>Cristina Villalobos</EventSpeakers>
    <EventSpeakerIDs>778806</EventSpeakerIDs>
    <EventSponsor></EventSponsor>
    <EventHandoutName>Abstract</EventHandoutName>
    <EventHandoutURL>http://meetings.siam.org/sess/dsp_talk.cfm?p=119914</EventHandoutURL>
    <EventDescription>Given the large percentage of Latino and first-generation college students in the Rio Grande Valley, the University of Texas Rio Grande Valley serves as a vital pipeline for preparing the nation’s leadership in STEM disciplines from underrepresented groups.  In this talk, we describe efforts to build communities in mathematics involving public schools, universities, students and faculty, and the UTRGV Center of Excellence in STEM Education (C-STEM).  We will discuss how we have built communities of undergraduates and K-12 students through summer camps and mobile STEM labs through the C-STEM.  Additionally, we will discuss how communities of faculty through university collaborations have created pathways to graduate programs via REUs, team-teaching of advanced math courses and boot camps aimed at preparing students to effectively apply for graduate programs. At the departmental level, we will describe how we have built communities within our student population through collaborative problem-solving sessions. A crucial component in many of these programs is the inclusion of professional development workshops to guide students along the path to success in graduate school.
	

</EventDescription>
    <EventParent>73757-SESS</EventParent>
    <EventUniqueID>73757-119914</EventUniqueID>
    <STATUS>active</STATUS>
    <AutoRecord>0</AutoRecord>
    <EnabledForIAV>0</EnabledForIAV>
    <MeetingIAVMode xsi:nil="true" />
    <PublishAutoRecordedVideo xsi:nil="true" />
    <Capacity xsi:nil="true" />
    <DirectLinkEnabled>0</DirectLinkEnabled>
    <DirectLinkRecordingEnabled xsi:nil="true" />
    <start>2022-07-11T11:45:00</start>
  </meeting>
  <meeting>
    <Confcode>ED22</Confcode>
    <EventName>The Graduate Student Mathematical Modeling Camp</EventName>
    <EventSubName></EventSubName>
    <Poster></Poster>
    <EventNumber>MS1</EventNumber>
    <EventDate>Jul 11, 2022</EventDate>
    <EventStartTime>2022-07-11T08:30:00</EventStartTime>
    <EventEndTime>2022-07-11T10:30:00</EventEndTime>
    <EventFilter>ED22|Minisymposium</EventFilter>
    <EventLocation></EventLocation>
    <EventRoom>406</EventRoom>
    <FloorPlan></FloorPlan>
    <EVENT_FEE></EVENT_FEE>
    <EventKeywords>2800</EventKeywords>
    <EventChairs></EventChairs>
    <EventModerators></EventModerators>
    <EventSpeakers>David Edwards</EventSpeakers>
    <EventSpeakerIDs>31568</EventSpeakerIDs>
    <EventSponsor></EventSponsor>
    <EventHandoutName>Abstract</EventHandoutName>
    <EventHandoutURL>http://meetings.siam.org/sess/dsp_talk.cfm?p=121101</EventHandoutURL>
    <EventDescription>In recent years, the need for increased opportunities for training graduate students in industrial mathematics has become clear.  Much of this training is extracurricular, taking place at summer workshops.  We present results from the first half of a two-part approach.  At the three-day Graduate Student Mathematical Modeling Camp (GSMMC), students work together in teams under faculty guidance on interdisciplinary problems typically inspired by industrial applications.  The problems are carefully chosen to promote a rich set of analytical and numerical problem-solving skills.  ``Soft skills" are promoted via lively discussions about the solution process, as well as oral and written presentations.  After the Camp, students travel to the Mathematical Problems in Industry Workshop (MPI).  There, they use their new-found skills to join teams of faculty, postdocs, and industrial scientists to solve open-ended, real-world problems.  We will discuss our successful outcomes, as well as the challenges of administering such a program, both before and during the pandemic.
</EventDescription>
    <EventParent>74229-SESS</EventParent>
    <EventUniqueID>74229-121101</EventUniqueID>
    <STATUS>active</STATUS>
    <AutoRecord>0</AutoRecord>
    <EnabledForIAV>0</EnabledForIAV>
    <MeetingIAVMode xsi:nil="true" />
    <PublishAutoRecordedVideo xsi:nil="true" />
    <Capacity xsi:nil="true" />
    <DirectLinkEnabled>0</DirectLinkEnabled>
    <DirectLinkRecordingEnabled xsi:nil="true" />
    <start>2022-07-11T08:30:00</start>
  </meeting>
  <meeting>
    <Confcode>ED22</Confcode>
    <EventName>Undergraduate Experiences and Training with High-Need K12 Students</EventName>
    <EventSubName></EventSubName>
    <Poster></Poster>
    <EventNumber>MS3</EventNumber>
    <EventDate>Jul 11, 2022</EventDate>
    <EventStartTime>2022-07-11T09:30:00</EventStartTime>
    <EventEndTime>2022-07-11T09:55:00</EventEndTime>
    <EventFilter>ED22|Minisymposium</EventFilter>
    <EventLocation></EventLocation>
    <EventRoom>402</EventRoom>
    <FloorPlan></FloorPlan>
    <EVENT_FEE></EVENT_FEE>
    <EventKeywords>2800</EventKeywords>
    <EventChairs></EventChairs>
    <EventModerators></EventModerators>
    <EventSpeakers>Corey Ryder</EventSpeakers>
    <EventSpeakerIDs>805523</EventSpeakerIDs>
    <EventSponsor></EventSponsor>
    <EventHandoutName>Abstract</EventHandoutName>
    <EventHandoutURL>http://meetings.siam.org/sess/dsp_talk.cfm?p=120312</EventHandoutURL>
    <EventDescription>Much like any profession, good educators require both formal education and firsthand experiences with teaching to grow to their full potential. Through experiences in formal settings and more informal work with students, educators are better able to build their confidence, learn better practices, and develop a strength in connecting with their students. The Noyce program provides participants with both aspects: a strong understanding of equity and best teaching practices in high-need settings as well as a plethora of opportunities to work with middle and high-school level students. A previous student and Noyce scholar describes how the program helped to shape his current mathematics teaching practices and how these experiences with multiple levels of education built the foundation of his teaching practices. 
</EventDescription>
    <EventParent>73964-SESS</EventParent>
    <EventUniqueID>73964-120312</EventUniqueID>
    <STATUS>active</STATUS>
    <AutoRecord>0</AutoRecord>
    <EnabledForIAV>0</EnabledForIAV>
    <MeetingIAVMode xsi:nil="true" />
    <PublishAutoRecordedVideo xsi:nil="true" />
    <Capacity xsi:nil="true" />
    <DirectLinkEnabled>0</DirectLinkEnabled>
    <DirectLinkRecordingEnabled xsi:nil="true" />
    <start>2022-07-11T08:30:00</start>
  </meeting>
  <meeting>
    <Confcode>ED22</Confcode>
    <EventName>Cultural Explorations and Experiences: Immersive Experiences to Better Serve a Diverse Population of Students</EventName>
    <EventSubName></EventSubName>
    <Poster></Poster>
    <EventNumber>MS3</EventNumber>
    <EventDate>Jul 11, 2022</EventDate>
    <EventStartTime>2022-07-11T10:00:00</EventStartTime>
    <EventEndTime>2022-07-11T10:25:00</EventEndTime>
    <EventFilter>ED22|Minisymposium</EventFilter>
    <EventLocation></EventLocation>
    <EventRoom>402</EventRoom>
    <FloorPlan></FloorPlan>
    <EVENT_FEE></EVENT_FEE>
    <EventKeywords>2800</EventKeywords>
    <EventChairs></EventChairs>
    <EventModerators></EventModerators>
    <EventSpeakers>Natalie Valla</EventSpeakers>
    <EventSpeakerIDs>805836</EventSpeakerIDs>
    <EventSponsor></EventSponsor>
    <EventHandoutName>Abstract</EventHandoutName>
    <EventHandoutURL>http://meetings.siam.org/sess/dsp_talk.cfm?p=120313</EventHandoutURL>
    <EventDescription>A recent Clarkson graduate shares her experience participating in the Noyce program while completing her MAT in secondary math education. She describes how the Noyce program enhances a STEM student’s experience in the MAT program by providing real opportunities to understand the benefit of working in a high-needs district and build the competency to do so. She shares how meeting with veteran teachers in both urban and rural high-needs districts allows students to learn the challenges and rewards of working in both settings, providing insight into which environment would be best suited for each individual. In addition she shares how the Noyce program builds a community of graduates and faculty that support each other through the graduates’ year-long student teaching experiences, action research projects, the job search process, and even current teaching positions. It is these experiences collectively that build the graduates competence to work in a high-needs district and ultimately supports them in succeeding as an educator in any setting. 
</EventDescription>
    <EventParent>73964-SESS</EventParent>
    <EventUniqueID>73964-120313</EventUniqueID>
    <STATUS>active</STATUS>
    <AutoRecord>0</AutoRecord>
    <EnabledForIAV>0</EnabledForIAV>
    <MeetingIAVMode xsi:nil="true" />
    <PublishAutoRecordedVideo xsi:nil="true" />
    <Capacity xsi:nil="true" />
    <DirectLinkEnabled>0</DirectLinkEnabled>
    <DirectLinkRecordingEnabled xsi:nil="true" />
    <start>2022-07-11T08:30:00</start>
  </meeting>
  <meeting>
    <Confcode>ED22</Confcode>
    <EventName>Mathematics Education as a Mathematician’s Research Discipline</EventName>
    <EventSubName></EventSubName>
    <Poster></Poster>
    <EventNumber>MS8</EventNumber>
    <EventDate>Jul 11, 2022</EventDate>
    <EventStartTime>2022-07-11T16:00:00</EventStartTime>
    <EventEndTime>2022-07-11T18:00:00</EventEndTime>
    <EventFilter>ED22|Minisymposium</EventFilter>
    <EventLocation></EventLocation>
    <EventRoom>402</EventRoom>
    <FloorPlan></FloorPlan>
    <EVENT_FEE></EVENT_FEE>
    <EventKeywords>3000</EventKeywords>
    <EventChairs></EventChairs>
    <EventModerators></EventModerators>
    <EventSpeakers>Ricardo Cortez</EventSpeakers>
    <EventSpeakerIDs>702229</EventSpeakerIDs>
    <EventSponsor></EventSponsor>
    <EventHandoutName>Abstract</EventHandoutName>
    <EventHandoutURL>http://meetings.siam.org/sess/dsp_talk.cfm?p=121018</EventHandoutURL>
    <EventDescription>Applied mathematicians often participate in collaborative projects with investigators from disciplines close to mathematics as well as more distant disciplines such as medicine and social sciences. In some cases the collaborators may be experimentalists or field workers who provide a complementary and synergistic approach to the mathematics. Mathematicians who are involved in the teaching and learning of mathematics at the university level develop effective teaching practices through experience.  These experiences are a starting point (akin to a conjecture) that can be assessed through research studies that take into account students’ cognitive development, learning environments, social contexts and other factors in which mathematics educators have expertise that mathematicians typically do not. It pays off to view mathematics education as any other discipline sufficiently distant from mathematics that collaborative partnerships are necessary in order to have broad impact beyond anecdotal evidence of effective teaching. We describe collaborative projects designed to inform teacher preparation programs on ways to include mathematical modeling in their curriculum.
</EventDescription>
    <EventParent>74198-SESS</EventParent>
    <EventUniqueID>74198-121018</EventUniqueID>
    <STATUS>active</STATUS>
    <AutoRecord>0</AutoRecord>
    <EnabledForIAV>0</EnabledForIAV>
    <MeetingIAVMode xsi:nil="true" />
    <PublishAutoRecordedVideo xsi:nil="true" />
    <Capacity xsi:nil="true" />
    <DirectLinkEnabled>0</DirectLinkEnabled>
    <DirectLinkRecordingEnabled xsi:nil="true" />
    <start>2022-07-11T16:00:00</start>
  </meeting>
  <meeting>
    <Confcode>ED22</Confcode>
    <EventName>Fourier's Heat Equation: Miniprojects for a Course in Differential Equations</EventName>
    <EventSubName></EventSubName>
    <Poster></Poster>
    <EventNumber>MS9</EventNumber>
    <EventDate>Jul 11, 2022</EventDate>
    <EventStartTime>2022-07-11T16:00:00</EventStartTime>
    <EventEndTime>2022-07-11T18:00:00</EventEndTime>
    <EventFilter>ED22|Minisymposium</EventFilter>
    <EventLocation></EventLocation>
    <EventRoom>401</EventRoom>
    <FloorPlan></FloorPlan>
    <EVENT_FEE></EVENT_FEE>
    <EventKeywords>300</EventKeywords>
    <EventChairs></EventChairs>
    <EventModerators></EventModerators>
    <EventSpeakers>Kenneth Monks</EventSpeakers>
    <EventSpeakerIDs>805735</EventSpeakerIDs>
    <EventSponsor></EventSponsor>
    <EventHandoutName>Abstract</EventHandoutName>
    <EventHandoutURL>http://meetings.siam.org/sess/dsp_talk.cfm?p=120944</EventHandoutURL>
    <EventDescription>It is often said that Joseph Fourier gave birth to modern climate science. His 1827 paper ``M´emoire sur les Temp´eratures du Globe Terrestre et des Espaces Plan´etaires" (translated to English as ``On
the Temperatures of the Terrestrial Sphere and Interplanetary Space" in [Pierrehumbert, 2004]) contained influential observations concerning climate and energy.  Its analysis was based on mathematical results, establishing the diffusion equation, in his earlier ``Analytical Theory of Heat."  We present a historically based project for a course in differential equations [Monks, K. M., Fourier's Heat Equation and the Birth of Modern Climate Science, 2021. Differential Equations. 5. https://digitalcommons.ursinus.edu/triumphs\_differ/5].  The goal of the project is to give the reader an insight into the techniques Fourier
employed in his work in climate, as it has become the basis of modern thermodynamics and has been enormously consequential in mathematics.  
</EventDescription>
    <EventParent>74180-SESS</EventParent>
    <EventUniqueID>74180-120944</EventUniqueID>
    <STATUS>active</STATUS>
    <AutoRecord>0</AutoRecord>
    <EnabledForIAV>0</EnabledForIAV>
    <MeetingIAVMode xsi:nil="true" />
    <PublishAutoRecordedVideo xsi:nil="true" />
    <Capacity xsi:nil="true" />
    <DirectLinkEnabled>0</DirectLinkEnabled>
    <DirectLinkRecordingEnabled xsi:nil="true" />
    <start>2022-07-11T16:00:00</start>
  </meeting>
  <meeting>
    <Confcode>ED22</Confcode>
    <EventName>Educational Frameworks for Engaging the Next Generation Workforce at the Interface of Mathematics and Biology</EventName>
    <EventSubName></EventSubName>
    <Poster></Poster>
    <EventNumber>MS11</EventNumber>
    <EventDate>Jul 12, 2022</EventDate>
    <EventStartTime>2022-07-12T08:30:00</EventStartTime>
    <EventEndTime>2022-07-12T10:30:00</EventEndTime>
    <EventFilter>ED22|Minisymposium</EventFilter>
    <EventLocation></EventLocation>
    <EventRoom>405</EventRoom>
    <FloorPlan></FloorPlan>
    <EVENT_FEE></EVENT_FEE>
    <EventKeywords>2800</EventKeywords>
    <EventChairs></EventChairs>
    <EventModerators></EventModerators>
    <EventSpeakers>Padhu Seshaiyer</EventSpeakers>
    <EventSpeakerIDs>733366</EventSpeakerIDs>
    <EventSponsor></EventSponsor>
    <EventHandoutName>Abstract</EventHandoutName>
    <EventHandoutURL>http://meetings.siam.org/sess/dsp_talk.cfm?p=120081</EventHandoutURL>
    <EventDescription>In this talk, we discuss some novel educational frameworks including experiential learning, inquiry-based learning, challenge based learning and interdisciplinary problem-based learning that provide the opportunity to engage students to represent, understand, analyze and solve real world problems at the interface of mathematics and biology. These approaches can help students to become life-long learners going beyond a content-based education in mathematical biology to also include a competency-based training. The talk will present examples of authentic tasks that can help to incorporate a shared collaborative experience with innovative pedagogical practices to advance teaching and learning. The session will also introduce participants to potential funding opportunities available at the interface of mathematics and biology.</EventDescription>
    <EventParent>73886-SESS</EventParent>
    <EventUniqueID>73886-120081</EventUniqueID>
    <STATUS>active</STATUS>
    <AutoRecord>0</AutoRecord>
    <EnabledForIAV>0</EnabledForIAV>
    <MeetingIAVMode xsi:nil="true" />
    <PublishAutoRecordedVideo xsi:nil="true" />
    <Capacity xsi:nil="true" />
    <DirectLinkEnabled>0</DirectLinkEnabled>
    <DirectLinkRecordingEnabled xsi:nil="true" />
    <start>2022-07-12T08:30:00</start>
  </meeting>
  <meeting>
    <Confcode>ED22</Confcode>
    <EventName>A Case Study on Undergraduate Math Research That Evolved into Entrepreneurship</EventName>
    <EventSubName></EventSubName>
    <Poster></Poster>
    <EventNumber>MS12</EventNumber>
    <EventDate>Jul 12, 2022</EventDate>
    <EventStartTime>2022-07-12T08:30:00</EventStartTime>
    <EventEndTime>2022-07-12T10:30:00</EventEndTime>
    <EventFilter>ED22|Minisymposium</EventFilter>
    <EventLocation></EventLocation>
    <EventRoom>404</EventRoom>
    <FloorPlan></FloorPlan>
    <EVENT_FEE></EVENT_FEE>
    <EventKeywords>2800</EventKeywords>
    <EventChairs></EventChairs>
    <EventModerators></EventModerators>
    <EventSpeakers>Tony Harkin</EventSpeakers>
    <EventSpeakerIDs>724456</EventSpeakerIDs>
    <EventSponsor></EventSponsor>
    <EventHandoutName>Abstract</EventHandoutName>
    <EventHandoutURL>http://meetings.siam.org/sess/dsp_talk.cfm?p=120299</EventHandoutURL>
    <EventDescription xsi:nil="true" />
    <EventParent>73860-SESS</EventParent>
    <EventUniqueID>73860-120299</EventUniqueID>
    <STATUS>active</STATUS>
    <AutoRecord>0</AutoRecord>
    <EnabledForIAV>0</EnabledForIAV>
    <MeetingIAVMode xsi:nil="true" />
    <PublishAutoRecordedVideo xsi:nil="true" />
    <Capacity xsi:nil="true" />
    <DirectLinkEnabled>0</DirectLinkEnabled>
    <DirectLinkRecordingEnabled xsi:nil="true" />
    <start>2022-07-12T08:30:00</start>
  </meeting>
  <meeting>
    <Confcode>ED22</Confcode>
    <EventName>Addressing Academic Status via Authentic Mathematical Modeling Tasks</EventName>
    <EventSubName></EventSubName>
    <Poster></Poster>
    <EventNumber>MS13</EventNumber>
    <EventDate>Jul 12, 2022</EventDate>
    <EventStartTime>2022-07-12T08:30:00</EventStartTime>
    <EventEndTime>2022-07-12T10:30:00</EventEndTime>
    <EventFilter>ED22|Minisymposium</EventFilter>
    <EventLocation></EventLocation>
    <EventRoom>403</EventRoom>
    <FloorPlan></FloorPlan>
    <EVENT_FEE></EVENT_FEE>
    <EventKeywords>3000</EventKeywords>
    <EventChairs></EventChairs>
    <EventModerators></EventModerators>
    <EventSpeakers>Amy Bennett</EventSpeakers>
    <EventSpeakerIDs>805744</EventSpeakerIDs>
    <EventSponsor></EventSponsor>
    <EventHandoutName>Abstract</EventHandoutName>
    <EventHandoutURL>http://meetings.siam.org/sess/dsp_talk.cfm?p=120981</EventHandoutURL>
    <EventDescription>Mathematical modeling is a process for describing the world with mathematics, as well as a practice for learning mathematics in the K-12 classroom. In this study, I implemented modeling materials from the MODULE(S)${}^2$ Project in a senior-level content course for secondary mathematics pre-service teachers. The diversity of contexts and math concepts in the modeling tasks led to collaborative instructional practices that highlighted students' mathematical strengths and created an equitable learning environment. In particular, the authenticity of the tasks and creativity of projects allowed students to draw on their funds of knowledge and mathematical knowledge bases to decrease issues of academic status. In this presentation, I will share examples of student work to illustrate the benefits of incorporating modeling tasks in undergraduate curricula for mathematics teacher preparation.


</EventDescription>
    <EventParent>74199-SESS</EventParent>
    <EventUniqueID>74199-120981</EventUniqueID>
    <STATUS>active</STATUS>
    <AutoRecord>0</AutoRecord>
    <EnabledForIAV>0</EnabledForIAV>
    <MeetingIAVMode xsi:nil="true" />
    <PublishAutoRecordedVideo xsi:nil="true" />
    <Capacity xsi:nil="true" />
    <DirectLinkEnabled>0</DirectLinkEnabled>
    <DirectLinkRecordingEnabled xsi:nil="true" />
    <start>2022-07-12T08:30:00</start>
  </meeting>
  <meeting>
    <Confcode>ED22</Confcode>
    <EventName>Using Place-Based Education in Precalculus</EventName>
    <EventSubName></EventSubName>
    <Poster></Poster>
    <EventNumber>MS15</EventNumber>
    <EventDate>Jul 12, 2022</EventDate>
    <EventStartTime>2022-07-12T16:00:00</EventStartTime>
    <EventEndTime>2022-07-12T18:00:00</EventEndTime>
    <EventFilter>ED22|Minisymposium</EventFilter>
    <EventLocation></EventLocation>
    <EventRoom>405</EventRoom>
    <FloorPlan></FloorPlan>
    <EVENT_FEE></EVENT_FEE>
    <EventKeywords>2800</EventKeywords>
    <EventChairs></EventChairs>
    <EventModerators></EventModerators>
    <EventSpeakers>Kamuela Yong</EventSpeakers>
    <EventSpeakerIDs>778808</EventSpeakerIDs>
    <EventSponsor></EventSponsor>
    <EventHandoutName>Abstract</EventHandoutName>
    <EventHandoutURL>http://meetings.siam.org/sess/dsp_talk.cfm?p=120889</EventHandoutURL>
    <EventDescription>Indigenous cultures have been using mathematics in their lives for generations. In this talk, we present methods of using place-based examples in a precalculus classroom using Native Hawaiian culture. Through these examples, we hope to increase student participation in the classroom from both Indigenous and non-Indigenous students as well as spread awareness of various cultures.</EventDescription>
    <EventParent>74171-SESS</EventParent>
    <EventUniqueID>74171-120889</EventUniqueID>
    <STATUS>active</STATUS>
    <AutoRecord>0</AutoRecord>
    <EnabledForIAV>0</EnabledForIAV>
    <MeetingIAVMode xsi:nil="true" />
    <PublishAutoRecordedVideo xsi:nil="true" />
    <Capacity xsi:nil="true" />
    <DirectLinkEnabled>0</DirectLinkEnabled>
    <DirectLinkRecordingEnabled xsi:nil="true" />
    <start>2022-07-12T16:00:00</start>
  </meeting>
  <meeting>
    <Confcode>ED22</Confcode>
    <EventName>2022 SIAM Annual Meeting (AN22): AWM-SIAM Sonia Kovalevsky Lecture - Anne Greenbaum, University of Washington, U.S.</EventName>
    <EventSubName></EventSubName>
    <Poster></Poster>
    <EventNumber>CB</EventNumber>
    <EventDate>Jul 11, 2022</EventDate>
    <EventStartTime>2022-07-11T14:45:00</EventStartTime>
    <EventEndTime>2022-07-11T15:30:00</EventEndTime>
    <EventFilter>ED22|</EventFilter>
    <EventLocation></EventLocation>
    <EventRoom>Spirit of Pittsburgh A - 3rd Floor</EventRoom>
    <FloorPlan></FloorPlan>
    <EVENT_FEE></EVENT_FEE>
    <EventKeywords></EventKeywords>
    <EventChairs xsi:nil="true" />
    <EventModerators></EventModerators>
    <EventSpeakers></EventSpeakers>
    <EventSpeakerIDs xsi:nil="true" />
    <EventSponsor></EventSponsor>
    <EventHandoutName></EventHandoutName>
    <EventHandoutURL></EventHandoutURL>
    <EventDescription>&lt;a href="https://meetings.siam.org/sess/dsp_programsess.cfm?
SESSIONCODE=74977"&gt;Click Here for Details&lt;/a&gt;
</EventDescription>
    <EventParent></EventParent>
    <EventUniqueID>74752-SESS</EventUniqueID>
    <STATUS>active</STATUS>
    <AutoRecord>0</AutoRecord>
    <EnabledForIAV>0</EnabledForIAV>
    <MeetingIAVMode xsi:nil="true" />
    <PublishAutoRecordedVideo xsi:nil="true" />
    <Capacity xsi:nil="true" />
    <DirectLinkEnabled xsi:nil="true" />
    <DirectLinkRecordingEnabled xsi:nil="true" />
    <start>2022-07-11T14:45:00</start>
  </meeting>
  <meeting>
    <Confcode>ED22</Confcode>
    <EventName>2022 SIAM Annual Meeting (AN22): Fellows Reception</EventName>
    <EventSubName></EventSubName>
    <Poster></Poster>
    <EventNumber>CB</EventNumber>
    <EventDate>Jul 12, 2022</EventDate>
    <EventStartTime>2022-07-12T19:45:00</EventStartTime>
    <EventEndTime>2022-07-12T20:45:00</EventEndTime>
    <EventFilter>ED22|</EventFilter>
    <EventLocation></EventLocation>
    <EventRoom>South Terrace - 3rd Floor</EventRoom>
    <FloorPlan></FloorPlan>
    <EVENT_FEE></EVENT_FEE>
    <EventKeywords></EventKeywords>
    <EventChairs xsi:nil="true" />
    <EventModerators></EventModerators>
    <EventSpeakers></EventSpeakers>
    <EventSpeakerIDs xsi:nil="true" />
    <EventSponsor></EventSponsor>
    <EventHandoutName></EventHandoutName>
    <EventHandoutURL></EventHandoutURL>
    <EventDescription></EventDescription>
    <EventParent></EventParent>
    <EventUniqueID>74766-SESS</EventUniqueID>
    <STATUS>active</STATUS>
    <AutoRecord>0</AutoRecord>
    <EnabledForIAV>0</EnabledForIAV>
    <MeetingIAVMode xsi:nil="true" />
    <PublishAutoRecordedVideo xsi:nil="true" />
    <Capacity xsi:nil="true" />
    <DirectLinkEnabled xsi:nil="true" />
    <DirectLinkRecordingEnabled xsi:nil="true" />
    <start>2022-07-12T19:45:00</start>
  </meeting>
  <meeting>
    <Confcode>ED22</Confcode>
    <EventName>2022 SIAM Annual Meeting (AN22): Graduate Student and Industry Reception</EventName>
    <EventSubName></EventSubName>
    <Poster></Poster>
    <EventNumber>CB</EventNumber>
    <EventDate>Jul 11, 2022</EventDate>
    <EventStartTime>2022-07-11T19:15:00</EventStartTime>
    <EventEndTime>2022-07-11T21:15:00</EventEndTime>
    <EventFilter>ED22|</EventFilter>
    <EventLocation></EventLocation>
    <EventRoom>Allegheny Overlook - 3rd Floor</EventRoom>
    <FloorPlan></FloorPlan>
    <EVENT_FEE></EVENT_FEE>
    <EventKeywords></EventKeywords>
    <EventChairs xsi:nil="true" />
    <EventModerators></EventModerators>
    <EventSpeakers></EventSpeakers>
    <EventSpeakerIDs xsi:nil="true" />
    <EventSponsor></EventSponsor>
    <EventHandoutName></EventHandoutName>
    <EventHandoutURL></EventHandoutURL>
    <EventDescription></EventDescription>
    <EventParent></EventParent>
    <EventUniqueID>74755-SESS</EventUniqueID>
    <STATUS>active</STATUS>
    <AutoRecord>0</AutoRecord>
    <EnabledForIAV>0</EnabledForIAV>
    <MeetingIAVMode xsi:nil="true" />
    <PublishAutoRecordedVideo xsi:nil="true" />
    <Capacity xsi:nil="true" />
    <DirectLinkEnabled xsi:nil="true" />
    <DirectLinkRecordingEnabled xsi:nil="true" />
    <start>2022-07-11T19:15:00</start>
  </meeting>
  <meeting>
    <Confcode>ED22</Confcode>
    <EventName>2022 SIAM Annual Meeting (AN22): Industry Panel</EventName>
    <EventSubName></EventSubName>
    <Poster></Poster>
    <EventNumber>CB</EventNumber>
    <EventDate>Jul 11, 2022</EventDate>
    <EventStartTime>2022-07-11T18:15:00</EventStartTime>
    <EventEndTime>2022-07-11T19:15:00</EventEndTime>
    <EventFilter>ED22|</EventFilter>
    <EventLocation></EventLocation>
    <EventRoom>Spirit of Pittsburgh A - 3rd Floor</EventRoom>
    <FloorPlan></FloorPlan>
    <EVENT_FEE></EVENT_FEE>
    <EventKeywords></EventKeywords>
    <EventChairs xsi:nil="true" />
    <EventModerators></EventModerators>
    <EventSpeakers></EventSpeakers>
    <EventSpeakerIDs xsi:nil="true" />
    <EventSponsor></EventSponsor>
    <EventHandoutName></EventHandoutName>
    <EventHandoutURL></EventHandoutURL>
    <EventDescription></EventDescription>
    <EventParent></EventParent>
    <EventUniqueID>74754-SESS</EventUniqueID>
    <STATUS>active</STATUS>
    <AutoRecord>0</AutoRecord>
    <EnabledForIAV>0</EnabledForIAV>
    <MeetingIAVMode xsi:nil="true" />
    <PublishAutoRecordedVideo xsi:nil="true" />
    <Capacity xsi:nil="true" />
    <DirectLinkEnabled xsi:nil="true" />
    <DirectLinkRecordingEnabled xsi:nil="true" />
    <start>2022-07-11T18:15:00</start>
  </meeting>
  <meeting>
    <Confcode>ED22</Confcode>
    <EventName>2022 SIAM Annual Meeting (AN22): John von Neumann Prize - Leah Edelstein-Keshet, University of British Columbia, Canada</EventName>
    <EventSubName></EventSubName>
    <Poster></Poster>
    <EventNumber>CB</EventNumber>
    <EventDate>Jul 12, 2022</EventDate>
    <EventStartTime>2022-07-12T14:30:00</EventStartTime>
    <EventEndTime>2022-07-12T15:30:00</EventEndTime>
    <EventFilter>ED22|</EventFilter>
    <EventLocation></EventLocation>
    <EventRoom>Spirit of Pittsburgh A - 3rd Floor</EventRoom>
    <FloorPlan></FloorPlan>
    <EVENT_FEE></EVENT_FEE>
    <EventKeywords></EventKeywords>
    <EventChairs xsi:nil="true" />
    <EventModerators></EventModerators>
    <EventSpeakers></EventSpeakers>
    <EventSpeakerIDs xsi:nil="true" />
    <EventSponsor></EventSponsor>
    <EventHandoutName></EventHandoutName>
    <EventHandoutURL></EventHandoutURL>
    <EventDescription>&lt;a href="https://meetings.siam.org/sess/dsp_programsess.cfm?
SESSIONCODE=74982"&gt;Click Here for Details&lt;/a&gt;
</EventDescription>
    <EventParent></EventParent>
    <EventUniqueID>74759-SESS</EventUniqueID>
    <STATUS>active</STATUS>
    <AutoRecord>0</AutoRecord>
    <EnabledForIAV>0</EnabledForIAV>
    <MeetingIAVMode xsi:nil="true" />
    <PublishAutoRecordedVideo xsi:nil="true" />
    <Capacity xsi:nil="true" />
    <DirectLinkEnabled xsi:nil="true" />
    <DirectLinkRecordingEnabled xsi:nil="true" />
    <start>2022-07-12T14:30:00</start>
  </meeting>
  <meeting>
    <Confcode>ED22</Confcode>
    <EventName>2022 SIAM Annual Meeting (AN22): SIAM Business Meeting</EventName>
    <EventSubName></EventSubName>
    <Poster></Poster>
    <EventNumber>CB</EventNumber>
    <EventDate>Jul 12, 2022</EventDate>
    <EventStartTime>2022-07-12T18:15:00</EventStartTime>
    <EventEndTime>2022-07-12T19:15:00</EventEndTime>
    <EventFilter>ED22|</EventFilter>
    <EventLocation></EventLocation>
    <EventRoom>Spirit of Pittsburgh A - 3rd Floor</EventRoom>
    <FloorPlan></FloorPlan>
    <EVENT_FEE></EVENT_FEE>
    <EventKeywords></EventKeywords>
    <EventChairs xsi:nil="true" />
    <EventModerators></EventModerators>
    <EventSpeakers></EventSpeakers>
    <EventSpeakerIDs xsi:nil="true" />
    <EventSponsor></EventSponsor>
    <EventHandoutName></EventHandoutName>
    <EventHandoutURL></EventHandoutURL>
    <EventDescription></EventDescription>
    <EventParent></EventParent>
    <EventUniqueID>74762-SESS</EventUniqueID>
    <STATUS>active</STATUS>
    <AutoRecord>1</AutoRecord>
    <EnabledForIAV>1</EnabledForIAV>
    <MeetingIAVMode>Meeting</MeetingIAVMode>
    <PublishAutoRecordedVideo>1</PublishAutoRecordedVideo>
    <Capacity>300</Capacity>
    <DirectLinkEnabled xsi:nil="true" />
    <DirectLinkRecordingEnabled xsi:nil="true" />
    <start>2022-07-12T18:15:00</start>
  </meeting>
  <meeting>
    <Confcode>ED22</Confcode>
    <EventName>Badge Pick-Up and Information Desk</EventName>
    <EventSubName></EventSubName>
    <Poster></Poster>
    <EventNumber>CB</EventNumber>
    <EventDate>Jul 10, 2022</EventDate>
    <EventStartTime>2022-07-10T16:00:00</EventStartTime>
    <EventEndTime>2022-07-10T20:00:00</EventEndTime>
    <EventFilter>ed22|</EventFilter>
    <EventLocation></EventLocation>
    <EventRoom>Ballroom Gallery - 3rd Floor</EventRoom>
    <FloorPlan></FloorPlan>
    <EVENT_FEE></EVENT_FEE>
    <EventKeywords></EventKeywords>
    <EventChairs xsi:nil="true" />
    <EventModerators></EventModerators>
    <EventSpeakers></EventSpeakers>
    <EventSpeakerIDs xsi:nil="true" />
    <EventSponsor></EventSponsor>
    <EventHandoutName></EventHandoutName>
    <EventHandoutURL></EventHandoutURL>
    <EventDescription></EventDescription>
    <EventParent></EventParent>
    <EventUniqueID>75063-SESS</EventUniqueID>
    <STATUS>active</STATUS>
    <AutoRecord>0</AutoRecord>
    <EnabledForIAV>0</EnabledForIAV>
    <MeetingIAVMode xsi:nil="true" />
    <PublishAutoRecordedVideo xsi:nil="true" />
    <Capacity xsi:nil="true" />
    <DirectLinkEnabled xsi:nil="true" />
    <DirectLinkRecordingEnabled xsi:nil="true" />
    <start>2022-07-10T16:00:00</start>
  </meeting>
  <meeting>
    <Confcode>ED22</Confcode>
    <EventName>Badge Pick-Up and Information Desk</EventName>
    <EventSubName></EventSubName>
    <Poster></Poster>
    <EventNumber>CB</EventNumber>
    <EventDate>Jul 11, 2022</EventDate>
    <EventStartTime>2022-07-11T07:30:00</EventStartTime>
    <EventEndTime>2022-07-11T16:30:00</EventEndTime>
    <EventFilter>ed22|</EventFilter>
    <EventLocation></EventLocation>
    <EventRoom>Ballroom Gallery - 3rd Floor</EventRoom>
    <FloorPlan></FloorPlan>
    <EVENT_FEE></EVENT_FEE>
    <EventKeywords></EventKeywords>
    <EventChairs xsi:nil="true" />
    <EventModerators></EventModerators>
    <EventSpeakers></EventSpeakers>
    <EventSpeakerIDs xsi:nil="true" />
    <EventSponsor></EventSponsor>
    <EventHandoutName></EventHandoutName>
    <EventHandoutURL></EventHandoutURL>
    <EventDescription></EventDescription>
    <EventParent></EventParent>
    <EventUniqueID>75061-SESS</EventUniqueID>
    <STATUS>active</STATUS>
    <AutoRecord>0</AutoRecord>
    <EnabledForIAV>0</EnabledForIAV>
    <MeetingIAVMode xsi:nil="true" />
    <PublishAutoRecordedVideo xsi:nil="true" />
    <Capacity xsi:nil="true" />
    <DirectLinkEnabled xsi:nil="true" />
    <DirectLinkRecordingEnabled xsi:nil="true" />
    <start>2022-07-11T07:30:00</start>
  </meeting>
  <meeting>
    <Confcode>ED22</Confcode>
    <EventName>Badge Pick-Up and Information Desk</EventName>
    <EventSubName></EventSubName>
    <Poster></Poster>
    <EventNumber>CB</EventNumber>
    <EventDate>Jul 12, 2022</EventDate>
    <EventStartTime>2022-07-12T08:00:00</EventStartTime>
    <EventEndTime>2022-07-12T16:30:00</EventEndTime>
    <EventFilter>ed22|</EventFilter>
    <EventLocation></EventLocation>
    <EventRoom>Ballroom Gallery - 3rd Floor</EventRoom>
    <FloorPlan></FloorPlan>
    <EVENT_FEE></EVENT_FEE>
    <EventKeywords></EventKeywords>
    <EventChairs xsi:nil="true" />
    <EventModerators></EventModerators>
    <EventSpeakers></EventSpeakers>
    <EventSpeakerIDs xsi:nil="true" />
    <EventSponsor></EventSponsor>
    <EventHandoutName></EventHandoutName>
    <EventHandoutURL></EventHandoutURL>
    <EventDescription></EventDescription>
    <EventParent></EventParent>
    <EventUniqueID>75062-SESS</EventUniqueID>
    <STATUS>active</STATUS>
    <AutoRecord>0</AutoRecord>
    <EnabledForIAV>0</EnabledForIAV>
    <MeetingIAVMode xsi:nil="true" />
    <PublishAutoRecordedVideo xsi:nil="true" />
    <Capacity xsi:nil="true" />
    <DirectLinkEnabled xsi:nil="true" />
    <DirectLinkRecordingEnabled xsi:nil="true" />
    <start>2022-07-12T08:00:00</start>
  </meeting>
  <meeting>
    <Confcode>ED22</Confcode>
    <EventName>Coffee Break</EventName>
    <EventSubName></EventSubName>
    <Poster></Poster>
    <EventNumber>CB</EventNumber>
    <EventDate>Jul 11, 2022</EventDate>
    <EventStartTime>2022-07-11T10:30:00</EventStartTime>
    <EventEndTime>2022-07-11T10:45:00</EventEndTime>
    <EventFilter>ED22|</EventFilter>
    <EventLocation></EventLocation>
    <EventRoom>Ballroom Gallery - 3rd Floor</EventRoom>
    <FloorPlan></FloorPlan>
    <EVENT_FEE></EVENT_FEE>
    <EventKeywords></EventKeywords>
    <EventChairs xsi:nil="true" />
    <EventModerators></EventModerators>
    <EventSpeakers></EventSpeakers>
    <EventSpeakerIDs xsi:nil="true" />
    <EventSponsor></EventSponsor>
    <EventHandoutName></EventHandoutName>
    <EventHandoutURL></EventHandoutURL>
    <EventDescription></EventDescription>
    <EventParent></EventParent>
    <EventUniqueID>74750-SESS</EventUniqueID>
    <STATUS>active</STATUS>
    <AutoRecord>0</AutoRecord>
    <EnabledForIAV>0</EnabledForIAV>
    <MeetingIAVMode xsi:nil="true" />
    <PublishAutoRecordedVideo xsi:nil="true" />
    <Capacity xsi:nil="true" />
    <DirectLinkEnabled xsi:nil="true" />
    <DirectLinkRecordingEnabled xsi:nil="true" />
    <start>2022-07-11T10:30:00</start>
  </meeting>
  <meeting>
    <Confcode>ED22</Confcode>
    <EventName>Coffee Break</EventName>
    <EventSubName></EventSubName>
    <Poster></Poster>
    <EventNumber>CB</EventNumber>
    <EventDate>Jul 11, 2022</EventDate>
    <EventStartTime>2022-07-11T15:30:00</EventStartTime>
    <EventEndTime>2022-07-11T16:00:00</EventEndTime>
    <EventFilter>ED22|</EventFilter>
    <EventLocation></EventLocation>
    <EventRoom>Ballroom Gallery - 3rd Floor</EventRoom>
    <FloorPlan></FloorPlan>
    <EVENT_FEE></EVENT_FEE>
    <EventKeywords></EventKeywords>
    <EventChairs xsi:nil="true" />
    <EventModerators></EventModerators>
    <EventSpeakers></EventSpeakers>
    <EventSpeakerIDs xsi:nil="true" />
    <EventSponsor></EventSponsor>
    <EventHandoutName></EventHandoutName>
    <EventHandoutURL></EventHandoutURL>
    <EventDescription></EventDescription>
    <EventParent></EventParent>
    <EventUniqueID>74753-SESS</EventUniqueID>
    <STATUS>active</STATUS>
    <AutoRecord>0</AutoRecord>
    <EnabledForIAV>0</EnabledForIAV>
    <MeetingIAVMode xsi:nil="true" />
    <PublishAutoRecordedVideo xsi:nil="true" />
    <Capacity xsi:nil="true" />
    <DirectLinkEnabled xsi:nil="true" />
    <DirectLinkRecordingEnabled xsi:nil="true" />
    <start>2022-07-11T15:30:00</start>
  </meeting>
  <meeting>
    <Confcode>ED22</Confcode>
    <EventName>Coffee Break</EventName>
    <EventSubName></EventSubName>
    <Poster></Poster>
    <EventNumber>CB</EventNumber>
    <EventDate>Jul 12, 2022</EventDate>
    <EventStartTime>2022-07-12T10:30:00</EventStartTime>
    <EventEndTime>2022-07-12T11:00:00</EventEndTime>
    <EventFilter>ED22|</EventFilter>
    <EventLocation></EventLocation>
    <EventRoom>Ballroom Gallery - 3rd Floor</EventRoom>
    <FloorPlan></FloorPlan>
    <EVENT_FEE></EVENT_FEE>
    <EventKeywords></EventKeywords>
    <EventChairs xsi:nil="true" />
    <EventModerators></EventModerators>
    <EventSpeakers></EventSpeakers>
    <EventSpeakerIDs xsi:nil="true" />
    <EventSponsor></EventSponsor>
    <EventHandoutName></EventHandoutName>
    <EventHandoutURL></EventHandoutURL>
    <EventDescription></EventDescription>
    <EventParent></EventParent>
    <EventUniqueID>74757-SESS</EventUniqueID>
    <STATUS>active</STATUS>
    <AutoRecord>0</AutoRecord>
    <EnabledForIAV>0</EnabledForIAV>
    <MeetingIAVMode xsi:nil="true" />
    <PublishAutoRecordedVideo xsi:nil="true" />
    <Capacity xsi:nil="true" />
    <DirectLinkEnabled xsi:nil="true" />
    <DirectLinkRecordingEnabled xsi:nil="true" />
    <start>2022-07-12T10:30:00</start>
  </meeting>
  <meeting>
    <Confcode>ED22</Confcode>
    <EventName>Coffee Break</EventName>
    <EventSubName></EventSubName>
    <Poster></Poster>
    <EventNumber>CB</EventNumber>
    <EventDate>Jul 12, 2022</EventDate>
    <EventStartTime>2022-07-12T15:30:00</EventStartTime>
    <EventEndTime>2022-07-12T16:00:00</EventEndTime>
    <EventFilter>ED22|</EventFilter>
    <EventLocation></EventLocation>
    <EventRoom>Ballroom Gallery - 3rd Floor</EventRoom>
    <FloorPlan></FloorPlan>
    <EVENT_FEE></EVENT_FEE>
    <EventKeywords></EventKeywords>
    <EventChairs xsi:nil="true" />
    <EventModerators></EventModerators>
    <EventSpeakers></EventSpeakers>
    <EventSpeakerIDs xsi:nil="true" />
    <EventSponsor></EventSponsor>
    <EventHandoutName></EventHandoutName>
    <EventHandoutURL></EventHandoutURL>
    <EventDescription></EventDescription>
    <EventParent></EventParent>
    <EventUniqueID>74760-SESS</EventUniqueID>
    <STATUS>active</STATUS>
    <AutoRecord>0</AutoRecord>
    <EnabledForIAV>0</EnabledForIAV>
    <MeetingIAVMode xsi:nil="true" />
    <PublishAutoRecordedVideo xsi:nil="true" />
    <Capacity xsi:nil="true" />
    <DirectLinkEnabled xsi:nil="true" />
    <DirectLinkRecordingEnabled xsi:nil="true" />
    <start>2022-07-12T15:30:00</start>
  </meeting>
  <meeting>
    <Confcode>ED22</Confcode>
    <EventName>CP1 Student-Engaged Teaching and Learning</EventName>
    <EventSubName></EventSubName>
    <Poster></Poster>
    <EventNumber>CP1</EventNumber>
    <EventDate>Jul 11, 2022</EventDate>
    <EventStartTime>2022-07-11T08:30:00</EventStartTime>
    <EventEndTime>2022-07-11T10:30:00</EventEndTime>
    <EventFilter>ED22|Contributed|</EventFilter>
    <EventLocation></EventLocation>
    <EventRoom>404</EventRoom>
    <FloorPlan></FloorPlan>
    <EVENT_FEE></EVENT_FEE>
    <EventKeywords></EventKeywords>
    <EventChairs>806682</EventChairs>
    <EventModerators></EventModerators>
    <EventSpeakers></EventSpeakers>
    <EventSpeakerIDs>716013,806682,805296</EventSpeakerIDs>
    <EventSponsor></EventSponsor>
    <EventHandoutName>session</EventHandoutName>
    <EventHandoutURL>http://meetings.siam.org/sess/dsp_programsess.cfm?SESSIONCODE=74686</EventHandoutURL>
    <EventDescription></EventDescription>
    <EventParent></EventParent>
    <EventUniqueID>74686-SESS</EventUniqueID>
    <STATUS>active</STATUS>
    <AutoRecord>1</AutoRecord>
    <EnabledForIAV>1</EnabledForIAV>
    <MeetingIAVMode>Meeting</MeetingIAVMode>
    <PublishAutoRecordedVideo>1</PublishAutoRecordedVideo>
    <Capacity>300</Capacity>
    <DirectLinkEnabled xsi:nil="true" />
    <DirectLinkRecordingEnabled xsi:nil="true" />
    <start>2022-07-11T08:30:00</start>
  </meeting>
  <meeting>
    <Confcode>ED22</Confcode>
    <EventName>CP2 Data and Computing Pedagogy</EventName>
    <EventSubName></EventSubName>
    <Poster></Poster>
    <EventNumber>CP2</EventNumber>
    <EventDate>Jul 12, 2022</EventDate>
    <EventStartTime>2022-07-12T16:00:00</EventStartTime>
    <EventEndTime>2022-07-12T18:00:00</EventEndTime>
    <EventFilter>ED22|Contributed|</EventFilter>
    <EventLocation></EventLocation>
    <EventRoom>406</EventRoom>
    <FloorPlan></FloorPlan>
    <EVENT_FEE></EVENT_FEE>
    <EventKeywords></EventKeywords>
    <EventChairs>805839</EventChairs>
    <EventModerators></EventModerators>
    <EventSpeakers></EventSpeakers>
    <EventSpeakerIDs>805361,805839,806192,783188,10328,703625</EventSpeakerIDs>
    <EventSponsor></EventSponsor>
    <EventHandoutName>session</EventHandoutName>
    <EventHandoutURL>http://meetings.siam.org/sess/dsp_programsess.cfm?SESSIONCODE=74689</EventHandoutURL>
    <EventDescription></EventDescription>
    <EventParent></EventParent>
    <EventUniqueID>74689-SESS</EventUniqueID>
    <STATUS>active</STATUS>
    <AutoRecord>1</AutoRecord>
    <EnabledForIAV>1</EnabledForIAV>
    <MeetingIAVMode>Meeting</MeetingIAVMode>
    <PublishAutoRecordedVideo>1</PublishAutoRecordedVideo>
    <Capacity>300</Capacity>
    <DirectLinkEnabled xsi:nil="true" />
    <DirectLinkRecordingEnabled xsi:nil="true" />
    <start>2022-07-12T16:00:00</start>
  </meeting>
  <meeting>
    <Confcode>ED22</Confcode>
    <EventName>Intermission</EventName>
    <EventSubName></EventSubName>
    <Poster></Poster>
    <EventNumber>CB</EventNumber>
    <EventDate>Jul 11, 2022</EventDate>
    <EventStartTime>2022-07-11T18:00:00</EventStartTime>
    <EventEndTime>2022-07-11T18:15:00</EventEndTime>
    <EventFilter>ED22|</EventFilter>
    <EventLocation></EventLocation>
    <EventRoom></EventRoom>
    <FloorPlan></FloorPlan>
    <EVENT_FEE></EVENT_FEE>
    <EventKeywords></EventKeywords>
    <EventChairs xsi:nil="true" />
    <EventModerators></EventModerators>
    <EventSpeakers></EventSpeakers>
    <EventSpeakerIDs xsi:nil="true" />
    <EventSponsor></EventSponsor>
    <EventHandoutName></EventHandoutName>
    <EventHandoutURL></EventHandoutURL>
    <EventDescription></EventDescription>
    <EventParent></EventParent>
    <EventUniqueID>74756-SESS</EventUniqueID>
    <STATUS>active</STATUS>
    <AutoRecord>0</AutoRecord>
    <EnabledForIAV>0</EnabledForIAV>
    <MeetingIAVMode xsi:nil="true" />
    <PublishAutoRecordedVideo xsi:nil="true" />
    <Capacity xsi:nil="true" />
    <DirectLinkEnabled xsi:nil="true" />
    <DirectLinkRecordingEnabled xsi:nil="true" />
    <start>2022-07-11T18:00:00</start>
  </meeting>
  <meeting>
    <Confcode>ED22</Confcode>
    <EventName>Intermission</EventName>
    <EventSubName></EventSubName>
    <Poster></Poster>
    <EventNumber>CB</EventNumber>
    <EventDate>Jul 12, 2022</EventDate>
    <EventStartTime>2022-07-12T18:00:00</EventStartTime>
    <EventEndTime>2022-07-12T18:15:00</EventEndTime>
    <EventFilter>ED22|</EventFilter>
    <EventLocation></EventLocation>
    <EventRoom></EventRoom>
    <FloorPlan></FloorPlan>
    <EVENT_FEE></EVENT_FEE>
    <EventKeywords></EventKeywords>
    <EventChairs xsi:nil="true" />
    <EventModerators></EventModerators>
    <EventSpeakers></EventSpeakers>
    <EventSpeakerIDs xsi:nil="true" />
    <EventSponsor></EventSponsor>
    <EventHandoutName></EventHandoutName>
    <EventHandoutURL></EventHandoutURL>
    <EventDescription></EventDescription>
    <EventParent></EventParent>
    <EventUniqueID>74761-SESS</EventUniqueID>
    <STATUS>active</STATUS>
    <AutoRecord>0</AutoRecord>
    <EnabledForIAV>0</EnabledForIAV>
    <MeetingIAVMode xsi:nil="true" />
    <PublishAutoRecordedVideo xsi:nil="true" />
    <Capacity xsi:nil="true" />
    <DirectLinkEnabled xsi:nil="true" />
    <DirectLinkRecordingEnabled xsi:nil="true" />
    <start>2022-07-12T18:00:00</start>
  </meeting>
  <meeting>
    <Confcode>ED22</Confcode>
    <EventName>IP1 Opening Remarks and Presentation: Preparing and Supporting Teachers to Include Mathematical Modeling in Their Curriculum </EventName>
    <EventSubName></EventSubName>
    <Poster></Poster>
    <EventNumber>IP1</EventNumber>
    <EventDate>Jul 11, 2022</EventDate>
    <EventStartTime>2022-07-11T10:45:00</EventStartTime>
    <EventEndTime>2022-07-11T11:45:00</EventEndTime>
    <EventFilter>ED22|Invited Speaker|</EventFilter>
    <EventLocation></EventLocation>
    <EventRoom>406</EventRoom>
    <FloorPlan></FloorPlan>
    <EVENT_FEE></EVENT_FEE>
    <EventKeywords></EventKeywords>
    <EventChairs>807376</EventChairs>
    <EventModerators></EventModerators>
    <EventSpeakers></EventSpeakers>
    <EventSpeakerIDs>729229</EventSpeakerIDs>
    <EventSponsor></EventSponsor>
    <EventHandoutName>session</EventHandoutName>
    <EventHandoutURL>http://meetings.siam.org/sess/dsp_programsess.cfm?SESSIONCODE=73754</EventHandoutURL>
    <EventDescription>Students clearly deserve stimulating problem-solving opportunities in which they create and explore mathematical models to address situations relevant and meaningful to them. Yet despite calls to incorporate more modeling activities in our classes, teachers at all levels struggle to put recommendations into action.  Since undergraduate mathematics serves as a confluence in the teacher preparation stream, it must include ‘model’ mathematical modeling pedagogy. In this talk, I will share insights my collaborators and I have gained from designing and implementing data driven mathematical modeling activities in undergraduate courses. I will further detail various strategies for engaging undergraduate mathematics faculty as well as prospective and professional secondary teachers in mathematical modeling focused professional development.</EventDescription>
    <EventParent></EventParent>
    <EventUniqueID>73754-SESS</EventUniqueID>
    <STATUS>active</STATUS>
    <AutoRecord xsi:nil="true" />
    <EnabledForIAV xsi:nil="true" />
    <MeetingIAVMode xsi:nil="true" />
    <PublishAutoRecordedVideo>1</PublishAutoRecordedVideo>
    <Capacity xsi:nil="true" />
    <DirectLinkEnabled>1</DirectLinkEnabled>
    <DirectLinkRecordingEnabled>1</DirectLinkRecordingEnabled>
    <start>2022-07-11T10:45:00</start>
  </meeting>
  <meeting>
    <Confcode>ED22</Confcode>
    <EventName>IP2 Research on Learning and Teaching University Mathematics: Where We Are and Where We Might Go Next</EventName>
    <EventSubName></EventSubName>
    <Poster></Poster>
    <EventNumber>IP2</EventNumber>
    <EventDate>Jul 11, 2022</EventDate>
    <EventStartTime>2022-07-11T14:00:00</EventStartTime>
    <EventEndTime>2022-07-11T14:45:00</EventEndTime>
    <EventFilter>ED22|Invited Speaker|</EventFilter>
    <EventLocation></EventLocation>
    <EventRoom>406</EventRoom>
    <FloorPlan></FloorPlan>
    <EVENT_FEE></EVENT_FEE>
    <EventKeywords></EventKeywords>
    <EventChairs>807377</EventChairs>
    <EventModerators></EventModerators>
    <EventSpeakers></EventSpeakers>
    <EventSpeakerIDs>783841</EventSpeakerIDs>
    <EventSponsor></EventSponsor>
    <EventHandoutName>session</EventHandoutName>
    <EventHandoutURL>http://meetings.siam.org/sess/dsp_programsess.cfm?SESSIONCODE=73755</EventHandoutURL>
    <EventDescription>In this talk I begin with a brief overview of what we know about the teaching and learning of calculus in the United States. In particular, I highlight findings from two large US national studies of the precalculus through calculus sequence . Next, I review what we know about the effects and uptake of research-based instructional strategies at the university level. I then reflect on new directions for the broader field of research in university mathematics education. These new directions include expanding the notion of inquiry, research related to departmental and institutional change, and research that centers issues of equity and social justice. </EventDescription>
    <EventParent></EventParent>
    <EventUniqueID>73755-SESS</EventUniqueID>
    <STATUS>active</STATUS>
    <AutoRecord xsi:nil="true" />
    <EnabledForIAV xsi:nil="true" />
    <MeetingIAVMode xsi:nil="true" />
    <PublishAutoRecordedVideo>1</PublishAutoRecordedVideo>
    <Capacity xsi:nil="true" />
    <DirectLinkEnabled>1</DirectLinkEnabled>
    <DirectLinkRecordingEnabled>1</DirectLinkRecordingEnabled>
    <start>2022-07-11T14:00:00</start>
  </meeting>
  <meeting>
    <Confcode>ED22</Confcode>
    <EventName>IP3 Education, Data, and Social Justice</EventName>
    <EventSubName></EventSubName>
    <Poster></Poster>
    <EventNumber>IP3</EventNumber>
    <EventDate>Jul 12, 2022</EventDate>
    <EventStartTime>2022-07-12T11:00:00</EventStartTime>
    <EventEndTime>2022-07-12T11:45:00</EventEndTime>
    <EventFilter>ED22|Invited Speaker|</EventFilter>
    <EventLocation></EventLocation>
    <EventRoom>406</EventRoom>
    <FloorPlan></FloorPlan>
    <EVENT_FEE></EVENT_FEE>
    <EventKeywords></EventKeywords>
    <EventChairs>732230</EventChairs>
    <EventModerators></EventModerators>
    <EventSpeakers></EventSpeakers>
    <EventSpeakerIDs>87940</EventSpeakerIDs>
    <EventSponsor></EventSponsor>
    <EventHandoutName>session</EventHandoutName>
    <EventHandoutURL>http://meetings.siam.org/sess/dsp_programsess.cfm?SESSIONCODE=73756</EventHandoutURL>
    <EventDescription>While the importance of data science training has been highlighted by stakeholders across the mathematical sciences, the fusion of data skills with core parts of the curriculum has yet to be fully realized. In parallel to this challenge, the mathematical sciences are struggling with issues of equity, diversity, and inclusion. This talk presents pathways for incorporating data skills into undergraduate mathematics education in ways that support social justice. One pathway is through the classroom. I will present selected examples of course activities such as creation of computational art designed to celebrate artists from marginalized identity groups. A second pathway is through undergraduate research. I will showcase data-intensive student projects, including work on incarceration policy on Rikers Island. Finally, I will highlight resources for instructors who themselves want to grow their data skills and/or their understanding of social justice.</EventDescription>
    <EventParent></EventParent>
    <EventUniqueID>73756-SESS</EventUniqueID>
    <STATUS>active</STATUS>
    <AutoRecord xsi:nil="true" />
    <EnabledForIAV xsi:nil="true" />
    <MeetingIAVMode xsi:nil="true" />
    <PublishAutoRecordedVideo>1</PublishAutoRecordedVideo>
    <Capacity xsi:nil="true" />
    <DirectLinkEnabled>1</DirectLinkEnabled>
    <DirectLinkRecordingEnabled>1</DirectLinkRecordingEnabled>
    <start>2022-07-12T11:00:00</start>
  </meeting>
  <meeting>
    <Confcode>ED22</Confcode>
    <EventName>IP4 Closing Remarks and Presentation: Toward a Culturally Relevant and Historically Responsive Data Science</EventName>
    <EventSubName></EventSubName>
    <Poster></Poster>
    <EventNumber>IP4</EventNumber>
    <EventDate>Jul 12, 2022</EventDate>
    <EventStartTime>2022-07-12T11:45:00</EventStartTime>
    <EventEndTime>2022-07-12T12:35:00</EventEndTime>
    <EventFilter>ED22|Invited Speaker|</EventFilter>
    <EventLocation></EventLocation>
    <EventRoom>406</EventRoom>
    <FloorPlan></FloorPlan>
    <EVENT_FEE></EVENT_FEE>
    <EventKeywords></EventKeywords>
    <EventChairs>807375</EventChairs>
    <EventModerators></EventModerators>
    <EventSpeakers></EventSpeakers>
    <EventSpeakerIDs>805303</EventSpeakerIDs>
    <EventSponsor></EventSponsor>
    <EventHandoutName>session</EventHandoutName>
    <EventHandoutURL>http://meetings.siam.org/sess/dsp_programsess.cfm?SESSIONCODE=73753</EventHandoutURL>
    <EventDescription>In the expanding discourses around data science and statistical data analysis, less work has been done
to make culturally- and historically- centered pedagogies a central area of investigation. To this end,
this invited talk will examine seminal theories in education focused on the role of culture and history in
teaching and student learning. Within the development of inquiry-based classrooms, these frameworks
support our collective knowledge around the role of culture and history in relation to applied
mathematics, statistics, and data science education in k-12, postsecondary, and community settings.
Moreover, these frameworks can be used to support the ongoing development of data science programs
and research-practice partnerships that advance actionable and critical data science practices.</EventDescription>
    <EventParent></EventParent>
    <EventUniqueID>73753-SESS</EventUniqueID>
    <STATUS>active</STATUS>
    <AutoRecord xsi:nil="true" />
    <EnabledForIAV xsi:nil="true" />
    <MeetingIAVMode xsi:nil="true" />
    <PublishAutoRecordedVideo>1</PublishAutoRecordedVideo>
    <Capacity xsi:nil="true" />
    <DirectLinkEnabled>1</DirectLinkEnabled>
    <DirectLinkRecordingEnabled>1</DirectLinkRecordingEnabled>
    <start>2022-07-12T11:45:00</start>
  </meeting>
  <meeting>
    <Confcode>ED22</Confcode>
    <EventName>JP1 Joint Plenary with the SIAM Annual Meeting AN22: Strengthening and Building Communities among Students, Faculty and the Public </EventName>
    <EventSubName></EventSubName>
    <Poster></Poster>
    <EventNumber>JP1</EventNumber>
    <EventDate>Jul 11, 2022</EventDate>
    <EventStartTime>2022-07-11T11:45:00</EventStartTime>
    <EventEndTime>2022-07-11T12:30:00</EventEndTime>
    <EventFilter>ED22|Invited Speaker|</EventFilter>
    <EventLocation></EventLocation>
    <EventRoom>Spirit of Pittsburgh A - 3rd Floor</EventRoom>
    <FloorPlan></FloorPlan>
    <EVENT_FEE></EVENT_FEE>
    <EventKeywords></EventKeywords>
    <EventChairs>704298</EventChairs>
    <EventModerators></EventModerators>
    <EventSpeakers></EventSpeakers>
    <EventSpeakerIDs>778806</EventSpeakerIDs>
    <EventSponsor></EventSponsor>
    <EventHandoutName>session</EventHandoutName>
    <EventHandoutURL>http://meetings.siam.org/sess/dsp_programsess.cfm?SESSIONCODE=73757</EventHandoutURL>
    <EventDescription>Given the large percentage of Latino and first-generation college students in the Rio Grande Valley, the University of Texas Rio Grande Valley serves as a hub for preparing the nation’s leadership in STEM disciplines from underrepresented groups.  In this talk, we describe efforts to build communities in applied mathematics involving public schools, students and faculty, universities, and the UTRGV Center of Excellence in STEM Education. We will discuss departmental initiatives in mathematics courses that build community among students and faculty, professional development activities and mentorship of college students, and K-12 collaborations.  </EventDescription>
    <EventParent></EventParent>
    <EventUniqueID>73757-SESS</EventUniqueID>
    <STATUS>active</STATUS>
    <AutoRecord xsi:nil="true" />
    <EnabledForIAV xsi:nil="true" />
    <MeetingIAVMode xsi:nil="true" />
    <PublishAutoRecordedVideo>1</PublishAutoRecordedVideo>
    <Capacity xsi:nil="true" />
    <DirectLinkEnabled>1</DirectLinkEnabled>
    <DirectLinkRecordingEnabled>1</DirectLinkRecordingEnabled>
    <start>2022-07-11T11:45:00</start>
  </meeting>
  <meeting>
    <Confcode>ED22</Confcode>
    <EventName>Lunch Break (attendees on their own)</EventName>
    <EventSubName></EventSubName>
    <Poster></Poster>
    <EventNumber>CB</EventNumber>
    <EventDate>Jul 11, 2022</EventDate>
    <EventStartTime>2022-07-11T12:30:00</EventStartTime>
    <EventEndTime>2022-07-11T14:00:00</EventEndTime>
    <EventFilter>ED22|</EventFilter>
    <EventLocation></EventLocation>
    <EventRoom>attendees on their own</EventRoom>
    <FloorPlan></FloorPlan>
    <EVENT_FEE></EVENT_FEE>
    <EventKeywords></EventKeywords>
    <EventChairs xsi:nil="true" />
    <EventModerators></EventModerators>
    <EventSpeakers></EventSpeakers>
    <EventSpeakerIDs xsi:nil="true" />
    <EventSponsor></EventSponsor>
    <EventHandoutName></EventHandoutName>
    <EventHandoutURL></EventHandoutURL>
    <EventDescription></EventDescription>
    <EventParent></EventParent>
    <EventUniqueID>74751-SESS</EventUniqueID>
    <STATUS>active</STATUS>
    <AutoRecord>0</AutoRecord>
    <EnabledForIAV>0</EnabledForIAV>
    <MeetingIAVMode xsi:nil="true" />
    <PublishAutoRecordedVideo xsi:nil="true" />
    <Capacity xsi:nil="true" />
    <DirectLinkEnabled xsi:nil="true" />
    <DirectLinkRecordingEnabled xsi:nil="true" />
    <start>2022-07-11T12:30:00</start>
  </meeting>
  <meeting>
    <Confcode>ED22</Confcode>
    <EventName>MS1 Extracurricular Training in Industrial Mathematics</EventName>
    <EventSubName></EventSubName>
    <Poster></Poster>
    <EventNumber>MS1</EventNumber>
    <EventDate>Jul 11, 2022</EventDate>
    <EventStartTime>2022-07-11T08:30:00</EventStartTime>
    <EventEndTime>2022-07-11T10:30:00</EventEndTime>
    <EventFilter>ED22|Minisymposium|</EventFilter>
    <EventLocation></EventLocation>
    <EventRoom>406</EventRoom>
    <FloorPlan></FloorPlan>
    <EVENT_FEE></EVENT_FEE>
    <EventKeywords>2800</EventKeywords>
    <EventChairs>31568</EventChairs>
    <EventModerators></EventModerators>
    <EventSpeakers></EventSpeakers>
    <EventSpeakerIDs>739164,31568,715127,716671</EventSpeakerIDs>
    <EventSponsor></EventSponsor>
    <EventHandoutName>session</EventHandoutName>
    <EventHandoutURL>http://meetings.siam.org/sess/dsp_programsess.cfm?SESSIONCODE=74229</EventHandoutURL>
    <EventDescription>For years, professional and governmental societies have advocated for providing mathematicians with training in industrial mathematics.  Successful industrial mathematicians need to be able to quickly assimilate and apply a wide variety of modeling, computational, and data science methods.  Given the rigid structure of many mathematics curricula, extracurricular training activities play a key role in supplementing the academic approach to better prepare math students for industrial careers.  Such short-term programs allow students to synthesize their mathematical knowledge while developing such "soft skills" as working in teams, making oral presentations, and writing technical reports.  The presenters will highlight two long-running summer programs where students work side-by-side with companies on industrial problems: an REU at Worcester Polytechnic Institute which exposes, and the joint Graduate Student Modeling Camp/Mathematical Problems in Industry Workshop program.</EventDescription>
    <EventParent></EventParent>
    <EventUniqueID>74229-SESS</EventUniqueID>
    <STATUS>active</STATUS>
    <AutoRecord>1</AutoRecord>
    <EnabledForIAV>1</EnabledForIAV>
    <MeetingIAVMode>Meeting</MeetingIAVMode>
    <PublishAutoRecordedVideo>1</PublishAutoRecordedVideo>
    <Capacity>300</Capacity>
    <DirectLinkEnabled xsi:nil="true" />
    <DirectLinkRecordingEnabled xsi:nil="true" />
    <start>2022-07-11T08:30:00</start>
  </meeting>
  <meeting>
    <Confcode>ED22</Confcode>
    <EventName>MS10 Advancing Racial Equity in Applied Mathematics - Part I of II</EventName>
    <EventSubName></EventSubName>
    <Poster></Poster>
    <EventNumber>MS10</EventNumber>
    <EventDate>Jul 12, 2022</EventDate>
    <EventStartTime>2022-07-12T08:30:00</EventStartTime>
    <EventEndTime>2022-07-12T10:30:00</EventEndTime>
    <EventFilter>ED22|Minisymposium|</EventFilter>
    <EventLocation></EventLocation>
    <EventRoom>406</EventRoom>
    <FloorPlan></FloorPlan>
    <EVENT_FEE></EVENT_FEE>
    <EventKeywords>2800</EventKeywords>
    <EventChairs>48079,733366,756849</EventChairs>
    <EventModerators></EventModerators>
    <EventSpeakers></EventSpeakers>
    <EventSpeakerIDs>48079,756849,788318,764425</EventSpeakerIDs>
    <EventSponsor></EventSponsor>
    <EventHandoutName>session</EventHandoutName>
    <EventHandoutURL>http://meetings.siam.org/sess/dsp_programsess.cfm?SESSIONCODE=74170</EventHandoutURL>
    <EventDescription>Issues of racial equity in the mathematical sciences have become more prominent since the catalyzing events of the summer of 2020. In this minisymposium we invite participants to present, learn and suggest mechanisms, programs or ideas that advance racial equity in the applied mathematics community.

Discussions of racial equity are an important component in any effort to promote justice, equity, diversity, and inclusion at SIAM and the larger applied mathematics community.</EventDescription>
    <EventParent></EventParent>
    <EventUniqueID>74170-SESS</EventUniqueID>
    <STATUS>active</STATUS>
    <AutoRecord>1</AutoRecord>
    <EnabledForIAV>1</EnabledForIAV>
    <MeetingIAVMode>Meeting</MeetingIAVMode>
    <PublishAutoRecordedVideo>1</PublishAutoRecordedVideo>
    <Capacity>300</Capacity>
    <DirectLinkEnabled xsi:nil="true" />
    <DirectLinkRecordingEnabled xsi:nil="true" />
    <start>2022-07-12T08:30:00</start>
  </meeting>
  <meeting>
    <Confcode>ED22</Confcode>
    <EventName>MS11 Teaching on the Interface of  Quantitative Sciences and the Life Sciences</EventName>
    <EventSubName></EventSubName>
    <Poster></Poster>
    <EventNumber>MS11</EventNumber>
    <EventDate>Jul 12, 2022</EventDate>
    <EventStartTime>2022-07-12T08:30:00</EventStartTime>
    <EventEndTime>2022-07-12T10:30:00</EventEndTime>
    <EventFilter>ED22|Minisymposium|</EventFilter>
    <EventLocation></EventLocation>
    <EventRoom>405</EventRoom>
    <FloorPlan></FloorPlan>
    <EVENT_FEE></EVENT_FEE>
    <EventKeywords>2800</EventKeywords>
    <EventChairs>805420</EventChairs>
    <EventModerators></EventModerators>
    <EventSpeakers></EventSpeakers>
    <EventSpeakerIDs>4007,733366,720567,805420</EventSpeakerIDs>
    <EventSponsor></EventSponsor>
    <EventHandoutName>session</EventHandoutName>
    <EventHandoutURL>http://meetings.siam.org/sess/dsp_programsess.cfm?SESSIONCODE=73886</EventHandoutURL>
    <EventDescription>The need for, and importance of, increased quantitative reasoning in life science education has been well documented in numerous reports such as HHMI’s Scientific Foundations for Future Physicians; AAAS’s Vision and Change; and Biology 2010, a cooperative effort led by the National Research Council. However, implementation has been slowed by disciplinary, institutional and historical challenges, especially when working across departments and across institutions.  To address these challenges, there are many active areas of research assessing best practices in developing and evaluating methods of incorporating quantitative reasoning in the life science curriculum. Speakers will highlight current work that advances our understanding of how best to incorporate quantitative reasoning and practices into the life science curriculum, including issues of what quantitative reasoning topics are best suited to the life sciences and in what order; what specific approaches have been most successful in promoting increased quantitative reasoning skills in a biological context; how can we assess changes in quantitative skills in undergraduate life science majors; what challenges have been most difficult to overcome in these efforts; and prospective efforts to confront those challenges.</EventDescription>
    <EventParent></EventParent>
    <EventUniqueID>73886-SESS</EventUniqueID>
    <STATUS>active</STATUS>
    <AutoRecord>1</AutoRecord>
    <EnabledForIAV>1</EnabledForIAV>
    <MeetingIAVMode>Meeting</MeetingIAVMode>
    <PublishAutoRecordedVideo>1</PublishAutoRecordedVideo>
    <Capacity>300</Capacity>
    <DirectLinkEnabled xsi:nil="true" />
    <DirectLinkRecordingEnabled xsi:nil="true" />
    <start>2022-07-12T08:30:00</start>
  </meeting>
  <meeting>
    <Confcode>ED22</Confcode>
    <EventName>MS12 Innovative Approaches to Undergraduate Research Mentorship - Part I of II</EventName>
    <EventSubName></EventSubName>
    <Poster></Poster>
    <EventNumber>MS12</EventNumber>
    <EventDate>Jul 12, 2022</EventDate>
    <EventStartTime>2022-07-12T08:30:00</EventStartTime>
    <EventEndTime>2022-07-12T10:30:00</EventEndTime>
    <EventFilter>ED22|Minisymposium|</EventFilter>
    <EventLocation></EventLocation>
    <EventRoom>404</EventRoom>
    <FloorPlan></FloorPlan>
    <EVENT_FEE></EVENT_FEE>
    <EventKeywords>2800</EventKeywords>
    <EventChairs>781853,783721,771154,805515</EventChairs>
    <EventModerators></EventModerators>
    <EventSpeakers></EventSpeakers>
    <EventSpeakerIDs>724456,793432,805602,805515</EventSpeakerIDs>
    <EventSponsor></EventSponsor>
    <EventHandoutName>session</EventHandoutName>
    <EventHandoutURL>http://meetings.siam.org/sess/dsp_programsess.cfm?SESSIONCODE=73860</EventHandoutURL>
    <EventDescription>Undergraduate research in applied mathematics is an important part of training for future scientists, mathematicians, and industry leaders. In this minisymposium, speakers will share innovative approaches to engage undergraduate students in research projects. Talks will highlight creative mentorship practices and examples of projects which have been successful. Innovative practices will range from creating individual/departmental structures to promote equitable research access, to building interdisciplinary/industrial/governmental partnerships. Speakers will represent a wide range of institutions and career stages, and the ideas shared in these sessions will inspire others to implement new and effective practices.</EventDescription>
    <EventParent></EventParent>
    <EventUniqueID>73860-SESS</EventUniqueID>
    <STATUS>active</STATUS>
    <AutoRecord>1</AutoRecord>
    <EnabledForIAV>1</EnabledForIAV>
    <MeetingIAVMode>Meeting</MeetingIAVMode>
    <PublishAutoRecordedVideo>1</PublishAutoRecordedVideo>
    <Capacity>300</Capacity>
    <DirectLinkEnabled xsi:nil="true" />
    <DirectLinkRecordingEnabled xsi:nil="true" />
    <start>2022-07-12T08:30:00</start>
  </meeting>
  <meeting>
    <Confcode>ED22</Confcode>
    <EventName>MS13 Project-Based Mathematical Modeling, Research, and Teacher Education - Part II of II</EventName>
    <EventSubName></EventSubName>
    <Poster></Poster>
    <EventNumber>MS13</EventNumber>
    <EventDate>Jul 12, 2022</EventDate>
    <EventStartTime>2022-07-12T08:30:00</EventStartTime>
    <EventEndTime>2022-07-12T10:30:00</EventEndTime>
    <EventFilter>ED22|Minisymposium|</EventFilter>
    <EventLocation></EventLocation>
    <EventRoom>403</EventRoom>
    <FloorPlan></FloorPlan>
    <EVENT_FEE></EVENT_FEE>
    <EventKeywords>3000</EventKeywords>
    <EventChairs>729229,702229</EventChairs>
    <EventModerators></EventModerators>
    <EventSpeakers></EventSpeakers>
    <EventSpeakerIDs>805744,792019,805748,805922</EventSpeakerIDs>
    <EventSponsor></EventSponsor>
    <EventHandoutName>session</EventHandoutName>
    <EventHandoutURL>http://meetings.siam.org/sess/dsp_programsess.cfm?SESSIONCODE=74199</EventHandoutURL>
    <EventDescription>Mathematical modeling is in the unique position of being part of the K-16 curriculum, a topic in undergraduate mathematics, a technique used by professionals, and an active area of research.  For this reason, it is important for mathematicians and mathematics educators to come together and advance collaboratively their instruction of a wide range of courses that prepare students for mathematical modeling applications in their future careers, including teacher preparation for K-12 education, consistent with the way practitioners construct and use mathematical models. This session will highlight collaborative research projects focused on modeling research, teacher education, and mathematical pedagogy in undergraduate courses, including practical approaches that engage students in data collection, theoretical, and computational approaches.</EventDescription>
    <EventParent></EventParent>
    <EventUniqueID>74199-SESS</EventUniqueID>
    <STATUS>active</STATUS>
    <AutoRecord>1</AutoRecord>
    <EnabledForIAV>1</EnabledForIAV>
    <MeetingIAVMode>Meeting</MeetingIAVMode>
    <PublishAutoRecordedVideo>1</PublishAutoRecordedVideo>
    <Capacity>300</Capacity>
    <DirectLinkEnabled xsi:nil="true" />
    <DirectLinkRecordingEnabled xsi:nil="true" />
    <start>2022-07-12T08:30:00</start>
  </meeting>
  <meeting>
    <Confcode>ED22</Confcode>
    <EventName>MS14 Supporting Teaching and Learning Differential Equations Through Modeling</EventName>
    <EventSubName></EventSubName>
    <Poster></Poster>
    <EventNumber>MS14</EventNumber>
    <EventDate>Jul 12, 2022</EventDate>
    <EventStartTime>2022-07-12T08:30:00</EventStartTime>
    <EventEndTime>2022-07-12T10:30:00</EventEndTime>
    <EventFilter>ED22|Minisymposium|</EventFilter>
    <EventLocation></EventLocation>
    <EventRoom>402</EventRoom>
    <FloorPlan></FloorPlan>
    <EVENT_FEE></EVENT_FEE>
    <EventKeywords>2800</EventKeywords>
    <EventChairs>773369</EventChairs>
    <EventModerators></EventModerators>
    <EventSpeakers></EventSpeakers>
    <EventSpeakerIDs>773369,711505,783282,806085</EventSpeakerIDs>
    <EventSponsor></EventSponsor>
    <EventHandoutName>session</EventHandoutName>
    <EventHandoutURL>http://meetings.siam.org/sess/dsp_programsess.cfm?SESSIONCODE=74292</EventHandoutURL>
    <EventDescription>It is appropriate and valuable to motivate student learning of applied mathematics through applications! In SIMIODE, an NSF funded community founded in 2013, we support faculty and teachers instructing and students learning differential equations in context in order to bring forth the excitement, intellectual joy, and practice in transferring the mathematics to cognate areas. The SIMIODE Community of Practice has thousands of members, hundreds of teaching and supplemental resources, and practical activities to foster and motivate learning the mathematics of differential equations through modeling.

We give an overview, as well as rich illustrations, of what SIMIODE has to offer in terms of OER resources and activities, e.g., teaching materials, potential modeling activities, forums, newsletter, workshops, EXPO conference, student challenge event SCUDEM, textbook, and much more, as well as examples of the actual teaching and learning process of using modeling in differential equations coursework.</EventDescription>
    <EventParent></EventParent>
    <EventUniqueID>74292-SESS</EventUniqueID>
    <STATUS>active</STATUS>
    <AutoRecord>1</AutoRecord>
    <EnabledForIAV>1</EnabledForIAV>
    <MeetingIAVMode>Meeting</MeetingIAVMode>
    <PublishAutoRecordedVideo>1</PublishAutoRecordedVideo>
    <Capacity>300</Capacity>
    <DirectLinkEnabled xsi:nil="true" />
    <DirectLinkRecordingEnabled xsi:nil="true" />
    <start>2022-07-12T08:30:00</start>
  </meeting>
  <meeting>
    <Confcode>ED22</Confcode>
    <EventName>MS15 Advancing Racial Equity in Applied Mathematics - Part II of II</EventName>
    <EventSubName></EventSubName>
    <Poster></Poster>
    <EventNumber>MS15</EventNumber>
    <EventDate>Jul 12, 2022</EventDate>
    <EventStartTime>2022-07-12T16:00:00</EventStartTime>
    <EventEndTime>2022-07-12T18:00:00</EventEndTime>
    <EventFilter>ED22|Minisymposium|</EventFilter>
    <EventLocation></EventLocation>
    <EventRoom>405</EventRoom>
    <FloorPlan></FloorPlan>
    <EVENT_FEE></EVENT_FEE>
    <EventKeywords>2800</EventKeywords>
    <EventChairs>48079,733366,756849</EventChairs>
    <EventModerators></EventModerators>
    <EventSpeakers></EventSpeakers>
    <EventSpeakerIDs>778808,805711,721529,727601</EventSpeakerIDs>
    <EventSponsor></EventSponsor>
    <EventHandoutName>session</EventHandoutName>
    <EventHandoutURL>http://meetings.siam.org/sess/dsp_programsess.cfm?SESSIONCODE=74171</EventHandoutURL>
    <EventDescription>Issues of racial equity in the mathematical sciences have become more prominent since the catalyzing events of the summer of 2020. In this minisymposium we invite participants to present, learn and suggest mechanisms, programs or ideas that advance racial equity in the applied mathematics community.

Discussions of racial equity are an important component in any effort to promote justice, equity, diversity, and inclusion at SIAM and the larger applied mathematics community.</EventDescription>
    <EventParent></EventParent>
    <EventUniqueID>74171-SESS</EventUniqueID>
    <STATUS>active</STATUS>
    <AutoRecord>1</AutoRecord>
    <EnabledForIAV>1</EnabledForIAV>
    <MeetingIAVMode>Meeting</MeetingIAVMode>
    <PublishAutoRecordedVideo>1</PublishAutoRecordedVideo>
    <Capacity>300</Capacity>
    <DirectLinkEnabled xsi:nil="true" />
    <DirectLinkRecordingEnabled xsi:nil="true" />
    <start>2022-07-12T16:00:00</start>
  </meeting>
  <meeting>
    <Confcode>ED22</Confcode>
    <EventName>MS16 Innovative Approaches to Undergraduate Research Mentorship - Part II of II</EventName>
    <EventSubName></EventSubName>
    <Poster></Poster>
    <EventNumber>MS16</EventNumber>
    <EventDate>Jul 12, 2022</EventDate>
    <EventStartTime>2022-07-12T16:00:00</EventStartTime>
    <EventEndTime>2022-07-12T18:00:00</EventEndTime>
    <EventFilter>ED22|Minisymposium|</EventFilter>
    <EventLocation></EventLocation>
    <EventRoom>404</EventRoom>
    <FloorPlan></FloorPlan>
    <EVENT_FEE></EVENT_FEE>
    <EventKeywords>2800</EventKeywords>
    <EventChairs>781853,783721,771154,805515</EventChairs>
    <EventModerators></EventModerators>
    <EventSpeakers></EventSpeakers>
    <EventSpeakerIDs>782398,783807,89782</EventSpeakerIDs>
    <EventSponsor></EventSponsor>
    <EventHandoutName>session</EventHandoutName>
    <EventHandoutURL>http://meetings.siam.org/sess/dsp_programsess.cfm?SESSIONCODE=73861</EventHandoutURL>
    <EventDescription>Undergraduate research in applied mathematics is an important part of training for future scientists, mathematicians, and industry leaders. In this minisymposium, speakers will share innovative approaches to engage undergraduate students in research projects. Talks will highlight creative mentorship practices and examples of projects which have been successful. Innovative practices will range from creating individual/departmental structures to promote equitable research access, to building interdisciplinary/industrial/governmental partnerships. Speakers will represent a wide range of institutions and career stages, and the ideas shared in these sessions will inspire others to implement new and effective practices.</EventDescription>
    <EventParent></EventParent>
    <EventUniqueID>73861-SESS</EventUniqueID>
    <STATUS>active</STATUS>
    <AutoRecord>1</AutoRecord>
    <EnabledForIAV>1</EnabledForIAV>
    <MeetingIAVMode>Meeting</MeetingIAVMode>
    <PublishAutoRecordedVideo>1</PublishAutoRecordedVideo>
    <Capacity>300</Capacity>
    <DirectLinkEnabled xsi:nil="true" />
    <DirectLinkRecordingEnabled xsi:nil="true" />
    <start>2022-07-12T16:00:00</start>
  </meeting>
  <meeting>
    <Confcode>ED22</Confcode>
    <EventName>MS17 Project-Based Learning</EventName>
    <EventSubName></EventSubName>
    <Poster></Poster>
    <EventNumber>MS17</EventNumber>
    <EventDate>Jul 12, 2022</EventDate>
    <EventStartTime>2022-07-12T16:00:00</EventStartTime>
    <EventEndTime>2022-07-12T18:00:00</EventEndTime>
    <EventFilter>ED22|Minisymposium|</EventFilter>
    <EventLocation></EventLocation>
    <EventRoom>403</EventRoom>
    <FloorPlan></FloorPlan>
    <EVENT_FEE></EVENT_FEE>
    <EventKeywords>2800</EventKeywords>
    <EventChairs>805751</EventChairs>
    <EventModerators></EventModerators>
    <EventSpeakers></EventSpeakers>
    <EventSpeakerIDs>783243,805751,805752,779205</EventSpeakerIDs>
    <EventSponsor></EventSponsor>
    <EventHandoutName>session</EventHandoutName>
    <EventHandoutURL>http://meetings.siam.org/sess/dsp_programsess.cfm?SESSIONCODE=74201</EventHandoutURL>
    <EventDescription>Incorporating class projects into the undergraduate math curriculum has numerous benefits. They create opportunities for students to engage with math content in a deeper and more personalized way, and to understand the applications of the math they learn. Projects also give students practice with technical writing and giving formal presentations. On the other hand, projects can be time-consuming and more subjective to grade as compared to traditional exams. In addition, within the constraints of a course, students must be given more structure as compared to an undergraduate research experience. In this minisymposium, speakers will share their ideas and experiences incorporating projects into their undergraduate math and applied math courses.</EventDescription>
    <EventParent></EventParent>
    <EventUniqueID>74201-SESS</EventUniqueID>
    <STATUS>active</STATUS>
    <AutoRecord>1</AutoRecord>
    <EnabledForIAV>1</EnabledForIAV>
    <MeetingIAVMode>Meeting</MeetingIAVMode>
    <PublishAutoRecordedVideo>1</PublishAutoRecordedVideo>
    <Capacity>300</Capacity>
    <DirectLinkEnabled xsi:nil="true" />
    <DirectLinkRecordingEnabled xsi:nil="true" />
    <start>2022-07-12T16:00:00</start>
  </meeting>
  <meeting>
    <Confcode>ED22</Confcode>
    <EventName>MS18 Modes of Reasoning About Proof in College Classrooms</EventName>
    <EventSubName></EventSubName>
    <Poster></Poster>
    <EventNumber>MS18</EventNumber>
    <EventDate>Jul 12, 2022</EventDate>
    <EventStartTime>2022-07-12T16:00:00</EventStartTime>
    <EventEndTime>2022-07-12T18:00:00</EventEndTime>
    <EventFilter>ED22|Minisymposium|</EventFilter>
    <EventLocation></EventLocation>
    <EventRoom>402</EventRoom>
    <FloorPlan></FloorPlan>
    <EVENT_FEE></EVENT_FEE>
    <EventKeywords>2800</EventKeywords>
    <EventChairs>701395</EventChairs>
    <EventModerators></EventModerators>
    <EventSpeakers></EventSpeakers>
    <EventSpeakerIDs>805430,701395,805431,805432</EventSpeakerIDs>
    <EventSponsor></EventSponsor>
    <EventHandoutName>session</EventHandoutName>
    <EventHandoutURL>http://meetings.siam.org/sess/dsp_programsess.cfm?SESSIONCODE=73891</EventHandoutURL>
    <EventDescription>Proofs are at the core of all mathematics, yet proofs are pedagogically challenging for both instructor and student. One reason that proof is challenging to teach and learn is that it is a rich and multifaceted concept. The minisymposium highlights recent advances in characterizing what it means to write and understand proofs and participate in a culture of proving, with an emphasis on classroom applications to improve the teaching of proof. The first talk will focus on the different ways a student can understand a proof, distinguishing between local understandings (why a particular step is valid) and global understanding (how the overarching method in the proof can be used to solve another problem). The development of valid and reliable proof comprehension tests will be discussed. The second talk will highlight the skills involved in proof construction, such as the skills involved in recalling definitions and structuring a proof. There will be a discussion of how these skills can be taught and how they correlate with performance in mathematics courses. The third talk will examine the functions of proof in the undergraduate mathematics classroom. The talk will highlight the explanatory role of proof, and focus on how explanatory proofs can be defined and identified. The fourth talk will discuss the myriad of proving activities, such as conjecturing, generalizing, and exemplifying, and how these activities can be fostered in student-centered classrooms.</EventDescription>
    <EventParent></EventParent>
    <EventUniqueID>73891-SESS</EventUniqueID>
    <STATUS>active</STATUS>
    <AutoRecord>1</AutoRecord>
    <EnabledForIAV>1</EnabledForIAV>
    <MeetingIAVMode>Meeting</MeetingIAVMode>
    <PublishAutoRecordedVideo>1</PublishAutoRecordedVideo>
    <Capacity>300</Capacity>
    <DirectLinkEnabled xsi:nil="true" />
    <DirectLinkRecordingEnabled xsi:nil="true" />
    <start>2022-07-12T16:00:00</start>
  </meeting>
  <meeting>
    <Confcode>ED22</Confcode>
    <EventName>MS2 NSF RTG Programs in Applied Mathematics and Data Science - Part I of II</EventName>
    <EventSubName></EventSubName>
    <Poster></Poster>
    <EventNumber>MS2</EventNumber>
    <EventDate>Jul 11, 2022</EventDate>
    <EventStartTime>2022-07-11T08:30:00</EventStartTime>
    <EventEndTime>2022-07-11T10:30:00</EventEndTime>
    <EventFilter>ED22|Minisymposium|</EventFilter>
    <EventLocation></EventLocation>
    <EventRoom>403</EventRoom>
    <FloorPlan></FloorPlan>
    <EVENT_FEE></EVENT_FEE>
    <EventKeywords>5100</EventKeywords>
    <EventChairs>704298</EventChairs>
    <EventModerators></EventModerators>
    <EventSpeakers></EventSpeakers>
    <EventSpeakerIDs>72042,795734,801430,729272</EventSpeakerIDs>
    <EventSponsor></EventSponsor>
    <EventHandoutName>session</EventHandoutName>
    <EventHandoutURL>http://meetings.siam.org/sess/dsp_programsess.cfm?SESSIONCODE=74081</EventHandoutURL>
    <EventDescription>NSF’s Research Training Groups in the Mathematical Sciences (RTG) program aims to increase the number of well-prepared U.S. citizens, nationals, and permanent residents to pursue careers in the mathematical sciences in academia, government, or industry. In this minisymposium, faculty from RTG programs from a variety of institutions will describe their research activities and models for training students and postdoctoral associates.  Topics will include research and educational activity integration, recruitment, mentorship, and undergraduate research engagement.  RTG programs in applied mathematics and data science will be the focus of this minisymposium.</EventDescription>
    <EventParent></EventParent>
    <EventUniqueID>74081-SESS</EventUniqueID>
    <STATUS>active</STATUS>
    <AutoRecord>1</AutoRecord>
    <EnabledForIAV>1</EnabledForIAV>
    <MeetingIAVMode>Meeting</MeetingIAVMode>
    <PublishAutoRecordedVideo>1</PublishAutoRecordedVideo>
    <Capacity>300</Capacity>
    <DirectLinkEnabled xsi:nil="true" />
    <DirectLinkRecordingEnabled xsi:nil="true" />
    <start>2022-07-11T08:30:00</start>
  </meeting>
  <meeting>
    <Confcode>ED22</Confcode>
    <EventName>MS3 STEM Up NY Noyce: Program Values and Why Focus on Rural/Urban Juxtaposition?</EventName>
    <EventSubName></EventSubName>
    <Poster></Poster>
    <EventNumber>MS3</EventNumber>
    <EventDate>Jul 11, 2022</EventDate>
    <EventStartTime>2022-07-11T08:30:00</EventStartTime>
    <EventEndTime>2022-07-11T10:30:00</EventEndTime>
    <EventFilter>ED22|Minisymposium|</EventFilter>
    <EventLocation></EventLocation>
    <EventRoom>402</EventRoom>
    <FloorPlan></FloorPlan>
    <EVENT_FEE></EVENT_FEE>
    <EventKeywords>2800</EventKeywords>
    <EventChairs>774513,805518</EventChairs>
    <EventModerators></EventModerators>
    <EventSpeakers></EventSpeakers>
    <EventSpeakerIDs>805517,805523,784709,805836</EventSpeakerIDs>
    <EventSponsor></EventSponsor>
    <EventHandoutName>session</EventHandoutName>
    <EventHandoutURL>http://meetings.siam.org/sess/dsp_programsess.cfm?SESSIONCODE=73964</EventHandoutURL>
    <EventDescription>Critical to the retention of STEM teachers in high-need districts is developing an understanding of the culture of both students and the learning environment combined with a strong background in STEM. In this session, we focus on overcoming the challenges in recruiting, training and retaining high-achieving STEM students to work in high-need secondary schools.  Exceptional undergraduate STEM students with a passion for teaching are recruited through the NSF Noyce Program at Clarkson University prior to their senior year. The main objective for the program is to support pre-service STEM teachers to develop cultural competence focusing on high-need schools (in urban and rural settings) so that they can appreciate the diversity of students they will work with and therefore better serve the schools and communities. The program offers a significant scholarship for both senior year and through their MAT (Masters of Arts in Teaching) year. We describe the framework of the program, with a focus on curriculum and immersive experiences that guide students in developing their own teaching identities with regards to equity, poverty, and social justice. A graduate student and an undergraduate student share their personal experiences about working with K-12 students and how the program supported them.</EventDescription>
    <EventParent></EventParent>
    <EventUniqueID>73964-SESS</EventUniqueID>
    <STATUS>active</STATUS>
    <AutoRecord>1</AutoRecord>
    <EnabledForIAV>1</EnabledForIAV>
    <MeetingIAVMode>Meeting</MeetingIAVMode>
    <PublishAutoRecordedVideo>1</PublishAutoRecordedVideo>
    <Capacity>300</Capacity>
    <DirectLinkEnabled xsi:nil="true" />
    <DirectLinkRecordingEnabled xsi:nil="true" />
    <start>2022-07-11T08:30:00</start>
  </meeting>
  <meeting>
    <Confcode>ED22</Confcode>
    <EventName>MS4 Mathematical Modeling Initiatives: An International Perspective</EventName>
    <EventSubName></EventSubName>
    <Poster></Poster>
    <EventNumber>MS4</EventNumber>
    <EventDate>Jul 11, 2022</EventDate>
    <EventStartTime>2022-07-11T08:30:00</EventStartTime>
    <EventEndTime>2022-07-11T10:30:00</EventEndTime>
    <EventFilter>ED22|Minisymposium|</EventFilter>
    <EventLocation></EventLocation>
    <EventRoom>401</EventRoom>
    <FloorPlan></FloorPlan>
    <EVENT_FEE></EVENT_FEE>
    <EventKeywords>2800</EventKeywords>
    <EventChairs>783292</EventChairs>
    <EventModerators></EventModerators>
    <EventSpeakers></EventSpeakers>
    <EventSpeakerIDs>805590,805592,805593,805605</EventSpeakerIDs>
    <EventSponsor></EventSponsor>
    <EventHandoutName>session</EventHandoutName>
    <EventHandoutURL>http://meetings.siam.org/sess/dsp_programsess.cfm?SESSIONCODE=74050</EventHandoutURL>
    <EventDescription>&lt;Mathematical modeling has increasingly become a focus of mathematics education worldwide. In 2014 COMAP created the International Mathematical Modeling Challenge (IMMC) to provide teachers the motivation for integrating modeling into the curriculum and students the opportunity to apply their modeling skills. Each country may enter up to two teams of up to four students each. This past year 55 teams from 40 countries participated. The purpose of the Challenge is to encourage changes in school curriculum by demonstrating the power of mathematical modeling. Countries have mobilized to successfully participate, and in several cases conduct their own pre-contests to select the two teams who will participate in the international Challenge.

In this minisymposium, we will first provide an overview and the history of the IMMC. We will present several examples of past Challenge problems and discuss students’ work. Challenge leaders from several participating countries will then describe their efforts in this area and how they are effecting institutional change. Moreover, the speakers will describe the position of mathematical modeling in their respective mathematics education systems.</EventDescription>
    <EventParent></EventParent>
    <EventUniqueID>74050-SESS</EventUniqueID>
    <STATUS>active</STATUS>
    <AutoRecord>1</AutoRecord>
    <EnabledForIAV>1</EnabledForIAV>
    <MeetingIAVMode>Meeting</MeetingIAVMode>
    <PublishAutoRecordedVideo>1</PublishAutoRecordedVideo>
    <Capacity>300</Capacity>
    <DirectLinkEnabled xsi:nil="true" />
    <DirectLinkRecordingEnabled xsi:nil="true" />
    <start>2022-07-11T08:30:00</start>
  </meeting>
  <meeting>
    <Confcode>ED22</Confcode>
    <EventName>MS5 Building Mathematical Communities from K-12 to Academia </EventName>
    <EventSubName></EventSubName>
    <Poster></Poster>
    <EventNumber>MS5</EventNumber>
    <EventDate>Jul 11, 2022</EventDate>
    <EventStartTime>2022-07-11T16:00:00</EventStartTime>
    <EventEndTime>2022-07-11T18:00:00</EventEndTime>
    <EventFilter>ED22|Minisymposium|</EventFilter>
    <EventLocation></EventLocation>
    <EventRoom>405</EventRoom>
    <FloorPlan></FloorPlan>
    <EVENT_FEE></EVENT_FEE>
    <EventKeywords>2800</EventKeywords>
    <EventChairs>778806</EventChairs>
    <EventModerators></EventModerators>
    <EventSpeakers></EventSpeakers>
    <EventSpeakerIDs>744264,779079,769784</EventSpeakerIDs>
    <EventSponsor></EventSponsor>
    <EventHandoutName>session</EventHandoutName>
    <EventHandoutURL>http://meetings.siam.org/sess/dsp_programsess.cfm?SESSIONCODE=74435</EventHandoutURL>
    <EventDescription>Building effective communities in mathematics is crucial to recruiting and retaining underrepresented participation at the student and faculty levels.  In this minisymposia, we will discuss several instances of building communities in mathematics.  Dr. Hand has built a vibrant community of high school students through a summer camp in collaboration with the Tapia Center for Excellence and Equity in Education.  Dr. Sifuentes will discuss how he has built communities in the classroom and research lab of diverse mathematicians on the Texas-Mexico border.  Finally, Dr. Harris will discuss how she has built communities of mathematics through the Lathisms organization.</EventDescription>
    <EventParent></EventParent>
    <EventUniqueID>74435-SESS</EventUniqueID>
    <STATUS>active</STATUS>
    <AutoRecord>1</AutoRecord>
    <EnabledForIAV>1</EnabledForIAV>
    <MeetingIAVMode>Meeting</MeetingIAVMode>
    <PublishAutoRecordedVideo>1</PublishAutoRecordedVideo>
    <Capacity>300</Capacity>
    <DirectLinkEnabled xsi:nil="true" />
    <DirectLinkRecordingEnabled xsi:nil="true" />
    <start>2022-07-11T16:00:00</start>
  </meeting>
  <meeting>
    <Confcode>ED22</Confcode>
    <EventName>MS6 Panel: QuantCrit: Thinking Critically about Quantification Methods for Teaching and Social Research</EventName>
    <EventSubName></EventSubName>
    <Poster></Poster>
    <EventNumber>MS6</EventNumber>
    <EventDate>Jul 11, 2022</EventDate>
    <EventStartTime>2022-07-11T16:00:00</EventStartTime>
    <EventEndTime>2022-07-11T18:00:00</EventEndTime>
    <EventFilter>ED22|Minisymposium|</EventFilter>
    <EventLocation></EventLocation>
    <EventRoom>404</EventRoom>
    <FloorPlan></FloorPlan>
    <EVENT_FEE></EVENT_FEE>
    <EventKeywords>2800</EventKeywords>
    <EventChairs>806414,805726</EventChairs>
    <EventModerators></EventModerators>
    <EventSpeakers></EventSpeakers>
    <EventSpeakerIDs>806412,806414,806415,805726</EventSpeakerIDs>
    <EventSponsor></EventSponsor>
    <EventHandoutName>session</EventHandoutName>
    <EventHandoutURL>http://meetings.siam.org/sess/dsp_programsess.cfm?SESSIONCODE=74336</EventHandoutURL>
    <EventDescription>QuantCrit is a relatively new field, rooted in the traditions of critical inquiry and designed to carefully think through the consequences of the way that data and models are constructed which require the quantification and aggregation of human data. This process of “bucketing and quantification” is typical for the work of applied mathematics. However, as applied mathematicians use their skills in education research or provide classroom examples which involve social dimensions, we need to develop frameworks and tools for understanding how to have conversations about the human dimensions of mathematics. For example - Do we set up our research questions in ways that allow us to examine intersectional issues in the classroom? How do we ask students for demographic information in ways that are validating? Do our models or classroom examples assume gender binary? How might our quantitative methods obscure inequities in student outcomes? Do we interpret observed inequities as gaps or as educational debts? Without these difficult conversations, students could feel their experiences have been erased in the classroom and education research might not elucidate the full picture.</EventDescription>
    <EventParent></EventParent>
    <EventUniqueID>74336-SESS</EventUniqueID>
    <STATUS>active</STATUS>
    <AutoRecord>1</AutoRecord>
    <EnabledForIAV>1</EnabledForIAV>
    <MeetingIAVMode>Meeting</MeetingIAVMode>
    <PublishAutoRecordedVideo>1</PublishAutoRecordedVideo>
    <Capacity>300</Capacity>
    <DirectLinkEnabled xsi:nil="true" />
    <DirectLinkRecordingEnabled xsi:nil="true" />
    <start>2022-07-11T16:00:00</start>
  </meeting>
  <meeting>
    <Confcode>ED22</Confcode>
    <EventName>MS7 Panel: NSF RTG Programs in Applied Mathematics and Data Science - Part II of II</EventName>
    <EventSubName></EventSubName>
    <Poster></Poster>
    <EventNumber>MS7</EventNumber>
    <EventDate>Jul 11, 2022</EventDate>
    <EventStartTime>2022-07-11T16:00:00</EventStartTime>
    <EventEndTime>2022-07-11T18:00:00</EventEndTime>
    <EventFilter>ED22|Minisymposium|</EventFilter>
    <EventLocation></EventLocation>
    <EventRoom>403</EventRoom>
    <FloorPlan></FloorPlan>
    <EVENT_FEE></EVENT_FEE>
    <EventKeywords>5100</EventKeywords>
    <EventChairs>704298</EventChairs>
    <EventModerators></EventModerators>
    <EventSpeakers></EventSpeakers>
    <EventSpeakerIDs>805838,35611,750466</EventSpeakerIDs>
    <EventSponsor></EventSponsor>
    <EventHandoutName>session</EventHandoutName>
    <EventHandoutURL>http://meetings.siam.org/sess/dsp_programsess.cfm?SESSIONCODE=74082</EventHandoutURL>
    <EventDescription>NSF’s Research Training Groups in the Mathematical Sciences (RTG) program aims to increase the number of well-prepared U.S. citizens, nationals, and permanent residents to pursue careers in the mathematical sciences in academia, government, or industry. In this mini-symposium, faculty from RTG programs from a variety of institutions will describe their research activities and models for training students and postdoctoral associates.  Topics will include research and educational activity integration, recruitment, mentorship, and undergraduate research engagement.  RTG programs in applied mathematics and data science will be the focus of this minisymposium.</EventDescription>
    <EventParent></EventParent>
    <EventUniqueID>74082-SESS</EventUniqueID>
    <STATUS>active</STATUS>
    <AutoRecord>1</AutoRecord>
    <EnabledForIAV>1</EnabledForIAV>
    <MeetingIAVMode>Meeting</MeetingIAVMode>
    <PublishAutoRecordedVideo>1</PublishAutoRecordedVideo>
    <Capacity>300</Capacity>
    <DirectLinkEnabled xsi:nil="true" />
    <DirectLinkRecordingEnabled xsi:nil="true" />
    <start>2022-07-11T16:00:00</start>
  </meeting>
  <meeting>
    <Confcode>ED22</Confcode>
    <EventName>MS8 Project-Based Mathematical Modeling, Research, and Teacher Education - Part I of II</EventName>
    <EventSubName></EventSubName>
    <Poster></Poster>
    <EventNumber>MS8</EventNumber>
    <EventDate>Jul 11, 2022</EventDate>
    <EventStartTime>2022-07-11T16:00:00</EventStartTime>
    <EventEndTime>2022-07-11T18:00:00</EventEndTime>
    <EventFilter>ED22|Minisymposium|</EventFilter>
    <EventLocation></EventLocation>
    <EventRoom>402</EventRoom>
    <FloorPlan></FloorPlan>
    <EVENT_FEE></EVENT_FEE>
    <EventKeywords>3000</EventKeywords>
    <EventChairs>729229,702229</EventChairs>
    <EventModerators></EventModerators>
    <EventSpeakers></EventSpeakers>
    <EventSpeakerIDs>702229,773408,805742</EventSpeakerIDs>
    <EventSponsor></EventSponsor>
    <EventHandoutName>session</EventHandoutName>
    <EventHandoutURL>http://meetings.siam.org/sess/dsp_programsess.cfm?SESSIONCODE=74198</EventHandoutURL>
    <EventDescription>Mathematical modeling is in the unique position of being part of the K-16 curriculum, a topic in undergraduate mathematics, a technique used by professionals, and an active area of research.  For this reason, it is important for mathematicians and mathematics educators to come together and advance collaboratively their instruction of a wide range of courses that prepare students for mathematical modeling applications in their future careers, including teacher preparation for K-12 education, consistent with the way practitioners construct and use mathematical models. This session will highlight collaborative research projects focused on modeling research, teacher education, and mathematical pedagogy in undergraduate courses, including practical approaches that engage students in data collection, theoretical, and computational approaches.</EventDescription>
    <EventParent></EventParent>
    <EventUniqueID>74198-SESS</EventUniqueID>
    <STATUS>active</STATUS>
    <AutoRecord>1</AutoRecord>
    <EnabledForIAV>1</EnabledForIAV>
    <MeetingIAVMode>Meeting</MeetingIAVMode>
    <PublishAutoRecordedVideo>1</PublishAutoRecordedVideo>
    <Capacity>300</Capacity>
    <DirectLinkEnabled xsi:nil="true" />
    <DirectLinkRecordingEnabled xsi:nil="true" />
    <start>2022-07-11T16:00:00</start>
  </meeting>
  <meeting>
    <Confcode>ED22</Confcode>
    <EventName>MS9 History of Science and Mathematics in Applied Maths Courses</EventName>
    <EventSubName></EventSubName>
    <Poster></Poster>
    <EventNumber>MS9</EventNumber>
    <EventDate>Jul 11, 2022</EventDate>
    <EventStartTime>2022-07-11T16:00:00</EventStartTime>
    <EventEndTime>2022-07-11T18:00:00</EventEndTime>
    <EventFilter>ED22|Minisymposium|</EventFilter>
    <EventLocation></EventLocation>
    <EventRoom>401</EventRoom>
    <FloorPlan></FloorPlan>
    <EVENT_FEE></EVENT_FEE>
    <EventKeywords>300</EventKeywords>
    <EventChairs>751042</EventChairs>
    <EventModerators></EventModerators>
    <EventSpeakers></EventSpeakers>
    <EventSpeakerIDs>805785,805735,805736,751042</EventSpeakerIDs>
    <EventSponsor></EventSponsor>
    <EventHandoutName>session</EventHandoutName>
    <EventHandoutURL>http://meetings.siam.org/sess/dsp_programsess.cfm?SESSIONCODE=74180</EventHandoutURL>
    <EventDescription>The history of math and science provides countless ideas not encountered in standard courses as well as avenues of exploring cultures.  History of mathematics courses often focus on mathematics with little reference to the scientific questions that inspired mathematical inquiry or science that was pushed forward by advances in mathematics.  Speakers in this minisymposium will present successful methods of integrating math and science history into applied mathematics courses that help students to see math and science as integrated endeavors.</EventDescription>
    <EventParent></EventParent>
    <EventUniqueID>74180-SESS</EventUniqueID>
    <STATUS>active</STATUS>
    <AutoRecord>1</AutoRecord>
    <EnabledForIAV>1</EnabledForIAV>
    <MeetingIAVMode>Meeting</MeetingIAVMode>
    <PublishAutoRecordedVideo>1</PublishAutoRecordedVideo>
    <Capacity>300</Capacity>
    <DirectLinkEnabled xsi:nil="true" />
    <DirectLinkRecordingEnabled xsi:nil="true" />
    <start>2022-07-11T16:00:00</start>
  </meeting>
  <meeting>
    <Confcode>ED22</Confcode>
    <EventName>MT1 Introduction to COMAP’s Certificate in Modeling (CiM) Program for Educators – Part I of II</EventName>
    <EventSubName></EventSubName>
    <Poster></Poster>
    <EventNumber>MT1</EventNumber>
    <EventDate>Jul 11, 2022</EventDate>
    <EventStartTime>2022-07-11T08:30:00</EventStartTime>
    <EventEndTime>2022-07-11T10:30:00</EventEndTime>
    <EventFilter>ED22|Minitutorial|</EventFilter>
    <EventLocation></EventLocation>
    <EventRoom>405</EventRoom>
    <FloorPlan></FloorPlan>
    <EVENT_FEE></EVENT_FEE>
    <EventKeywords></EventKeywords>
    <EventChairs>807334,732230</EventChairs>
    <EventModerators></EventModerators>
    <EventSpeakers></EventSpeakers>
    <EventSpeakerIDs>807334,732230</EventSpeakerIDs>
    <EventSponsor></EventSponsor>
    <EventHandoutName>session</EventHandoutName>
    <EventHandoutURL>http://meetings.siam.org/sess/dsp_programsess.cfm?SESSIONCODE=74631</EventHandoutURL>
    <EventDescription>During this workshop, we will introduce participants to the CiM program as well as the opportunity to obtain the Modeling Educator Certificate (MEC). Workshop participants will participate in two hour-long sessions where COMAP will expose participants to the material contained within the first two modules of the Modeling for Education course. During module 1, participants will trace a bit of history of educational practices from traditional/computational (#1-15 odd), to “word” problems, to applied problem solving, to “modeling problem.” After completing module 1, every participant will have a better understanding of the philosophy of teaching/learning and framework for applied problem solving and modeling. During module 2, participants will explore a Showcase of (Modeling) Examples to learn how to expose students to various fields, levels of solutions, and types of mathematics involved. In addition to being exposed to the course in-class activities, workshop participants will also experience some of the pre- and post-class activities planned as part of the program. Following the completion of module 2, the workshop will conclude with a discussion about the workshop experience and opportunity to obtain the modeling certificate.</EventDescription>
    <EventParent></EventParent>
    <EventUniqueID>74631-SESS</EventUniqueID>
    <STATUS>active</STATUS>
    <AutoRecord>1</AutoRecord>
    <EnabledForIAV>1</EnabledForIAV>
    <MeetingIAVMode>Meeting</MeetingIAVMode>
    <PublishAutoRecordedVideo>1</PublishAutoRecordedVideo>
    <Capacity>300</Capacity>
    <DirectLinkEnabled xsi:nil="true" />
    <DirectLinkRecordingEnabled xsi:nil="true" />
    <start>2022-07-11T08:30:00</start>
  </meeting>
  <meeting>
    <Confcode>ED22</Confcode>
    <EventName>MT2 Introduction to COMAP’s Certificate in Modeling (CiM) Program for Educators – Part II of II</EventName>
    <EventSubName></EventSubName>
    <Poster></Poster>
    <EventNumber>MT2</EventNumber>
    <EventDate>Jul 11, 2022</EventDate>
    <EventStartTime>2022-07-11T16:00:00</EventStartTime>
    <EventEndTime>2022-07-11T18:00:00</EventEndTime>
    <EventFilter>ED22|Minitutorial|</EventFilter>
    <EventLocation></EventLocation>
    <EventRoom>406</EventRoom>
    <FloorPlan></FloorPlan>
    <EVENT_FEE></EVENT_FEE>
    <EventKeywords></EventKeywords>
    <EventChairs>807334,732230</EventChairs>
    <EventModerators></EventModerators>
    <EventSpeakers></EventSpeakers>
    <EventSpeakerIDs>732230,807334</EventSpeakerIDs>
    <EventSponsor></EventSponsor>
    <EventHandoutName>session</EventHandoutName>
    <EventHandoutURL>http://meetings.siam.org/sess/dsp_programsess.cfm?SESSIONCODE=74632</EventHandoutURL>
    <EventDescription>During this workshop, we will introduce participants to the CiM program as well as the opportunity to obtain the Modeling Educator Certificate (MEC). Workshop participants will participate in two hour-long sessions where COMAP will expose participants to the material contained within the first two modules of the Modeling for Education course. During module 1, participants will trace a bit of history of educational practices from traditional/computational (#1-15 odd), to “word” problems, to applied problem solving, to “modeling problem.” After completing module 1, every participant will have a better understanding of the philosophy of teaching/learning and framework for applied problem solving and modeling. During module 2, participants will explore a Showcase of (Modeling) Examples to learn how to expose students to various fields, levels of solutions, and types of mathematics involved. In addition to being exposed to the course in-class activities, workshop participants will also experience some of the pre- and post-class activities planned as part of the program. Following the completion of module 2, the workshop will conclude with a discussion about the workshop experience and opportunity to obtain the modeling certificate.</EventDescription>
    <EventParent></EventParent>
    <EventUniqueID>74632-SESS</EventUniqueID>
    <STATUS>active</STATUS>
    <AutoRecord>1</AutoRecord>
    <EnabledForIAV>1</EnabledForIAV>
    <MeetingIAVMode>Meeting</MeetingIAVMode>
    <PublishAutoRecordedVideo>1</PublishAutoRecordedVideo>
    <Capacity>300</Capacity>
    <DirectLinkEnabled xsi:nil="true" />
    <DirectLinkRecordingEnabled xsi:nil="true" />
    <start>2022-07-11T16:00:00</start>
  </meeting>
  <meeting>
    <Confcode>ED22</Confcode>
    <EventName>Poster Session &amp; Dessert Reception (AN22 and LS22 posters will be presented)</EventName>
    <EventSubName></EventSubName>
    <Poster></Poster>
    <EventNumber>CB</EventNumber>
    <EventDate>Jul 12, 2022</EventDate>
    <EventStartTime>2022-07-12T20:00:00</EventStartTime>
    <EventEndTime>2022-07-12T22:00:00</EventEndTime>
    <EventFilter>ED22|</EventFilter>
    <EventLocation></EventLocation>
    <EventRoom>West Atrium - 3rd Floor</EventRoom>
    <FloorPlan></FloorPlan>
    <EVENT_FEE></EVENT_FEE>
    <EventKeywords></EventKeywords>
    <EventChairs xsi:nil="true" />
    <EventModerators></EventModerators>
    <EventSpeakers></EventSpeakers>
    <EventSpeakerIDs xsi:nil="true" />
    <EventSponsor></EventSponsor>
    <EventHandoutName></EventHandoutName>
    <EventHandoutURL></EventHandoutURL>
    <EventDescription></EventDescription>
    <EventParent></EventParent>
    <EventUniqueID>74733-SESS</EventUniqueID>
    <STATUS>active</STATUS>
    <AutoRecord>0</AutoRecord>
    <EnabledForIAV>0</EnabledForIAV>
    <MeetingIAVMode xsi:nil="true" />
    <PublishAutoRecordedVideo xsi:nil="true" />
    <Capacity xsi:nil="true" />
    <DirectLinkEnabled xsi:nil="true" />
    <DirectLinkRecordingEnabled xsi:nil="true" />
    <start>2022-07-12T20:00:00</start>
  </meeting>
  <meeting>
    <Confcode>ED22</Confcode>
    <EventName>Prizes and Awards Luncheon (ticketed event)</EventName>
    <EventSubName></EventSubName>
    <Poster></Poster>
    <EventNumber>CB</EventNumber>
    <EventDate>Jul 12, 2022</EventDate>
    <EventStartTime>2022-07-12T12:30:00</EventStartTime>
    <EventEndTime>2022-07-12T14:30:00</EventEndTime>
    <EventFilter>ED22|</EventFilter>
    <EventLocation></EventLocation>
    <EventRoom>301-303</EventRoom>
    <FloorPlan></FloorPlan>
    <EVENT_FEE></EVENT_FEE>
    <EventKeywords></EventKeywords>
    <EventChairs xsi:nil="true" />
    <EventModerators></EventModerators>
    <EventSpeakers></EventSpeakers>
    <EventSpeakerIDs xsi:nil="true" />
    <EventSponsor></EventSponsor>
    <EventHandoutName></EventHandoutName>
    <EventHandoutURL></EventHandoutURL>
    <EventDescription></EventDescription>
    <EventParent></EventParent>
    <EventUniqueID>74758-SESS</EventUniqueID>
    <STATUS>active</STATUS>
    <AutoRecord>0</AutoRecord>
    <EnabledForIAV>0</EnabledForIAV>
    <MeetingIAVMode xsi:nil="true" />
    <PublishAutoRecordedVideo xsi:nil="true" />
    <Capacity xsi:nil="true" />
    <DirectLinkEnabled xsi:nil="true" />
    <DirectLinkRecordingEnabled xsi:nil="true" />
    <start>2022-07-12T12:30:00</start>
  </meeting>
  <meeting>
    <Confcode>ED22</Confcode>
    <EventName>SIAG/ED Business Meeting</EventName>
    <EventSubName></EventSubName>
    <Poster></Poster>
    <EventNumber>CB</EventNumber>
    <EventDate>Jul 12, 2022</EventDate>
    <EventStartTime>2022-07-12T19:15:00</EventStartTime>
    <EventEndTime>2022-07-12T19:45:00</EventEndTime>
    <EventFilter>ED22|</EventFilter>
    <EventLocation></EventLocation>
    <EventRoom>406</EventRoom>
    <FloorPlan></FloorPlan>
    <EVENT_FEE></EVENT_FEE>
    <EventKeywords></EventKeywords>
    <EventChairs xsi:nil="true" />
    <EventModerators></EventModerators>
    <EventSpeakers></EventSpeakers>
    <EventSpeakerIDs xsi:nil="true" />
    <EventSponsor></EventSponsor>
    <EventHandoutName></EventHandoutName>
    <EventHandoutURL></EventHandoutURL>
    <EventDescription></EventDescription>
    <EventParent></EventParent>
    <EventUniqueID>74765-SESS</EventUniqueID>
    <STATUS>active</STATUS>
    <AutoRecord>1</AutoRecord>
    <EnabledForIAV>1</EnabledForIAV>
    <MeetingIAVMode>Meeting</MeetingIAVMode>
    <PublishAutoRecordedVideo>1</PublishAutoRecordedVideo>
    <Capacity>300</Capacity>
    <DirectLinkEnabled xsi:nil="true" />
    <DirectLinkRecordingEnabled xsi:nil="true" />
    <start>2022-07-12T19:15:00</start>
  </meeting>
  <meeting>
    <Confcode>ED22</Confcode>
    <EventName>Welcome Reception</EventName>
    <EventSubName></EventSubName>
    <Poster></Poster>
    <EventNumber>CB</EventNumber>
    <EventDate>Jul 10, 2022</EventDate>
    <EventStartTime>2022-07-10T18:00:00</EventStartTime>
    <EventEndTime>2022-07-10T20:00:00</EventEndTime>
    <EventFilter>ED22|</EventFilter>
    <EventLocation></EventLocation>
    <EventRoom>South Terrace - 3rd Floor</EventRoom>
    <FloorPlan></FloorPlan>
    <EVENT_FEE></EVENT_FEE>
    <EventKeywords></EventKeywords>
    <EventChairs xsi:nil="true" />
    <EventModerators></EventModerators>
    <EventSpeakers></EventSpeakers>
    <EventSpeakerIDs xsi:nil="true" />
    <EventSponsor></EventSponsor>
    <EventHandoutName></EventHandoutName>
    <EventHandoutURL></EventHandoutURL>
    <EventDescription></EventDescription>
    <EventParent></EventParent>
    <EventUniqueID>74749-SESS</EventUniqueID>
    <STATUS>active</STATUS>
    <AutoRecord>0</AutoRecord>
    <EnabledForIAV>0</EnabledForIAV>
    <MeetingIAVMode xsi:nil="true" />
    <PublishAutoRecordedVideo xsi:nil="true" />
    <Capacity xsi:nil="true" />
    <DirectLinkEnabled xsi:nil="true" />
    <DirectLinkRecordingEnabled xsi:nil="true" />
    <start>2022-07-10T18:00:00</start>
  </meeting>
</meetings>